{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Convert the following SOP expression to an equivalent POS expression.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Determine the values of A, B, C, and D that make the sum term  equal to zero.", "opta": "A = 1, B = 0, C = 0, D = 0", "optb": "A = 1, B = 0, C = 1, D = 0", "optc": "A = 0, B = 1, C = 0, D = 0", "optd": "A = 1, B = 0, C = 1, D = 1", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following expressions is in the sum-of-products (SOP) form?", "opta": "(A + B)(C + D)", "optb": "(A)B(CD)", "optc": "AB(CD)", "optd": "AB + CD", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Derive the Boolean expression for the logic circuit shown below:", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "From the truth table below, determine the standard SOP expression.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One of De Morgan's theorems states that . Simply stated, this means that logically there is no difference between:", "opta": "a NOR and an AND gate with inverted inputs", "optb": "a NAND and an OR gate with inverted inputs", "optc": "an AND and a NOR gate with inverted inputs", "optd": "a NOR and a NAND gate with inverted inputs", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The commutative law of Boolean addition states that A + B = A \u00d7 B.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Applying DeMorgan's theorem to the expression , we get ________.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The systematic reduction of logic circuits is accomplished by:", "opta": "using Boolean algebra", "optb": "symbolic reduction", "optc": "TTL logic", "optd": "using a truth table", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which output expression might indicate a product-of-sums circuit construction?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An AND gate with schematic \"bubbles\" on its inputs performs the same function as a(n)________ gate.", "opta": "NOT", "optb": "OR", "optc": "NOR", "optd": "NAND", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the SOP expression , how many 1s are in the truth table's output column?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "5", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A truth table for the SOP expression  has how many input combinations?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "8", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many gates would be required to implement the following Boolean expression before simplification? XY + X(X + Z) + Y(X + Z)", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Determine the values of A, B, C, and D that make the product term  equal to 1.", "opta": "A = 0, B = 1, C = 0, D = 1", "optb": "A = 0, B = 0, C = 0, D = 1", "optc": "A = 1, B = 1, C = 1, D = 1", "optd": "A = 0, B = 0, C = 1, D = 0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the primary motivation for using Boolean algebra to simplify logic expressions?", "opta": "It may make it easier to understand the overall function of the circuit.", "optb": "It may reduce the number of gates.", "optc": "It may reduce the number of inputs required.", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many gates would be required to implement the following Boolean expression after simplification? XY + X(X + Z) + Y(X + Z)", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "AC + ABC = AC", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When  are the inputs to a NAND gate, according to De Morgan's theorem, the output expression could be:", "opta": "X = A + B", "optb": "", "optc": "X = (A)(B)", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which Boolean algebra property allows us to group operands in an expression in any order without affecting the results of the operation [for example, A + B = B + A]?", "opta": "associative", "optb": "commutative", "optc": "Boolean", "optd": "distributive", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Applying DeMorgan's theorem to the expression , we get ________", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When grouping cells within a K-map, the cells must be combined in groups of ________.", "opta": "2s", "optb": "1, 2, 4, 8, etc.", "optc": "4s", "optd": "3s", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Use Boolean algebra to find the most simplified SOP expression for F = ABD + CD + ACD + ABC + ABCD.", "opta": "F = ABD + ABC + CD", "optb": "F = CD + AD", "optc": "F = BC + AB", "optd": "F = AC + AD", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Occasionally, a particular logic expression will be of no consequence in the operation of a circuit, such as a BCD-to-decimal converter. These result in ________terms in the K-map and can be treated as either ________ or ________, in order to ________ the resulting term.", "opta": "don't care, 1s, 0s, simplify", "optb": "spurious, ANDs, ORs, eliminate", "optc": "duplicate, 1s, 0s, verify", "optd": "spurious, 1s, 0s, simplify", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The NAND or NOR gates are referred to as \"universal\" gates because either:", "opta": "can be found in almost all digital circuits", "optb": "can be used to build all the other types of gates", "optc": "are used in all countries of the world", "optd": "were the first gates to be integrated", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The truth table for the SOP expression  has how many input combinations?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "8", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Converting the Boolean expression LM + M(NO + PQ) to SOP form, we get ________.", "opta": "LM + MNOPQ", "optb": "L + MNO + MPQ", "optc": "LM + M + NO + MPQ", "optd": "LM + MNO + MPQ", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A Karnaugh map is a systematic way of reducing which type of expression?", "opta": "product-of-sums", "optb": "exclusive NOR", "optc": "sum-of-products", "optd": "those with overbars", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Boolean expression  is logically equivalent to what single gate?", "opta": "NAND", "optb": "NOR", "optc": "AND", "optd": "OR", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Applying the distributive law to the expression , we get ________.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mapping the SOP expression , we get ________.", "opta": "(A)", "optb": "(B)", "optc": "(C)", "optd": "(D)", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Derive the Boolean expression for the logic circuit shown below:", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is the correct logic function for this PAL diagram?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the SOP expression , how many 0s are in the truth table's output column?", "opta": "zero", "optb": "1", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mapping the standard SOP expression , we get", "opta": "(A)", "optb": "(B)", "optc": "(C)", "optd": "(D)", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which statement below best describes a Karnaugh map?", "opta": "A Karnaugh map can be used to replace Boolean rules.", "optb": "The Karnaugh map eliminates the need for using NAND and NOR gates.", "optc": "Variable complements can be eliminated by using Karnaugh maps.", "optd": "Karnaugh maps provide a cookbook approach to simplifying Boolean expressions.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Applying DeMorgan's theorem to the expression , we get ________.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the examples below expresses the distributive law of Boolean algebra?", "opta": "(A + B) + C = A + (B + C)", "optb": "A(B + C) = AB + AC", "optc": "A + (B + C) = AB + AC", "optd": "A(BC) = (AB) + C", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Applying DeMorgan's theorem to the expression , we get ________.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an important feature of the sum-of-products (SOP) form of expression?", "opta": "All logic circuits are reduced to nothing more than simple AND and OR gates.", "optb": "The delay times are greatly reduced over other forms.", "optc": "No signal must pass through more than two gates, not including inverters.", "optd": "The maximum number of gates that any signal must pass through is reduced by a factor of two.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An OR gate with schematic \"bubbles\" on its inputs performs the same functions as a(n)________ gate.", "opta": "NOR", "optb": "OR", "optc": "NOT", "optd": "NAND", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the examples below expresses the commutative law of multiplication?", "opta": "A + B = B + A", "optb": "AB = B + A", "optc": "AB = BA", "optd": "AB = A \u00d7 B", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Determine the binary values of the variables for which the following standard POS expression is equal to 0.", "opta": "(0 + 1 + 0)(1 + 0 + 1)", "optb": "(1 + 1 + 1)(0 + 0 + 0)", "optc": "(0 + 0 + 0)(1 + 0 + 1)", "optd": "(1 + 1 + 0)(1 + 0 + 0)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The expression W(X + YZ) can be converted to SOP form by applying which law?", "opta": "associative law", "optb": "commutative law", "optc": "distributive law", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The commutative law of addition and multiplication indicates that:", "opta": "we can group variables in an AND or in an OR any way we want", "optb": "an expression can be expanded by multiplying term by term just the same as in ordinary algebra", "optc": "the way we OR or AND two variables is unimportant because the result is the same", "optd": "the factoring of Boolean expressions requires the multiplication of product terms that contain like variables", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following combinations cannot be combined into K-map groups?", "opta": "corners in the same row", "optb": "corners in the same column", "optc": "diagonal", "optd": "overlapping combinations", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many outputs are on a BCD decoder?", "opta": "4", "optb": "16", "optc": "8", "optd": "10", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a Gray code, each number is 3 greater than the binary representation of that number.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Use the weighting factors to convert the following BCD numbers to binary. 0101\u00a00011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00010\u00a00110\u00a01000", "opta": "01010011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0001001101000", "optb": "11010100\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0100001100000", "optc": "110101\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0100001100", "optd": "101011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0001100001", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which digital system translates coded characters into a more useful form?", "opta": "encoder", "optb": "display", "optc": "counter", "optd": "decoder", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "From the following list of input conditions, determine the state of the five output leads on a 74148 octal-to-binary encoder.  I0 = 1 I3 = 1 I6 = 1 I1 = 1 I4 = 0 I7 = 1 I2 = 1 I5 = 1 EI = 0", "opta": "GS = L, A0 = L, A1 = L, A2 = H, EO = H", "optb": "GS = L, A0 = H, A1 = L, A2 = L, EO = H", "optc": "GS = L, A0 = L, A1 = H, A2 = L, EO = H", "optd": "GS = L, A0 = H, A1 = H, A2 = L, EO = H", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the function of an enable input on a multiplexer chip?", "opta": "to apply Vcc", "optb": "to connect ground", "optc": "to active the entire chip", "optd": "to active one half of the chip", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The expansion inputs to a comparator are used for expansion to a(n):", "opta": "4-bit system", "optb": "8-bit system", "optc": "BCD system", "optd": "counter system", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do the mathematical symbols A < b and A > B mean?", "opta": "A < B means A is greater than B. A > B means A is less than B.", "optb": "A > B means A is less than B. A < B means A is greater than B.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A basic multiplexer principle can be demonstrated through the use of a:", "opta": "single-pole relay", "optb": "DPDT switch", "optc": "rotary switch", "optd": "linear stepper", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many inputs will a decimal-to-BCD encoder have?", "opta": "4", "optb": "8", "optc": "10", "optd": "16", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A principle regarding most IC decoders is that when the correct input is present, the related output will switch:", "opta": "active-HIGH", "optb": "to a high impedance", "optc": "to an open", "optd": "active-LOW", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What control signals may be necessary to operate a 1-line-to-16 line decoder?", "opta": "flasher circuit control signal", "optb": "a LOW on all gate enable inputs", "optc": "input from a hexadecimal counter", "optd": "a HIGH on all gate enable circuits", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One multiplexer can take the place of:", "opta": "several SSI logic gates", "optb": "combinational logic circuits", "optc": "several Ex-NOR gates", "optd": "several SSI logic gates or combinational logic circuits", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many exclusive-NOR gates would be required for an 8-bit comparator circuit?", "opta": "4", "optb": "6", "optc": "8", "optd": "10", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many inputs are required for a 1-of-10 BCD decoder?", "opta": "4", "optb": "8", "optc": "10", "optd": "1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A BCD decoder will have how many rows in its truth table?", "opta": "10", "optb": "9", "optc": "8", "optd": "3", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many possible outputs would a decoder have with a 6-bit binary input?", "opta": "16", "optb": "32", "optc": "64", "optd": "128", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most demultiplexers facilitate which type of conversion?", "opta": "decimal-to-hexadecimal", "optb": "single input, multiple outputs", "optc": "ac to dc", "optd": "odd parity to even parity", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The inputs/outputs of an analog multiplexer/demultiplexer are:", "opta": "bidirectional", "optb": "unidirectional", "optc": "even parity", "optd": "binary-coded decimal", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why can a CMOS IC be used as both a multiplexer and a demultiplexer?", "opta": "It cannot be used as both.", "optb": "CMOS uses bidirectional switches.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One application of a digital multiplexer is to facilitate:", "opta": "data generation", "optb": "serial-to-parallel conversion", "optc": "parity checking", "optd": "data selector", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The primary use for Gray code is:", "opta": "coded representation of a shaft's mechanical position", "optb": "turning on/off software switches", "optc": "to represent the correct ASCII code to indicate the angular position of a shaft on rotating machinery", "optd": "to convert the angular position of a shaft on rotating machinery into hexadecimal code", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why is a demultiplexer called a data distributor?", "opta": "The input will be distributed to one of the outputs.", "optb": "One of the inputs will be selected for the output.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the status of the inputs S0, S1, and S2 of the 74151 eight-line multiplexer in order for the output Y to be a copy of input I5?", "opta": "S0 = 0, S1 = 1, S2 = 0", "optb": "S0 = 0, S1 = 0, S2 = 1", "optc": "S0 = 1, S1 = 1, S2 = 0", "optd": "S0 = 1, S1 = 0, S2 = 1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One way to convert BCD to binary using the hardware approach is:", "opta": "with MSI IC circuits", "optb": "with a keyboard encoder", "optc": "with an ALU", "optd": "UART", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A microcontroller differs from a microprocessor in that it has several ________ ports and ________ built into its architecture, making it better suited for ________ applications.", "opta": "communication, PROMs, control", "optb": "parallel, logic gates, processing", "optc": "input/output, memory, control", "optd": "data, memory, decoding", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is an encoder different from a decoder?", "opta": "The output of an encoder is a binary code for 1-of-N input.", "optb": "The output of a decoder is a binary code for 1-of-N input.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why is the Gray code more practical to use when coding the position of a rotating shaft?", "opta": "All digits change between counts.", "optb": "Two digits change between counts.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the following conditions on a 7485 magnitude comparator, what will be the state of each of the three outputs?   A0 = 0B0 = 1IA < B = 0 A1 = 1B1 = 0IA = B = 1 A2 = 1B2 = 0IA > B = 0 A3 = 0B3 = 0", "opta": "A = B = 0, A < B = 0, A > B = 1", "optb": "A = B = 0, A < B = 1, A > B = 0", "optc": "A = B = 1, A < B = 0, A > B = 0", "optd": "A = B = 0, A < B = 0, A > B = 0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When two or more inputs are active simultaneously, the process is called:", "opta": "first-in, first-out processing", "optb": "priority encoding", "optc": "ripple blanking", "optd": "first-in, first-out processing or priority encoding", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A binary code that progresses such that only one bit changes between two successive codes is:", "opta": "nine's-complement code", "optb": "8421 code", "optc": "excess-3 code", "optd": "Gray code", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a weighted value positional numbering system:", "opta": "hexadecimal", "optb": "binary-coded decimal", "optc": "binary", "optd": "octal", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many inputs are required for a 1-of-16 decoder?", "opta": "2", "optb": "4", "optc": "8", "optd": "16", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A truth table with output columns numbered 0\u201315 may be for which type of decoder IC?", "opta": "hexadecimal 1-of-16", "optb": "dual octal outputs", "optc": "binary-to-hexadecimal", "optd": "hexadecimal-to-binary", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a BCD-to-seven-segment converter, why must a code converter be utilized?", "opta": "to convert the 4-bit BCD into 7-bit code", "optb": "to convert the 4-bit BCD into 10-bit code", "optc": "to convert the 4-bit BCD into Gray code", "optd": "No conversion is necessary.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How can the active condition (HIGH or LOW) or the decoder output be determined from the logic symbol?", "opta": "A bubble indicates active-HIGH.", "optb": "A bubble indicates active-LOW.", "optc": "A square indicates active-HIGH.", "optd": "A square indicates active-LOW.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If two inputs are active on a priority encoder, which will be coded on the output?", "opta": "the higher value", "optb": "the lower value", "optc": "neither of the inputs", "optd": "both of the inputs", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A circuit that responds to a specific set of signals to produce a related digital signal output is called a(n):", "opta": "BCD matrix", "optb": "display driver", "optc": "encoder", "optd": "decoder", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many 74184 BCD-to-binary converters would be required to convert two complete BCD digits to a binary number?", "opta": "8", "optb": "4", "optc": "2", "optd": "1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many select lines would be required for an 8-line-to-1-line multiplexer?", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "4", "optd": "8", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Referring to the GAL diagram, which is the correct logic function?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of an exclusive-NOR gate is 1. Which input combination is correct?", "opta": "A = 1, B = 0", "optb": "A = 0, B = 1", "optc": "A = 0, B = 0", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Boolean SOP expression obtained from the truth table below is ________.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 8-input XOR circuit shown has an output of Y = 1. Which input combination below (ordered A \u2013 H) is correct?", "opta": "10111100", "optb": "10111000", "optc": "11100111", "optd": "00011101", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Implementing the expression AB + CDE using NAND logic, we get:", "opta": "(A)", "optb": "(B)", "optc": "(C)", "optd": "(D)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Before an SOP implementation, the expression  would require a total of how many gates?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following waveform pattern is for a(n) ________.", "opta": "2-input AND gate", "optb": "2-input OR gate", "optc": "Exclusive-OR gate", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Implementing the expression  with NOR logic, we get:", "opta": "(A)", "optb": "(B)", "optc": "(C)", "optd": "(D)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 4-variable AND-OR-Invert circuit produces a 0 at its Y output. Which combination of inputs is correct?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following waveform pattern is for a(n) ________.", "opta": "2-input AND gate", "optb": "2-input OR gate", "optc": "Exclusive-OR gate", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To implement the expression , it takes one OR gate and ________.", "opta": "three AND gates and three inverters", "optb": "three AND gates and four inverters", "optc": "three AND gates", "optd": "one AND gate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One positive pulse with tw = 75 \u00b5s is applied to one of the inputs of an exclusive-OR circuit. A second positive pulse with tw = 15 \u00b5s is applied to the other input beginning 20 \u00b5s after the leading edge of the first pulse. Which statement describes the output in relation to the inputs?", "opta": "The exclusive-OR output is a 20 s pulse followed by a 40 s pulse, with a separation of 15 s between the pulses.", "optb": "The exclusive-OR output is a 20 s pulse followed by a 15 s pulse, with a separation of 40 s between the pulses.", "optc": "The exclusive-OR output is a 15 s pulse followed by a 40 s pulse.", "optd": "*The exclusive-OR output is a 20 s pulse followed by a 15 s pulse, followed by a 40 s pulse.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many AND gates are required to implement the Boolean expression, ?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many NOT gates are required to implement the Boolean expression, ?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The inverter can be produced with how many NAND gates?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 4-variable AND-OR circuit produces a 0 at its Y output. Which combination of inputs is correct?", "opta": "A = 0, B = 0, C = 1, D = 1", "optb": "A = 1, B = 1, C = 0, D = 0", "optc": "A = 1, B = 1, C = 1, D = 1", "optd": "A = 1, B = 0, C = 1, D = 0", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 4-variable AND-OR circuit produces a 1 at its Y output. Which combination of inputs is correct?", "opta": "A = 0, B = 0, C = 0, D = 0", "optb": "A = 0, B = 1, C = 1, D = 0", "optc": "A = 1, B = 1, C = 0, D = 0", "optd": "A = 1, B = 0, C = 0, D = 0", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Implementing the expression  using NAND logic, we get:", "opta": "(A)", "optb": "(B)", "optc": "(C)", "optd": "(D)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Implementing the expression  using NAND logic, we get:", "opta": "(A)", "optb": "(B)", "optc": "(C)", "optd": "(D)", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following waveform pattern is for a(n) ________.", "opta": "2-input AND gate", "optb": "2-input OR gate", "optc": "Exclusive-OR gate", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Implementation of the Boolean expression  results in ________.", "opta": "three AND gates, one OR gate", "optb": "three AND gates, one NOT gate, one OR gate", "optc": "three AND gates, one NOT gate, three OR gates", "optd": "three AND gates, three OR gates", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One possible output expression for an AND-OR-Invert circuit having one AND gate with inputs A, B, and C and one AND gate with inputs D and E is ________.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many 2-input NOR gates does it take to produce a 2-input NAND gate?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A logic circuit with an output  consists of ________.", "opta": "two AND gates, two OR gates, two inverters", "optb": "three AND gates, two OR gates, one inverter", "optc": "two AND gates, one OR gate, two inverters", "optd": "two AND gates, one OR gate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many 3-line-to-8-line decoders are required for a 1-of-32 decoder?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "8", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the figures shown below represents the exclusive-NOR gate?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the circuits in figure (a to d) is the sum-of-products implementation of figure (e)?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the device shown here, let all D inputs be LOW, both S inputs be HIGH, and the  input be LOW. What is the status of the Y output?", "opta": "LOW", "optb": "HIGH", "optc": "Don't Care", "optd": "Cannot be determined", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the device shown here, let all D inputs be LOW, both S inputs be HIGH, and the  input be HIGH. What is the status of the Y output?", "opta": "LOW", "optb": "HIGH", "optc": "Don't Care", "optd": "Cannot be determined", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert BCD 0001 0010 0110 to binary.", "opta": "1111110", "optb": "1111101", "optc": "1111000", "optd": "1111111", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 74HC147 priority encoder has ten active-LOW inputs and four active-LOW outputs. What would be the state of the four outputs if inputs 4 and 5 are LOW and all other inputs are HIGH?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert BCD 0001 0111 to binary.", "opta": "10101", "optb": "10010", "optc": "10001", "optd": "11000", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the figures in figure (a to d) is equivalent to figure (e)?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many data select lines are required for selecting eight inputs?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The simplest equation which implements the K-map shown below is:", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many 1-of-16 decoders are required for decoding a 7-bit binary number?", "opta": "5", "optb": "6", "optc": "7", "optd": "8", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following logic expressions represents the logic diagram shown?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The implementation of simplified sum-of-products expressions may be easily implemented into actual logic circuits using all universal ________ gates with little or no increase in circuit complexity. (Select the response for the blank space that will BEST make the statement true.)", "opta": "AND/OR", "optb": "NAND", "optc": "NOR", "optd": "OR/AND", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements accurately represents the two BEST methods of logic circuit simplification?", "opta": "Boolean algebra and Karnaugh mapping", "optb": "Karnaugh mapping and circuit waveform analysis", "optc": "Actual circuit trial and error evaluation and waveform analysis", "optd": "Boolean algebra and actual circuit trial and error evaluation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the device shown here, assume the D input is LOW, both S inputs are HIGH, and the  input is HIGH. What is the status of the  outputs?", "opta": "All are HIGH.", "optb": "All are LOW.", "optc": "All but  are LOW.", "optd": "All but  are HIGH.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following combinations cannot be combined into K-map groups?", "opta": "Corners in the same row", "optb": "Corners in the same column", "optc": "Diagonal corners", "optd": "Overlapping combinations", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As a technician you are confronted with a TTL circuit board containing dozens of IC chips. You have taken several readings at numerous IC chips, but the readings are inconclusive because of their erratic nature. Of the possible faults listed, select the one that most probably is causing the problem.", "opta": "A defective IC chip that is drawing excessive current from the power supply", "optb": "A solar bridge between the inputs on the first IC chip on the board", "optc": "An open input on the first IC chip on the board", "optd": "A defective output IC chip that has an internal open to Vcc", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which gate is best used as a basic comparator?", "opta": "NOR", "optb": "OR", "optc": "Exclusive-OR", "optd": "AND", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The device shown here is most likely a ________.", "opta": "comparator", "optb": "multiplexer", "optc": "demultiplexer", "optd": "parity generator", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In VHDL, macrofunctions is/are:", "opta": "digital circuits.", "optb": "analog circuits.", "optc": "a set of bit vectors.", "optd": "preprogrammed TTL devices.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following expressions is in the product-of-sums form?", "opta": "(A + B)(C + D)", "optb": "(AB)(CD)", "optc": "AB(CD)", "optd": "AB + CD", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an important feature of the sum-of-products form of expressions?", "opta": "All logic circuits are reduced to nothing more than simple AND and OR operations.", "optb": "The delay times are greatly reduced over other forms.", "optc": "No signal must pass through more than two gates, not including inverters.", "optd": "The maximum number of gates that any signal must pass through is reduced by a factor of two.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the device shown here, assume the D input is LOW, both S inputs are LOW, and the  input is LOW. What is the status of the  outputs?", "opta": "All are HIGH.", "optb": "All are LOW.", "optc": "All but  are LOW.", "optd": "All but  are HIGH.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An output gate is connected to four input gates; the circuit does not function. Preliminary tests with the DMM indicate that the power is applied; scope tests show that the primary input gate has a pulsing signal, while the interconnecting node has no signal. The four load gates are all on different ICs. Which instrument will best help isolate the problem?", "opta": "Current tracer", "optb": "Logic probe", "optc": "Oscilloscope", "optd": "Logic analyzer", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary numbers A = 1100 and B = 1001 are applied to the inputs of a comparator. What are the output levels?", "opta": "A > B = 1, A < B = 0, A < B = 1", "optb": "A > B = 0, A < B = 1, A = B = 0", "optc": "A > B = 1, A < B = 0, A = B = 0", "optd": "A > B = 0, A < B = 1, A = B = 1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A logic probe is placed on the output of a gate and the display indicator is dim. A pulser is used on each of the input terminals, but the output indication does not change. What is wrong?", "opta": "The output of the gate appears to be open.", "optb": "The dim indication on the logic probe indicates that the supply voltage is probably low.", "optc": "The dim indication is a result of a bad ground connection on the logic probe.", "optd": "The gate may be a tristate device.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Two 4-bit binary numbers (1011 and 1111) are applied to a 4-bit parallel adder. The carry input is 1. What are the values for the sum and carry output?", "opta": "4321 = 0111, Cout = 0", "optb": "4321 = 1111, Cout = 1", "optc": "4321 = 1011, Cout = 1", "optd": "4321 = 1100, Cout = 1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Each \"1\" entry in a K-map square represents:", "opta": "a HIGH for each input truth table condition that produces a HIGH output.", "optb": "a HIGH output on the truth table for all LOW input combinations.", "optc": "a LOW output for all possible HIGH input conditions.", "optd": "a DON'T CARE condition for all possible input truth table combinations.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Looping on a K-map always results in the elimination of:", "opta": "variables within the loop that appear only in their complemented form.", "optb": "variables that remain unchanged within the loop.", "optc": "variables within the loop that appear in both complemented and uncomplemented form.", "optd": "variables within the loop that appear only in their uncomplemented form.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What will a design engineer do after he/she is satisfied that the design will work?", "opta": "Put it in a flow chart", "optb": "Program a chip and test it", "optc": "Give the design to a technician to verify the design", "optd": "Perform a vector test", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Based on the indications of probe A in the figure given below, what is wrong, if anything, with the circuit?", "opta": "The logic probe is unable to determine the state of the circuit at that point and is blinking to alert the technician to the problem.", "optb": "The output appears to be shorted to Vcc, but is being pulsed by the pulser.", "optc": "The output appears to be LOW, but is being pulsed by the pulser.", "optd": "Nothing appears to be wrong at that point.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the indication of a short on the input of a load gate?", "opta": "Only the output of the defective gate is affected.", "optb": "There is a signal loss to all gates on the node.", "optc": "The affected node will be stuck in the LOW state.", "optd": "There is a signal loss to all gates on the node, and the affected node will be stuck in the LOW state.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In HDL, LITERALS is/are:", "opta": "digital systems.", "optb": "scalars.", "optc": "binary coded decimals.", "optd": "a numbering system.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following expressions is in the sum-of-products form?", "opta": "(A + B)(C + D)", "optb": "(AB)(CD)", "optc": "AB(CD)", "optd": "AB + CD", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The carry propagation can be expressed as ________.", "opta": "Cp = AB", "optb": "Cp = A + B", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the K-maps given below represents the expression X = AC + BC + B?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A decoder can be used as a demultiplexer by ________.", "opta": "tying all enable pins LOW", "optb": "tying all data-select lines LOW", "optc": "tying all data-select lines HIGH", "optd": "using the input lines for data selection and an enable line for data input", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many 4-bit parallel adders would be required to add two binary numbers each representing decimal numbers up through 30010?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which statement below best describes a Karnaugh map?", "opta": "A Karnaugh map can be used to replace Boolean rules.", "optb": "The Karnaugh map eliminates the need for using NAND and NOR gates.", "optc": "Variable complements can be eliminated by using Karnaugh maps.", "optd": "Karnaugh maps provide a visual approach to simplifying Boolean expressions.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a two-input XNOR gate, with the input waveforms as shown below, which output waveform is correct?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A certain BCD-to-decimal decoder has active-HIGH inputs and active-LOW outputs. Which output goes LOW when the inputs are 1001?", "opta": "0", "optb": "3", "optc": "9", "optd": "None. All outputs are HIGH.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Solve the network in the figure given below for X.", "opta": "A + BC + D", "optb": "((A + B)C) + D", "optc": "D(A + B + C)", "optd": "(AC + BC)D", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A full-adder has a Cin = 0. What are the sum () and the carry (Cout) when A = 1 and B = 1?", "opta": "= 0, Cout = 0", "optb": "= 0, Cout = 1", "optc": "= 1, Cout = 0", "optd": "= 1, Cout = 1", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of logic circuit is represented by the figure shown below?", "opta": "XOR", "optb": "XNOR", "optc": "XAND", "optd": "XNAND", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The device shown here is most likely a ________.", "opta": "comparator", "optb": "multiplexer", "optc": "demultiplexer", "optd": "parity generator", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The design concept of using building blocks of circuits in a PLD program is called a(n):", "opta": "hierarchical design.", "optb": "architectural design.", "optc": "digital design.", "optd": "verilog.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When adding an even parity bit to the code 110010, the result is ________.", "opta": "1110010", "optb": "1111001", "optc": "110010", "optd": "001101", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following combinations of logic gates can decode binary 1101?", "opta": "One 4-input AND gate", "optb": "One 4-input AND gate, one OR gate", "optc": "One 4-input NAND gate, one inverter", "optd": "One 4-input AND gate, one inverter", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the indication of a short to ground in the output of a driving gate?", "opta": "Only the output of the defective gate is affected.", "optb": "There is a signal loss to all load gates.", "optc": "The node may be stuck in either the HIGH or the LOW state.", "optd": "The affected node will be stuck in the HIGH state.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many outputs would two 8-line-to-3-line encoders, expanded to a 16-line-to-4-line encoder, have?", "opta": "3", "optb": "4", "optc": "5", "optd": "6", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a basic element within the microprocessor?", "opta": "Microcontroller", "optb": "Arithmetic logic unit (ALU)", "optc": "Register array", "optd": "Control unit", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which method bypasses the CPU for certain types of data transfer?", "opta": "Software interrupts", "optb": "Interrupt-driven I/O", "optc": "Polled I/O", "optd": "Direct memory access (DMA)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an enhancement to the Pentium that was unavailable in the 8086/8088?", "opta": "\"Pipelined\" architecture", "optb": "Expansion of cache memory", "optc": "Inclusion of an internal math coprocessor", "optd": "Data/address line multiplexing", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which bus is bidirectional?", "opta": "Address bus", "optb": "Control bus", "optc": "Data bus", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DMA is particularly suited for data transfer between the ________.", "opta": "disk drive and CPU", "optb": "disk drive and RAM", "optc": "disk drive and ROM", "optd": "disk drive and I/O", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The first microprocessor had a(n)________.", "opta": "1-bit data bus", "optb": "2-bit data bus", "optc": "4-bit data bus", "optd": "8-bit data bus", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which microprocessor has multiplexed data and address lines?", "opta": "8086/8088", "optb": "80286", "optc": "80386", "optd": "Pentium", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not an operand?", "opta": "Variable", "optb": "Register", "optc": "Memory location", "optd": "Assembler", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not part of the execution unit (EU)?", "opta": "Arithmetic logic unit (ALU)", "optb": "Clock", "optc": "General registers", "optd": "Flags", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 20-bit address bus can locate ________.", "opta": "1,048,576 locations", "optb": "2,097,152 locations", "optc": "4,194,304 locations", "optd": "8,388,608 locations", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is occurring when two or more sources of data attempt to use the same bus?", "opta": "Bus contention", "optb": "Direct memory access", "optc": "Bus interruption", "optd": "PPI", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a jump instruction?", "opta": "JB (jump back)", "optb": "JA (jump above)", "optc": "JO (jump if overflow)", "optd": "JMP (unconditional jump)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following was not a design improvement for the 8086/8088 over the 8085?", "opta": "Execution unit (EU)", "optb": "16-bit data bus", "optc": "Arithmetic logic unit (ALU)", "optd": "Bus interface unit (BIU)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Polled I/O works best when ________.", "opta": "there are no priority considerations", "optb": "priority considerations are frequent", "optc": "the polling rate exceeds 1000 s", "optd": "the polling rate is below 1000 s", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an arithmetic instruction?", "opta": "INC (increment)", "optb": "CMP (compare)", "optc": "DEC (decrement)", "optd": "ROL (rotate left)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During a read operation the CPU fetches ________.", "opta": "a program instruction", "optb": "another address", "optc": "data itself", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The first Intel microprocessor to contain on-board cache memory was the ________.", "opta": "80386", "optb": "80486", "optc": "Pentium", "optd": "Pentium Pro", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an 8086/8088 general-purpose register?", "opta": "Code segment (CS)", "optb": "Data segment (DS)", "optc": "Stack segment (SS)", "optd": "Address segment (AS)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a computer bus?", "opta": "Data bus", "optb": "Control bus", "optc": "Timer bus", "optd": "Address bus", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With interrupt-driven I/O, if two or more devices request service at the same time, ________.", "opta": "the device closest to the CPU gets priority", "optb": "the device that is fastest gets priority", "optc": "the device assigned the highest priority is serviced first", "optd": "the system is likely to crash", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Pentium can address ________.", "opta": "1 MB", "optb": "1 GB", "optc": "2 GB", "optd": "4 GB", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A port can be ________.", "opta": "strictly for input", "optb": "strictly for output", "optc": "bidirectional", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a computer functional block?", "opta": "Analog-to-digital converter", "optb": "Central-processing unit", "optc": "Memory", "optd": "Input/output ports", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Pentium microprocessor has a data bus of ________.", "opta": "16 bits", "optb": "32 bits", "optc": "64 bits", "optd": "128 bits", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The process of jointly establishing communication is called ________.", "opta": "DMA", "optb": "bidirectional addressing", "optc": "multiplexing", "optd": "handshaking", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many flip-flops are required to make a MOD-32 binary counter?", "opta": "3", "optb": "45", "optc": "5", "optd": "6", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Using four cascaded counters with a total of 16 bits, how many states must be deleted to achieve a modulus of 50,000?", "opta": "50,000", "optb": "65,536", "optc": "25,536", "optd": "15,536", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A MOD-16 ripple counter is holding the count 10012. What will the count be after 31 clock pulses?", "opta": "10002", "optb": "10102", "optc": "10112", "optd": "11012", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The terminal count of a modulus-11 binary counter is ________.", "opta": "1010", "optb": "1000", "optc": "1001", "optd": "1100", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "List which pins need to be connected together on a 7493 to make a MOD-12 counter.", "opta": "12 to 1, 11 to 3, 9 to 2", "optb": "12 to 1, 11 to 3, 12 to 2", "optc": "12 to 1, 11 to 3, 8 to 2", "optd": "12 to 1, 11 to 3, 1 to 2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How can a digital one-shot be implemented using HDL?", "opta": "By using a resistor and a capacitor", "optb": "By applying the concept of a counter", "optc": "By using a library function", "optd": "By applying a level trigger", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Integrated-circuit counter chips are used in numerous applications including:", "opta": "timing operations, counting operations, sequencing, and frequency multiplication", "optb": "timing operations, counting operations, sequencing, and frequency division", "optc": "timing operations, decoding operations, sequencing, and frequency multiplication", "optd": "data generation, counting operations, sequencing, and frequency multiplication", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Synchronous construction reduces the delay time of a counter to the delay of:", "opta": "all flip-flops and gates", "optb": "all flip-flops and gates after a 3 count", "optc": "a single gate", "optd": "a single flip-flop and a gate", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Synchronous counters eliminate the delay problems encountered with asynchronous counters because the:", "opta": "input clock pulses are applied only to the first and last stages", "optb": "input clock pulses are applied only to the last stage", "optc": "input clock pulses are not used to activate any of the counter stages", "optd": "input clock pulses are applied simultaneously to each stage", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between combinational logic and sequential logic?", "opta": "Combinational circuits are not triggered by timing pulses, sequential circuits are triggered by timing pulses.", "optb": "Combinational and sequential circuits are both triggered by timing pulses.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between a 7490 and a 7492?", "opta": "7490 is a MOD-12, 7492 is a MOD-10", "optb": "7490 is a MOD-12, 7492 is a MOD-16", "optc": "7490 is a MOD-16, 7492 is a MOD-10", "optd": "7490 is a MOD-10, 7492 is a MOD-12", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of register is shown below?", "opta": "Parallel in/parallel out register", "optb": "Serial in/parallel out register", "optc": "Serial/parallel-in parallel-out register", "optd": "Parallel-access shift register", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When two counters are cascaded, the overall MOD number is equal to the ________ of their individual MOD numbers.", "opta": "product", "optb": "sum", "optc": "log", "optd": "reciprocal", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A MOD-12 and a MOD-10 counter are cascaded. Determine the output frequency if the input clock frequency is 60 MHz.", "opta": "500 kHz", "optb": "1,500 kHz", "optc": "6 MHz", "optd": "5 MHz", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which segments of a seven-segment display would be required to be active to display the decimal digit 2?", "opta": "a, b, d, e, and g", "optb": "a, b, c, d, and g", "optc": "a, c, d, f, and g", "optd": "a, b, c, d, e, and f", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many AND gates would be required to completely decode ALL the states of a MOD-64 counter, and how many inputs must each AND gate have?", "opta": "128 gates, 6 inputs to each gate", "optb": "64 gates, 5 inputs to each gate", "optc": "64 gates, 6 inputs to each gate", "optd": "128 gates, 5 inputs to each gate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What decimal value is required to produce an output at \"X\" ?", "opta": "1", "optb": "1 or 4", "optc": "2", "optd": "5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A BCD counter is a ________.", "opta": "binary counter", "optb": "full-modulus counter", "optc": "decade counter", "optd": "divide-by-10 counter", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The circuit given below has no output on Q1 when examined with an oscilloscope. All J-K inputs are HIGH, the CLK signal is present, and the Q0 is toggling. The C input of FF1 is a constant LOW. What could be causing the problem?", "opta": "The Q0 output should be connected to the J input of FF1.", "optb": "The output of FF0 may be shorted to ground.", "optc": "The input of FF1 may be shorted to ground.", "optd": "Either the output of FF0 or the input of FF1 may be shorted to ground.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many flip-flops are required to construct a decade counter?", "opta": "10", "optb": "8", "optc": "5", "optd": "4", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The terminal count of a typical modulus-10 binary counter is ________.", "opta": "0000", "optb": "1010", "optc": "1001", "optd": "1111", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A seven-segment, common-anode LED display is designed for:", "opta": "all cathodes to be wired together", "optb": "one common LED", "optc": "a HIGH to turn off each segment", "optd": "disorientation of segment modules", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To operate correctly, starting a ring counter requires:", "opta": "clearing one flip-flop and presetting all the others.", "optb": "clearing all the flip-flops.", "optc": "presetting one flip-flop and clearing all the others.", "optd": "presetting all the flip-flops.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The process of designing a synchronous counter that will count in a nonbinary manner is primarily based on:", "opta": "external logic circuits that decode the various states of the counter to apply the correct logic levels to the J-K inputs", "optb": "modifying BCD counters to change states on every second input clock pulse", "optc": "modifying asynchronous counters to change states on every second input clock pulse", "optd": "elimination of the counter stages and the addition of combinational logic circuits to produce the desired counts", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Select the response that best describes the use of the Master Reset on typical 4-bit binary counters.", "opta": "When MR1 and MR2 are both HIGH, all Qs will be reset to zero.", "optb": "When MR1 and MR2 are both HIGH, all Qs will be reset to one.", "optc": "MR1 and MR2 are provided to synchronously reset all four flip-flops.", "optd": "To enable the count mode, MR1 and MR2 must be held LOW.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a multistage counter to be truly synchronous, the ________ of each stage must be connected to ________.", "opta": "Cp, the same clock input line", "optb": "CE, the same clock input line", "optc": ", the terminal count output", "optd": ", both clock input lines", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an invalid output state for an 8421 BCD counter?", "opta": "1110", "optb": "0000", "optc": "0010", "optd": "0001", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many different states does a 3-bit asynchronous counter have?", "opta": "2", "optb": "4", "optc": "8", "optd": "16", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 5-bit asynchronous binary counter is made up of five flip-flops, each with a 12 ns propagation delay. The total propagation delay (tp(tot)) is ________.", "opta": "12 ms", "optb": "24 ns", "optc": "48 ns", "optd": "60 ns", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A four-channel scope is used to check the counter in the figure given below. Are the displayed waveforms correct?", "opta": "Yes", "optb": "No", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following procedures could be used to check the parallel loading feature of a counter?", "opta": "Preset the LOAD inputs, set the CLR to its active level, and check to see that the Q outputs match the values preset into the LOAD inputs.", "optb": "Apply LOWs to the parallel DATA inputs, pulse the CLK input, and check for LOWs on all the Q outputs.", "optc": "Apply HIGHs to all the DATA inputs, pulse the CLK and CLR inputs, and check to be sure that the Q outputs are all LOW.", "optd": "Apply HIGHs to all the Q terminals, pulse the CLK, and check to see if the DATA terminals now match the Q outputs.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One of the major drawbacks to the use of asynchronous counters is:", "opta": "low-frequency applications are limited because of internal propagation delays", "optb": "high-frequency applications are limited because of internal propagation delays", "optc": "asynchronous counters do not have major drawbacks and are suitable for use in high- and low-frequency counting applications", "optd": "asynchronous counters do not have propagation delays and this limits their use in high-frequency applications", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Once an up-/down-counter begins its count sequence, it cannot be reversed.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Three cascaded modulus-5 counters have an overall modulus of ________.", "opta": "5", "optb": "25", "optc": "125", "optd": "500", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An asynchronous 4-bit binary down counter changes from count 2 to count 3. How many transitional states are required?", "opta": "None", "optb": "One", "optc": "Two", "optd": "Fifteen", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The final output of a modulus-8 counter occurs one time for every ________.", "opta": "8 clock pulses", "optb": "16 clock pulses", "optc": "24 clock pulses", "optd": "32 clock pulses", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 4-bit up/down binary counter is in the DOWN mode and in the 1100 state. To what state does the counter go on the next clock pulse?", "opta": "1101", "optb": "1011", "optc": "1111", "optd": "0000", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 4-bit ripple counter consists of flip-flops, which each have a propagation delay from clock to Q output of 15 ns. For the counter to recycle from 1111 to 0000, it takes a total of ________.", "opta": "15 ns", "optb": "30 ns", "optc": "45 ns", "optd": "60 ns", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The terminal count of a 3-bit binary counter in the DOWN mode is ________.", "opta": "000", "optb": "111", "optc": "101", "optd": "010", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The hexadecimal equivalent of 15,536 is ________.", "opta": "3CB0", "optb": "3C66", "optc": "63C0", "optd": "6300", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an HDL ring counter, many invalid states are included in the programming by:", "opta": "using a case statement.", "optb": "using an elsif statement.", "optc": "including them under others.", "optd": "the ser_in line.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a VHDL retriggerable edge-triggered one-shot, which condition will not exist when a clock edge occurs?", "opta": "A trigger edge has occurred and we must load the counter.", "optb": "The counter is zero and we need to keep it at zero.", "optc": "The shift register is reset.", "optd": "The counter is not zero and we need to count down by one.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What function does the CTR DIV 8 circuit given below perform?", "opta": "It divides the clock frequency down to match the frequency of the serial data in.", "optb": "The divide-by-8 counter is triggered by the control flip-flop and clock, which then allows the data output register to begin storing the input data. Once all eight data bits are stored in the data output register, the data output register and the divide-by-8 counter trigger the one-shot. The one-shot then begins the process all over again.", "optc": "The divide-by-8 counter is used to verify that the parity bit is attached to the input data string.", "optd": "It keeps track of the eight data bits, triggering the transfer of the data through the output register and the one-shot, which then resets the control flip-flop and divide-by-8 counter.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Synchronous (parallel) counters eliminate the delay problems encountered with asynchronous (ripple) counters because the:", "opta": "input clock pulses are applied only to the first and last stages.", "optb": "input clock pulses are applied only to the last stage.", "optc": "input clock pulses are applied simultaneously to each stage.", "optd": "input clock pulses are not used to activate any of the counter stages.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "List the state of each output pin of a 7447 if RBI\u00a0=\u00a00, LT\u00a0=\u00a01, A0\u00a0=\u00a01, A1\u00a0=\u00a00, A2\u00a0=\u00a00, and A3\u00a0=\u00a01.", "opta": "RBO\u00a0=\u00a00, a\u00a0=\u00a00, b\u00a0=\u00a00, c\u00a0=\u00a00, d\u00a0=\u00a01, e\u00a0=\u00a01, f\u00a0=\u00a00, g\u00a0=\u00a00", "optb": "RBO\u00a0=\u00a01, a\u00a0=\u00a00, b\u00a0=\u00a00, c\u00a0=\u00a00, d\u00a0=\u00a01, e\u00a0=\u00a01, f\u00a0=\u00a00, g\u00a0=\u00a00", "optc": "RBO\u00a0=\u00a00, a\u00a0=\u00a00, b\u00a0=\u00a00, c\u00a0=\u00a00, d\u00a0=\u00a00, e\u00a0=\u00a01, f\u00a0=\u00a00, g\u00a0=\u00a00", "optd": "RBO\u00a0=\u00a01, a\u00a0=\u00a00, b\u00a0=\u00a00, c\u00a0=\u00a00, d\u00a0=\u00a00, e\u00a0=\u00a01, f\u00a0=\u00a00, g\u00a0=\u00a00", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Referring to the given figure, what causes the Control FF to reset after D7?", "opta": "Once the data cycle is initiated by the Start bit, the one-shot produces an output pulse equal to the duration of the eight data bits. Once the eight data bits have been transferred to the data input register, the falling edge of the one-shot pulse resets the Control FF to start the sequence all over again.", "optb": "After counting the eight data bits, the divide-by-8 counter produces an output on its active-LOW CLR line to reset the Control FF.", "optc": "After counting eight clock pulses equivalent to eight data periods, the terminal count of the divide-by-8 counter and the clock trigger the one-shot, which in turn resets the Control FF and divide-by-8 circuits to begin the sequence all over again. Simultaneously the data is transferred through the output register.", "optd": "When the data output register is full, it produces an output on its C terminal that triggers the one-shot, which in turn resets the Control FF.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What function will the counter shown below be performing during period \"B\" on the timing diagram?", "opta": "Counting up", "optb": "Counting down", "optc": "Inhibited", "optd": "Loading", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Three cascaded decade counters will divide the input frequency by ________.", "opta": "10", "optb": "20", "optc": "100", "optd": "1,000", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A counter with a modulus of 16 acts as a ________.", "opta": "divide-by-8 counter", "optb": "divide-by-16 counter", "optc": "divide-by-32 counter", "optd": "divide-by-64 counter", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many data bits can be stored in the register shown below?", "opta": "5", "optb": "32", "optc": "31", "optd": "4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between a 7490 and a 7493?", "opta": "7490 is a MOD-10, 7493 is a MOD-16", "optb": "7490 is a MOD-16, 7493 is a MOD-10", "optc": "7490 is a MOD-12, 7493 is a MOD-16", "optd": "7490 is a MOD-10, 7493 is a MOD-12", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A ripple counter's speed is limited by the propagation delay of:", "opta": "each flip-flop", "optb": "all flip-flops and gates", "optc": "the flip-flops only with gates", "optd": "only circuit gates", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Referring to the given figure, at which point is the serial data transferred to the parallel output?", "opta": "W", "optb": "X", "optc": "Y", "optd": "Z", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 4-bit counter has a maximum modulus of ________.", "opta": "3", "optb": "6", "optc": "8", "optd": "16", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements best describes the operation of a synchronous up-/down-counter?", "opta": "The counter can count in either direction, but must continue in that direction once started.", "optb": "The counter can be reversed, but must be reset before counting in the other direction.", "optc": "In general, the counter can be reversed at any point in its counting sequence.", "optd": "The count sequence cannot be reversed, once it has begun, without first resetting the counter to zero.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The parallel outputs of a counter circuit represent the:", "opta": "parallel data word", "optb": "clock frequency", "optc": "counter modulus", "optd": "clock count", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Any divide-by-N counter can be formed by using external gating to ________ at a predetermined number.", "opta": "HIGH", "optb": "reset", "optc": "LOW", "optd": "preset", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A MOD-16 synchronous counter has inputs labeled . These inputs would most probably be used to:", "opta": "reset the counter to 0000 at the end of each count cycle", "optb": "preset the counter to a value determined by the  inputs any time the  is active-HIGH", "optc": "preset the counter to a value determined by the  inputs any time the  is active-LOW", "optd": "reset the counter to 0000 any time  is active-HIGH and  is active-LOW", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many natural states will there be in a 4-bit ripple counter?", "opta": "4", "optb": "8", "optc": "16", "optd": "32", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "List which pins need to be connected together on a 7492 to make a MOD-12 counter.", "opta": "1 to 12, 11 to 6, 9 to 7", "optb": "1 to 12, 12 to 6, 11 to 7", "optc": "1 to 12, 9 to 6, 8 to 7", "optd": "1 to 12", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A principle regarding most display decoders is that when the correct input is present, the related output will switch:", "opta": "HIGH", "optb": "to high impedance", "optc": "to an open", "optd": "LOW", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A modulus-10 counter must have ________.", "opta": "10 flip-flops", "optb": "flip-flops", "optc": "2 flip-flops", "optd": "synchronous clocking", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a one-shot application, how can HDL code be used to make a circuit respond once to each positive transition on its trigger input?", "opta": "By using a counter", "optb": "By using an active clock", "optc": "By using an immediate reload", "optd": "By using edge trapping", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not an example of a truncated modulus?", "opta": "8", "optb": "9", "optc": "11", "optd": "15", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Four cascaded modulus-10 counters have an overall modulus of ________.", "opta": "10", "optb": "100", "optc": "1,000", "optd": "10,000", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the maximum delay that can occur if four flip-flops are connected as a ripple counter and each flip-flop has propagation delays of tPHL = 22 ns and tPLH = 15 ns?", "opta": "15 ns", "optb": "22 ns", "optc": "60 ns", "optd": "88 ns", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements are true?", "opta": "Asynchronous events do not occur at the same time.", "optb": "Asynchronous events are controlled by a clock.", "optc": "Synchronous events do not need a clock to control them.", "optd": "Only asynchronous events need a control clock.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which segments (by letter) of a seven-segment display need to be active in order to display a digit 6?", "opta": "b, c, d, e, f, and g", "optb": "a, c, d, e, f, and g", "optc": "a, b, c, d, and f", "optd": "b, c, d, e, and f", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following groups of logic devices would be the minimum required for a MOD-64 synchronous counter?", "opta": "Five flip-flops, three AND gates", "optb": "Seven flip-flops, five AND gates", "optc": "Four flip-flops, ten AND gates", "optd": "Six flip-flops, four AND gates", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The circuit given below fails to produce data output. The individual flip-flops are checked with a logic probe and pulser, and each checks OK. What could be causing the problem?", "opta": "The data output line may be grounded.", "optb": "One of the clock input lines may be open.", "optc": "One of the interconnect lines between two stages may have a solder bridge to ground.", "optd": "One of the flip-flops may have a solder bridge between its input and Vcc.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 22-MHz clock signal is put into a MOD-16 counter. What is the frequency of the Q output of each stage of the counter?", "opta": "Q1\u00a0=\u00a022 MHz, Q2\u00a0=\u00a011 MHz, Q3\u00a0=\u00a05.5 MHz, Q4\u00a0=\u00a02.75 MHz", "optb": "Q1\u00a0=\u00a011 MHz, Q2\u00a0=\u00a05.5 MHz, Q3\u00a0=\u00a02.75 MHz, Q4\u00a0=\u00a01.375 MHz", "optc": "Q1\u00a0=\u00a011 MHz, Q2\u00a0=\u00a011 MHz, Q3\u00a0=\u00a011 MHz, Q4\u00a0=\u00a011 MHz", "optd": "Q1\u00a0=\u00a022 MHz, Q2\u00a0=\u00a022 MHz, Q3\u00a0=\u00a022 MHz, Q4\u00a0=\u00a022 MHz", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The designation  means that the ________.", "opta": "up count is active-HIGH, the down count is active-LOW", "optb": "up count is active-LOW, the down count is active-HIGH", "optc": "up and down counts are both active-LOW", "optd": "up and down counts are both active-HIGH", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of device is shown below?", "opta": "4-bit bidirectional universal shift register", "optb": "Parallel in/parallel out shift register with bidirectional data flow", "optc": "2-way parallel in/serial out bidirectional register", "optd": "2-bit serial in/4-bit parallel out bidirectional shift register", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why can a synchronous counter operate at a higher frequency than a ripple counter?", "opta": "The flip-flops change one after the other.", "optb": "The flip-flops change at the same time.", "optc": "A synchronous counter cannot operate at higher frequencies.", "optd": "A ripple counter is faster.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A multiplexed display being driven by a logic circuit:", "opta": "accepts data inputs from one line and passes this data to multiple output lines", "optb": "accepts data inputs from several lines and allows one of them at a time to pass to the output", "optc": "accepts data inputs from multiple lines and passes this data to multiple output lines", "optd": "accepts data inputs from several lines and multiplexes this input data to four BCD lines", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is meant by parallel load of a counter?", "opta": "Each FF is loaded with data on a separate clock.", "optb": "The counter is cleared.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an example of a counter with a truncated modulus?", "opta": "8", "optb": "13", "optc": "16", "optd": "32", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a type of shift register counter?", "opta": "Decade", "optb": "Binary", "optc": "Ring", "optd": "BCD", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "MOD-6 and MOD-12 counters and multiples are most commonly used as:", "opta": "frequency counters", "optb": "multiplexed displays", "optc": "digital clocks", "optd": "power consumption meters", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an invalid state in an 8421 BCD counter?", "opta": "0011", "optb": "1001", "optc": "1000", "optd": "1100", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "After 10 clock cycles, and assuming that the DATA input had returned to 0 following the storage sequence, what values would be stored in Q4, Q3, Q2, Q1, Q0 of the register in Figure 7-5?", "opta": "0,1,0,1,1", "optb": "1,1,0,1,0", "optc": "1,0,1,0,1", "optd": "0,0,0,0,0", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many different states does a 2-bit asynchronous counter have?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "8", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 12 MHz clock frequency is applied to a cascaded counter containing a modulus-5 counter, a modulus-8 counter, and a modulus-10 counter. The lowest output frequency possible is ________.", "opta": "10 kHz", "optb": "20 kHz", "optc": "30 kHz", "optd": "60 kHz", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The format used to present the logic output for the various combinations of logic inputs to a gate is called a(n):", "opta": "truth table.", "optb": "input logic function.", "optc": "Boolean constant.", "optd": "Boolean variable.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the basic difference between AHDL and VHDL?", "opta": "ADHL is used in all PLD's.", "optb": "VHDL is used in all PLD's.", "optc": "ADHL is proprietary.", "optd": "VHDL is proprietary.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A small circle on the output of a logic gate is used to represent the:", "opta": "Comparator operation.", "optb": "OR operation.", "optc": "NOT operation.", "optd": "AND operation.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a three-input OR gate, with the input waveforms as shown below, which output waveform is correct?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the figures given below represents a NOR gate?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the figures (a to d) is the DeMorgan equivalent of Figure (e)?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the figures in figure (a to d) is equivalent to figure (e)?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In VHDL, the mode of a port does not define:", "opta": "an input.", "optb": "an output.", "optc": "both an input and an output.", "optd": "the TYPE of the bit.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following equations would accurately describe a 4-input OR gate when A = 1, B = 1, C = 0, and D = 0?", "opta": "1 + 1 + 0 + 0 = 1", "optb": "1 + 1 + 0 + 0 = 01", "optc": "1 + 1 + 0 + 0 = 0", "optd": "1 + 1 + 0 + 0 = 00", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the examples below expresses the distributive law?", "opta": "(A + B) + C = A + (B + C)", "optb": "A(B + C) = AB + AC", "optc": "A + (B + C) = AB + AC", "optd": "A(BC) = (AB) + C", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the examples below expresses the associative law of addition:", "opta": "A + (B + C) = (A + B) + C", "optb": "A + (B + C) = A + (BC)", "optc": "A(BC) = (AB) + C", "optd": "ABC = A + B + C", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How are the statements between BEGIN and END not evaluated in VHDL?", "opta": "Constantly", "optb": "Simultaneously", "optc": "Concurrently", "optd": "Sequentially", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which logic gate does this truth table describe?", "opta": "AND", "optb": "OR", "optc": "NAND", "optd": "NOR", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a 3-input NAND gate, with the input waveforms as shown below, which output waveform is correct?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the figures given below represents a NAND gate?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which timing diagram shown below is correct for an inverter?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A NOR gate with one HIGH input and one LOW input:", "opta": "will output a HIGH", "optb": "functions as an AND", "optc": "will not function", "optd": "will output a LOW", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A NAND gate has:", "opta": "active-LOW inputs and an active-HIGH output.", "optb": "active-LOW inputs and an active-LOW output.", "optc": "active-HIGH inputs and an active-HIGH output.", "optd": "active-HIGH inputs and an active-LOW output.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the figures given below represents an OR gate?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a form of DeMorgan's theorem?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The logic gate that will have HIGH or \"1\" at its output when any one of its inputs is HIGH is a(n):", "opta": "NOR gate", "optb": "OR gate", "optc": "AND gate", "optd": "NOT operation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the symbols shown below represents an AND gate?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a three-input AND gate, with the input waveforms as shown below, which output waveform is correct?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An OR gate with inverted inputs functions as:", "opta": "an AND gate.", "optb": "a NAND gate.", "optc": "a NOR gate.", "optd": "an inverter.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The special software application that translates from HDL into a grid of 1's and 0's, which can be loaded into a PLD, is called a:", "opta": "formatter.", "optb": "compiler.", "optc": "programmable wiring.", "optd": "CPU.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Boolean equation for a NOR function is:", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which step in this reduction process is using DeMorgan's theorem?", "opta": "STEP 1", "optb": "STEP 2", "optc": "STEP 3", "optd": "STEP 4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Simplify the expression  using DeMorgan's theorems.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a three-input NOR gate, with the input waveforms as shown below, which output waveform is correct?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a 4-bit parallel adder, if the carry-in is connected to a logical HIGH, the result is:", "opta": "the same as if the carry-in is tied LOW since the least significant carry-in is ignored.", "optb": "that carry-out will always be HIGH.", "optc": "a one will be added to the final result.", "optd": "the carry-out is ignored.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the first thing you will need if you are going to use a macrofunction?", "opta": "A complicated design project", "optb": "An experienced design engineer", "optc": "Good documentation", "optd": "Experience in HDL", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Perform subtraction on each of the following binary numbers by taking the two's-complement of the number being subtracted and then adding it to the first number.01001\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00110000011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a000111", "opta": "01100\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a010011", "optb": "00110\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a000101", "optc": "10110\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a010101", "optd": "00111\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a000100", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Solving \u201311 + (\u20132) will yield which two's-complement answer?", "opta": "1110 1101", "optb": "1111 1001", "optc": "1111 0011", "optd": "1110 1001", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Multiply the following binary numbers.   1010 \u00a0 1011 \u00a0 1001  \u00d70011 \u00a0 \u00d70111 \u00a0 \u00d71010", "opta": "0001\u00a0\u00a01110\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00100\u00a0\u00a01101\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00101\u00a0\u00a01011", "optb": "0001\u00a0\u00a01110\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00100\u00a0\u00a01100\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00101\u00a0\u00a01010", "optc": "0001\u00a0\u00a01110\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00100\u00a0\u00a01101\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00101\u00a0\u00a01010", "optd": "0001\u00a0\u00a01101\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00100\u00a0\u00a01101\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00101\u00a0\u00a01010", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Add the following BCD numbers.   0110 \u00a0 0111 \u00a0 1001  0101 \u00a0 1000 \u00a0 1000", "opta": "0000\u00a0\u00a01011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00000\u00a0\u00a01111\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00001\u00a0\u00a00001", "optb": "0001\u00a0\u00a00001\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00001\u00a0\u00a00101\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00001\u00a0\u00a00001", "optc": "0000\u00a0\u00a01011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00000\u00a0\u00a01111\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00001\u00a0\u00a00111", "optd": "0001\u00a0\u00a00001\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00001\u00a0\u00a00101\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00001\u00a0\u00a00111", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Add the following hexadecimal numbers.    3C \u00a0 14 \u00a0 3B  +25 \u00a0 +28 \u00a0 +DC", "opta": "60\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a03C\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0116", "optb": "62\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a03C\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0118", "optc": "61\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a03C\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0117", "optd": "61\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a03D\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0117", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Solve this BCD problem: 0100 + 0110 =", "opta": "00010000BCD", "optb": "00010111BCD", "optc": "00001011BCD", "optd": "00010011BCD", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are constants in VHDL code?", "opta": "Fixed numbers represented by a name", "optb": "Fixed variables used in functions", "optc": "Fixed number types", "optd": "Constants do not exist in VHDL code.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 2's-complement system is to be used to add the signed binary numbers 11110010 and 11110011. Determine, in decimal, the sign and value of each number and their sum.", "opta": "\u2013113 and \u2013114, \u2013227", "optb": "\u201314 and \u201313, \u201327", "optc": "\u201311 and \u201316, \u201327", "optd": "\u201327 and \u201313, \u201340", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most commonly used system for representing signed binary numbers is the:", "opta": "2's-complement system.", "optb": "1's-complement system.", "optc": "10's-complement system.", "optd": "sign-magnitude system.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the major difference between half-adders and full-adders?", "opta": "Nothing basically; full-adders are made up of two half-adders.", "optb": "Full adders can handle double-digit numbers.", "optc": "Full adders have a carry input capability.", "optd": "Half adders can handle only single-digit numbers.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The decimal value for E16 is:", "opta": "1210", "optb": "1310", "optc": "1410", "optd": "1510", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fast-look-ahead carry circuits found in most 4-bit full-adder circuits:", "opta": "determine sign and magnitude", "optb": "reduce propagation delay", "optc": "add a 1 to complemented inputs", "optd": "increase ripple delay", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Add the following hex numbers: 011016 + 1001016", "opta": "1012016", "optb": "1002016", "optc": "1112016", "optd": "0012016", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary subtraction 0 \u2013 0 =", "opta": "difference = 0borrow = 0", "optb": "difference = 1borrow = 0", "optc": "difference = 1borrow = 1", "optd": "difference = 0borrow = 1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert each of the decimal numbers to 8-bit two's-complement form and then perform subtraction by taking the two's-complement and adding.", "opta": "0001\u00a0\u00a00011", "optb": "0000\u00a0\u00a01110", "optc": "0010\u00a0\u00a01110", "optd": "1110\u00a0\u00a00000", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Adding in binary, a decimal 26 + 27 will produce a sum of:", "opta": "111010", "optb": "110110", "optc": "110101", "optd": "101011", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert each of the following signed binary numbers (two's-complement) to a signed decimal number.00000101\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a011111100\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a011111000", "opta": "\u20135\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0+4\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0+8", "optb": "+5\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u20134\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u20138", "optc": "\u20135\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0+252\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0+248", "optd": "+5\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u2013252\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u2013248", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many basic binary subtraction operations are possible?", "opta": "4", "optb": "3", "optc": "2", "optd": "1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If [A] = 1011 1010, [B] = 0011 0110, and [C] = [A] \u0095 [B], what is [C 4..2] in decimal?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Using 4-bit adders to create a 1See Section 6-bit adder:", "opta": "requires 16 adders.", "optb": "requires 4 adders.", "optc": "requires the carry-out of the less significant adder to be connected to the carry-in of the next significant adder.", "optd": "requires 4 adders and the connection of the carry out of the less significant adder to the carry-in of the next significant adder.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When performing subtraction by addition in the 2's-complement system:", "opta": "the minuend and the subtrahend are both changed to the 2's-complement.", "optb": "the minuend is changed to 2's-complement and the subtrahend is left in its original form.", "optc": "the minuend is left in its original form and the subtrahend is changed to its 2's-complement.", "optd": "the minuend and subtrahend are both left in their original form.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The two's-complement system is to be used to add the signed numbers 11110010 and 11110011. Determine, in decimal, the sign and value of each number and their sum.", "opta": "\u201314 and \u201313, \u201327", "optb": "\u2013113 and \u2013114, 227", "optc": "\u201327 and \u201313, 40", "optd": "\u201311 and \u201316, \u201327", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When 1100010 is divided by 0101, what is the decimal remainder?", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "4", "optd": "6", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One way to make a four-bit adder perform subtraction is by:", "opta": "inverting the output.", "optb": "inverting the carry-in.", "optc": "inverting the B inputs.", "optd": "grounding the B inputs.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the most important operation in binary-coded decimal (BCD) arithmetic?", "opta": "addition", "optb": "subtraction", "optc": "multiplication", "optd": "division", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The range of positive numbers when using an eight-bit two's-complement system is:", "opta": "0 to 64", "optb": "0 to 100", "optc": "0 to 127", "optd": "0 to 256", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the two types of basic adder circuits?", "opta": "sum and carry", "optb": "half-adder and full-adder", "optc": "asynchronous and synchronous", "optd": "one- and two's-complement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The truth table for a full adder is shown below. What are the values of X, Y, and Z?", "opta": "X = 0, Y = 1, Z = 1", "optb": "X = 1, Y = 1, Z = 1", "optc": "X = 1, Y = 0, Z = 1", "optd": "X = 0, Y = 0, Z = 1", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A half-adder circuit would normally be used each time a carry input is required in an added circuit.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If B[7..0] = 10100101, what is the value of B[6..2]?", "opta": "10100", "optb": "01001", "optc": "10010", "optd": "00101", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many inputs must a full-adder have?", "opta": "4", "optb": "2", "optc": "5", "optd": "3", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "", "opta": "10011110", "optb": "01211110", "optc": "000100000100", "optd": "001000001000", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Determine the two's-complement of each binary number.00110\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a000011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a011101", "opta": "11001\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a011100\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a000010", "optb": "00111\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a000010\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a000010", "optc": "00110\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a000011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a011101", "optd": "11010\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a011101\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a000011", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Solve this binary problem: 01110010 \u2013 01001000 =", "opta": "00011010", "optb": "00101010", "optc": "01110010", "optd": "00111100", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What distinguishes the look-ahead-carry adder?", "opta": "It is slower than the ripple-carry adder.", "optb": "It is easier to implement logically than a full adder.", "optc": "It is faster than a ripple-carry adder.", "optd": "It requires advance knowledge of the final answer.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Solve this binary problem:", "opta": "1001", "optb": "0110", "optc": "0111", "optd": "0101", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Half-adders can be combined to form a full-adder with no additional gates.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Perform the following hex subtraction: ACE16 \u2013 99916 =", "opta": "23516", "optb": "13516", "optc": "03516", "optd": "33516", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct for full adders?", "opta": "Full adders have the capability of directly adding decimal numbers.", "optb": "Full adders are used to make half adders.", "optc": "Full adders are limited to two inputs since there are only two binary digits.", "optd": "In a parallel full adder, the first stage may be a half adder.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert each of the signed decimal numbers to an 8-bit signed binary number (two's-complement).+7\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u20133\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u201312", "opta": "0000\u00a0\u00a00111\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a01111\u00a0\u00a01101\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a01111\u00a0\u00a00100", "optb": "1000\u00a0\u00a00111\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00111\u00a0\u00a01101\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00111\u00a0\u00a00100", "optc": "0000\u00a0\u00a00111\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00000\u00a0\u00a00011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00000\u00a0\u00a01100", "optd": "0000\u00a0\u00a00111\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a01000\u00a0\u00a00011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a01000\u00a0\u00a01100", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is one disadvantage of the ripple-carry adder?", "opta": "The interconnections are more complex.", "optb": "More stages are required to a full adder.", "optc": "It is slow due to propagation time.", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Solve this binary problem: 01000110 \u00f7 00001010 =", "opta": "0111", "optb": "10011", "optc": "1001", "optd": "0011", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Divide the following binary numbers.", "opta": "0000\u00a0\u00a00010\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00000\u00a0\u00a00010\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a01000\u00a0\u00a01111", "optb": "0000\u00a0\u00a00010\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00001\u00a0\u00a00010\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00000\u00a0\u00a00100", "optc": "0000\u00a0\u00a00011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00000\u00a0\u00a00010\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00000\u00a0\u00a00100", "optd": "0000\u00a0\u00a00010\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00000\u00a0\u00a00010\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00000\u00a0\u00a00100", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the decimal numbers 275 and 965 to binary-coded decimal (BCD) and add. Select the BCD code groups that reflect the final answer.", "opta": "1101 1110 1010", "optb": "1110 1010 1110", "optc": "0001 0010 0100 0000", "optd": "0010 0011 0100 0000", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When multiplying 13 \u00d7 11 in binary, what is the third partial product?", "opta": "1011", "optb": "00000000", "optc": "100000", "optd": "100001", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many BCD adders would be required to add the numbers 97310 + 3910?", "opta": "3", "optb": "4", "optc": "5", "optd": "6", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The selector inputs to an arithmetic/logic unit (ALU) determine the:", "opta": "selection of the IC", "optb": "arithmetic or logic function", "optc": "data word selection", "optd": "clock frequency to be used", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is wrong, if anything, with the circuit in the given figure based on the logic analyzer display accompanying the circuit?", "opta": "The CO terminal is shorted to ground.", "optb": "The S1 output is shorted to Vcc.", "optc": "The P1 input is not being added into the total.", "optd": "Nothing is wrong; the circuit is functioning correctly.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the statements below best describes the given figure?", "opta": "Half-carry adder; Sum = 0, Carry = 1", "optb": "Half-carry adder; Sum = 1, Carry = 0", "optc": "Full-carry adder; Sum = 1, Carry = 0", "optd": "Full-carry adder; Sum = 1, Carry = 1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An 8-bit register may provide storage for two's-complement codes within which decimal range?", "opta": "+128 to \u2013128", "optb": "\u2013128 to +127", "optc": "+128 to \u2013127", "optd": "+127 to \u2013127", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A full-adder adds ________.", "opta": "two single bits and one carry bit", "optb": "two 2-bit binary numbers", "optc": "two 4-bit binary numbers", "optd": "two 2-bit numbers and one carry bit", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The carry propagation delay in 4-bit full-adder circuits:", "opta": "is cumulative for each stage and limits the speed at which arithmetic operations are performed", "optb": "is normally not a consideration because the delays are usually in the nanosecond range", "optc": "decreases in direct ratio to the total number of full-adder stages", "optd": "increases in direct ratio to the total number of full-adder stages, but is not a factor in limiting the speed of arithmetic operations", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An input to the mode pin of an arithmetic/logic unit (ALU) determines if the function will be:", "opta": "one's-complemented", "optb": "arithmetic or logic", "optc": "positive or negative", "optd": "with or without carry", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Could the sum output of a full-adder be used as a two-bit parity generator?", "opta": "Yes", "optb": "No", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In VHDL, what is a GENERATE statement?", "opta": "The start statement of a program", "optb": "Not used in VHDL or ADHL", "optc": "A way to get the computer to generate a program from a circuit diagram", "optd": "A way to tell the compiler to replicate several components", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Binary subtraction of a decimal 15 from 43 will utilize which two's complement?", "opta": "101011", "optb": "110000", "optc": "011100", "optd": "110001", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the primary advantage of using binary-coded decimal (BCD) instead of straight binary coding?", "opta": "Fewer bits are required to represent a decimal number with the BCD code.", "optb": "BCD codes are easily converted from decimal.", "optc": "the relative ease of converting to and from decimal", "optd": "BCD codes are easily converted to straight binary codes.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many inputs must a full-adder have?", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert each of the decimal numbers to two's-complement form and perform the addition in binary.  +13\u00a0\u201310 add \u20137\u00a0add +15", "opta": "0001\u00a0\u00a00100\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00000\u00a0\u00a00101", "optb": "0000\u00a0\u00a00110\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00001\u00a0\u00a01001", "optc": "0000\u00a0\u00a00110\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00000\u00a0\u00a00101", "optd": "1111\u00a0\u00a00110\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a01111\u00a0\u00a00101", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Add the following binary numbers.   0010 0110 \u00a0 0011 1011 \u00a0 0011 1100  +0101 0101 \u00a0 +0001 1110 \u00a0 +0001 1111", "opta": "0111 1011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00100\u00a0\u00a00001\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00101\u00a0\u00a01011", "optb": "0111 1011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00101\u00a0\u00a01001\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00101\u00a0\u00a01011", "optc": "0111 0111\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00101\u00a0\u00a01001\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00101\u00a0\u00a01011", "optd": "0111 0111\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00100\u00a0\u00a00001\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00101\u00a0\u00a01011", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The carry propagation delay in full-adder circuits:", "opta": "is normally not a consideration because the delays are usually in the nanosecond range.", "optb": "decreases in a direct ratio to the total number of FA stages.", "optc": "is cumulative for each stage and limits the speed at which arithmetic operations are performed.", "optd": "increases in a direct ratio to the total number of FA stages but is not a factor in limiting the speed of arithmetic operations.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between a full-adder and a half-adder?", "opta": "Half-adder has a carry-in.", "optb": "Full-adder has a carry-in.", "optc": "Half-adder does not have a carry-out.", "optd": "Full-adder does not have a carry-out.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The summing outputs of a half- or full-adder are designated by which Greek symbol?", "opta": "omega", "optb": "theta", "optc": "lambda", "optd": "sigma", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Subtract the following hexadecimal numbers.    47 \u00a0 34 \u00a0 FA  \u201325 \u00a0 \u20131C \u00a0 \u20132F", "opta": "22\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a018\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0CB", "optb": "22\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a017\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0CB", "optc": "22\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a019\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0CB", "optd": "22\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a018\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0CC", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the correct output of the adder in the given figure, with the outputs in the order:", "opta": "10111", "optb": "11101", "optc": "01101", "optd": "10011", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Solve this binary problem:", "opta": "11001001", "optb": "10010000", "optc": "01101110", "optd": "01110110", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The BCD addition of 910 and 710 will give initial code groups of 1001 + 0111. Addition of these groups generates a carry to the next higher position. The correct solution to this problem would be to:", "opta": "ignore the lowest order code group because 0000 is a valid code group and prefix the carry with three zeros", "optb": "add 0110 to both code groups to validate the carry from the lowest order code group", "optc": "disregard the carry and add 0110 to the lowest order code group", "optd": "add 0110 to the lowest order code group because a carry was generated and then prefix the carry with three zeros", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Subtract the following binary numbers.   0101 1000 \u00a0 1010 0011 \u00a0 1101 1110  \u20130010 0011 \u00a0 \u20130011 1000 \u00a0 \u20130101 0111", "opta": "0011\u00a0\u00a00100\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00110\u00a0\u00a01010\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a01000\u00a0\u00a00110", "optb": "0011\u00a0\u00a00101\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00110\u00a0\u00a01011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a01000\u00a0\u00a00111", "optc": "0011\u00a0\u00a00101\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00110\u00a0\u00a01010\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a01000\u00a0\u00a00111", "optd": "0011\u00a0\u00a00101\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00110\u00a0\u00a01010\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a01000\u00a0\u00a00110", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why is a fast-look-ahead carry circuit used in the 7483 4-bit full-adder?", "opta": "to decrease the cost", "optb": "to make it smaller", "optc": "to slow down the circuit", "optd": "to speed up the circuit", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Find the 2's complement of \u20131101102.", "opta": "1101002", "optb": "1010102", "optc": "0010012", "optd": "0010102", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What logic function is the sum output of a half-adder?", "opta": "AND", "optb": "exclusive-OR", "optc": "exclusive-NOR", "optd": "NAND", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary adder circuit is designed to add ________ binary numbers at the same time.", "opta": "2", "optb": "4", "optc": "6", "optd": "8", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Any number with an exponent of zero is equal to:", "opta": "zero", "optb": "one", "optc": "that number", "optd": "ten", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the decimal numbering system, what is the MSD?", "opta": "The middle digit of a stream of numbers", "optb": "The digit to the right of the decimal point", "optc": "The last digit on the right", "optd": "The digit with the most weight", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements does NOT describe an advantage of digital technology?", "opta": "The values may vary over a continuous range.", "optb": "The circuits are less affected by noise.", "optc": "The operation can be programmed.", "optd": "Information storage is easy.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The generic array logic (GAL) device is ________.", "opta": "one-time programmable", "optb": "reprogrammable", "optc": "a CMOS device", "optd": "reprogrammable and a CMOS device", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The range of voltages between VL(max) and VH(min) are ________.", "opta": "unknown", "optb": "unnecessary", "optc": "unacceptable", "optd": "between 2 V and 5 V", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is a digital-to-analog converter?", "opta": "It takes the digital information from an audio CD and converts it to a usable form.", "optb": "It allows the use of cheaper analog techniques, which are always simpler.", "optc": "It stores digital data on a hard drive.", "optd": "It converts direct current to alternating current.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "A DAC converts an abstract finite-precision number (usually a fixed-point binary number) into a concrete physical quantity (e.g., a voltage or a pressure)."}, {"question": "What are the symbols used to represent digits in the binary number system?", "opta": "0,1", "optb": "0,1,2", "optc": "0 through 8", "optd": "1,2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A full subtracter circuit requires ________.", "opta": "two inputs and two outputs", "optb": "two inputs and three outputs", "optc": "three inputs and one output", "optd": "three inputs and two outputs", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of an AND gate is LOW ________.", "opta": "all the time", "optb": "when any input is LOW", "optc": "when any input is HIGH", "optd": "when all inputs are HIGH", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Give the decimal value of binary 10010.", "opta": "610", "optb": "910", "optc": "1810", "optd": "2010", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Parallel format means that:", "opta": "each digital signal has its own conductor.", "optb": "several digital signals are sent on each conductor.", "optc": "both binary and hexadecimal can be used.", "optd": "no clock is needed.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A decoder converts ________.", "opta": "noncoded information into coded form", "optb": "coded information into noncoded form", "optc": "HIGHs to LOWs", "optd": "LOWs to HIGHs", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A DAC changes ________.", "opta": "an analog signal into digital data", "optb": "digital data into an analog signal", "optc": "digital data into an amplified signal", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of a NOT gate is HIGH when ________.", "opta": "the input is LOW", "optb": "the input is HIGH", "optc": "the input changes from LOW to HIGH", "optd": "voltage is removed from the gate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of an OR gate is LOW when ________.", "opta": "all inputs are LOW", "optb": "any input is LOW", "optc": "any input is HIGH", "optd": "all inputs are HIGH", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an analog device?", "opta": "Thermocouple", "optb": "Current flow in a circuit", "optc": "Light switch", "optd": "Audio microphone", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A demultiplexer has ________.", "opta": "one data input and a number of selection inputs, and they have several outputs", "optb": "one input and one output", "optc": "several inputs and several outputs", "optd": "several inputs and one output", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A flip-flop has ________.", "opta": "one stable state", "optb": "no stable states", "optc": "two stable states", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Digital signals transmitted on a single conductor (and a ground) must be transmitted in:", "opta": "slow speed.", "optb": "parallel.", "optc": "analog.", "optd": "serial.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a certain digital waveform, the period is four times the pulse width. The duty cycle is ________.", "opta": "0%", "optb": "25%", "optc": "50%", "optd": "100%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In positive logic, ________.", "opta": "a HIGH = 1, a LOW = 0", "optb": "a LOW = 1, a HIGH = 0", "optc": "only HIGHs are present", "optd": "only LOWs are present", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the fractional binary number 0000.1010 to decimal.", "opta": "0.625", "optb": "0.50", "optc": "0.55", "optd": "0.10", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Digital representations of numerical values of quantities may BEST be described as having characteristics:", "opta": "that are difficult to interpret because they are continuously changing.", "optb": "that vary constantly over a continuous range of values.", "optc": "that vary in constant and direct proportion to the values they represent.", "optd": "that vary in discrete steps in proportion to the values they represent.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A common instrument used in troubleshooting a digital circuit is a(n) ________.", "opta": "logic probe", "optb": "oscilloscope", "optc": "pulser", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The parallel transmission of digital data:", "opta": "is much slower than the serial transmission of data.", "optb": "requires only one signal line between sender and receiver.", "optc": "requires as many signal lines between sender and receiver as there are data bits.", "optd": "is less expensive than the serial method of data transmission.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the fractional decimal number 6.75 to binary.", "opta": "0111.1100", "optb": "0110.1010", "optc": "0110.1100", "optd": "0110.0110", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is one relative disadvantage of serial transfer?", "opta": "It requires too many conductors.", "optb": "Its interconnect system is complex.", "optc": "It is slow.", "optd": "It can only be used over very short distances.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which format requires fewer conductors?", "opta": "Parallel", "optb": "Serial", "optc": "Both are the same", "optd": "Cannot tell", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A pulse has a period of 15 ms. Its frequency is ________.", "opta": "6.66 Hz", "optb": "66.66 Hz", "optc": "666.66 Hz", "optd": "15 Hz", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Give the decimal value of binary 10000110.", "opta": "13410", "optb": "14410", "optc": "11010", "optd": "12610", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The rise time is the time it takes a pulse to go from ________.", "opta": "the base line to the maximum HIGH voltage", "optb": "10% of the pulse amplitude to the maximum HIGH voltage", "optc": "the base line to 90% of the pulse amplitude", "optd": "10% of the pulse amplitude to 90% of the pulse amplitude", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is an analog-to-digital converter?", "opta": "It makes digital signals.", "optb": "It takes analog signals and puts them in digital format.", "optc": "It allows the use of digital signals in everyday life.", "optd": "It stores information on a CD.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A multiplexer has ________.", "opta": "one input and several outputs", "optb": "one input and one output", "optc": "several inputs and several outputs", "optd": "several inputs and one output", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the decimal value of 23 ?", "opta": "2", "optb": "4", "optc": "6", "optd": "8", "ans": "D", "explanation": "23  = 2*2*2=8"}, {"question": "An encoder converts ________.", "opta": "noncoded information into coded form", "optb": "coded information into noncoded form", "optc": "HIGHs to LOWs", "optd": "LOWs to HIGHs", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What kind of logic device or circuit is used to store information?", "opta": "Counter", "optb": "Register", "optc": "Inverter", "optd": "Buffer", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "PLCC packages have leads on ________.", "opta": "one side", "optb": "two sides", "optc": "three sides", "optd": "four sides", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the typical invalid voltage for a binary signal?", "opta": "0.7\u20132.8 volts", "optb": "0.8\u20133 volts", "optc": "0.8\u20132 volts", "optd": "0.7\u20132.5 volts", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the fractional binary number 0001.0010 to decimal.", "opta": "1.40", "optb": "1.125", "optc": "1.20", "optd": "1.80", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the fractional binary number 10010.0100 to decimal.", "opta": "24.50", "optb": "18.25", "optc": "18.40", "optd": "16.25", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many binary bits are necessary to represent 748 different numbers?", "opta": "9", "optb": "7", "optc": "10", "optd": "8", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A periodic digital waveform has a pulse width (tw) of 6 ms and a period (T) of 18 ms. The duty cycle is ________.", "opta": "3.3%", "optb": "33.3%", "optc": "6%", "optd": "18%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Any number with an exponent of one is equal to:", "opta": "zero.", "optb": "one.", "optc": "two.", "optd": "that number.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Serial format means digital signals are:", "opta": "sent over many conductors simultaneously.", "optb": "sent over one conductor sequentially.", "optc": "sent in groups of eight signals.", "optd": "sent in binary coded decimal.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the decimal value of 2\u20131 ?", "opta": "0.5", "optb": "0.25", "optc": "0.05", "optd": "0.1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which format can send several bits of information faster?", "opta": "Parallel", "optb": "Serial", "optc": "Both are the same", "optd": "Cannot tell", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The frequency of a pulse train is 2 kHz. The pulse period is ________.", "opta": "5 ms", "optb": "50 ms", "optc": "500 s", "optd": "2 s", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What has happened to the advances in digital technologies over the past three decades?", "opta": "Slowed down considerably", "optb": "Continued to increase, but at a decreasing rate", "optc": "Made excellent progress", "optd": "Nothing short of phenomenal", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A type of digital circuit technology that uses bipolar junction transistors is ________.", "opta": "TTL", "optb": "CMOS", "optc": "LSI", "optd": "NMOS", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many unique symbols are used in the decimal number system?", "opta": "One", "optb": "Nine", "optc": "Ten", "optd": "Unlimited", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A classification of ICs with complexities of 12 to 100 equivalent gates on a chip is known as ________.", "opta": "SSI", "optb": "MSI", "optc": "LSI", "optd": "VLSI", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a semiconductor memory?", "opta": "RAM", "optb": "MAR", "optc": "CD-ROM", "optd": "CD", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The holes through a PC board are ________.", "opta": "smaller with SMT than with through-hole mounting", "optb": "larger with SMT than with through-hole mounting", "optc": "the same size as with through-hole mounting", "optd": "usually unnecessary", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A classification of ICs with complexities of 100 to 10,000 equivalent gates per chip is known as ________.", "opta": "SSI", "optb": "MSI", "optc": "LSI", "optd": "VLSI", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a flash analog-to-digital converter, the output of each comparator is connected to an input of a ________.", "opta": "decoder", "optb": "priority encoder", "optc": "multiplexer", "optd": "demultiplexer", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which term applies to the maintaining of a given signal level until the next sampling?", "opta": "Holding", "optb": "Aliasing", "optc": "Shannon frequency sampling", "optd": "\"Stair-stepping\"", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An op-amp has very ________.", "opta": "high voltage gain", "optb": "high input impedance", "optc": "low output impedance", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a 4-bit DAC, the least significant bit (LSB) is ________.", "opta": "6.25% of full scale", "optb": "0.625% of full scale", "optc": "12% of full scale", "optd": "1.2% of full scale", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The dual-slope analog-to-digital converter finds extensive use in ________.", "opta": "digital voltmeters", "optb": "function generators", "optc": "frequency counters", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ADC0804 is an example of a ________.", "opta": "single-slope analog-to-digital converter", "optb": "dual-slope analog-to-digital converter", "optc": "digital-ramp analog-to-digital converter", "optd": "successive-approximation analog-to-digital converter", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a digital representation of voltages using an 8-bit binary code, how many values can be defined?", "opta": "16", "optb": "64", "optc": "128", "optd": "256", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 4-bit R/2R ladder digital-to-analog converter uses ________.", "opta": "one resistor value", "optb": "two resistor values", "optc": "three resistor values", "optd": "four resistor values", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A binary-weighted-input digital-to-analog converter has a feedback resistor, Rf, of 12 k. If 50 A of current is through the resistor, voltage out of the circuit is ________.", "opta": "0.6 V", "optb": "\u20130.6 V", "optc": "0.1 V", "optd": "\u20130.1 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The resolution of a 6-bit DAC is ________.", "opta": "63%", "optb": "64%", "optc": "15.9%", "optd": "1.59%", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of ADC quantizes the analog signal into a stream of bits whose amount corresponds to the signal level?", "opta": "Successive approximation", "optb": "Sigma-delta", "optc": "Dual-slope", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A binary-weighted-input digital-to-analog converter has an input resistor of 100 k. If the resistor is connected to a 5 V source, current through the resistor is ________.", "opta": "50 mA", "optb": "50 A", "optc": "5 mA", "optd": "500 A", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In troubleshooting a DAC, we check its performance characteristics, such as ________.", "opta": "nonmonotonicity", "optb": "differential nonlinearity", "optc": "low and high gain", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a digital reproduction of an analog curve, accuracy can be increased by ________.", "opta": "sampling the curve more often", "optb": "sampling the curve less often", "optc": "decreasing the number of bits used to represent each sampled value", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a 4-bit R/2R ladder digital-to-analog converter, because of negative feedback, the operational amplifier keeps the inverting (minus) input near ________.", "opta": "5 volts", "optb": "zero volts", "optc": "a voltage determined by the binary weighted input", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the result of taking more samples during the quantization process?", "opta": "More errors in the analog-to-digital conversion", "optb": "More bit requirements", "optc": "More accurate signal representation", "optd": "More bit requirements and more accurate signal representation", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which A/D conversion method has a fixed conversion time?", "opta": "Single-slope analog-to-digital converter", "optb": "Dual-slope analog-to-digital converter", "optc": "Digital-ramp analog-to-digital converter", "optd": "Successive-approximation analog-to-digital converter", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is a typical application of digital signal processing?", "opta": "Noise elimination", "optb": "Music signal processing", "optc": "Image processing", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a DAC has a full-scale, or maximum, output of 12 V and accuracy of 0.1%, then the maximum error for any output voltage is ________.", "opta": "12 V", "optb": "120 mV", "optc": "12 mV", "optd": "0 V", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do we call the manipulation of an analog signal in a digital domain?", "opta": "Analog-to-digital conversion", "optb": "Digital-to-analog conversion", "optc": "Digital signal processing", "optd": "Signal filtering", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How are unwanted frequencies removed prior to digital conversion?", "opta": "Pre-filters", "optb": "Digital signal processing", "optc": "Sample-and-hold circuits", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of programming is typically used for digital signal processors?", "opta": "Assembly language", "optb": "Machine language", "optc": "C", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following best defines Nyquist frequency?", "opta": "The frequency of resonance for the filtering circuit", "optb": "The second harmonic", "optc": "The lower frequency limit of sampling", "optd": "The highest frequency component of a given analog signal", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not an A/D conversion error?", "opta": "Differential nonlinearity", "optb": "Missing code", "optc": "Incorrect code", "optd": "Offset", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Settling time is normally defined as the time it takes a DAC to settle within ________.", "opta": "1/8 LSB of its final value when a change occurs in the input code", "optb": "1/4 LSB of its final value when a change occurs in the input code", "optc": "1/2 LSB of its final value when a change occurs in the input code", "optd": "1 LSB of its final value when a change occurs in the input code", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a frequency counter, what happens at high frequencies when the sampling interval is too long?", "opta": "The counter works fine.", "optb": "The counter undercounts the frequency.", "optc": "The measurement is less precise.", "optd": "The counter overflows.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the digital clock project, when does the PM indicator go high?", "opta": "Never", "optb": "Going from 11:59:59 to 12:00:00", "optc": "Going from 12:59:59 to 01:00:00", "optd": "On the falling edge of the clock after enable goes high", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is the output frequency related to the sampling interval of a frequency counter?", "opta": "Directly with the sampling interval", "optb": "Inversely with the sampling interval", "optc": "More precision with longer sampling interval", "optd": "Less precision with longer sampling interval", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an HDL application of a stepper motor, after an up/down counter is built what is done next?", "opta": "Build the sequencer", "optb": "Test it on a simulator", "optc": "Test the decoder", "optd": "Design an intermediate integer variable", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a digital clock application, the basic frequency must be divided down to:", "opta": "1 Hz.", "optb": "60 Hz.", "optc": "100 Hz.", "optd": "1000 Hz.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the keypad application, what does the data signal define?", "opta": "The row and column encoded data", "optb": "The ring encoded data", "optc": "The freeze locator data", "optd": "The ring counter data", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does the ring counter in the HDL keypad application do when a key is pressed?", "opta": "Count to find the row", "optb": "Freeze", "optc": "Count to find the column", "optd": "Start the D flip-flop", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the digital clock project, the purpose of the frequency prescaler is to:", "opta": "find the basic frequency.", "optb": "transform a 60 pps input to a 1 pps timing signal.", "optc": "prevent the clock from exceeding 12:59:59.", "optd": "allow the BCD display to have a value from 00\u201359.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a step that should be followed in project management?", "opta": "Overall definition", "optb": "System documentation", "optc": "Synthesis and testing", "optd": "System integration", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the keypad application, what does the preset state of the ring counter define?", "opta": "The proper output of the column encoder", "optb": "The NANDing of the rows", "optc": "The NANDing of the columns", "optd": "The proper output of the row encoder", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an HDL stepper motor design, why is there more than one mode?", "opta": "To change the speed of the stepper motor", "optb": "To change the direction of the stepper motor", "optc": "To direct drive the stepper motor", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a major block of an HDL frequency counter?", "opta": "Display register", "optb": "Decoder/display", "optc": "Timing and control unit", "optd": "Bit shifter", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a full-step sequence involving two flip-flops driving four coils of a stepper motor, how far will the stepper motor step?", "opta": "90\u00b0", "optb": "45\u00b0", "optc": "30\u00b0", "optd": "15\u00b0", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a step used to define the scope of an HDL project?", "opta": "Are the inputs and outputs active HIGH or active LOW?", "optb": "A clear vision of how to make each block work", "optc": "What are the speed requirements?", "optd": "How many bits of data are needed?", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the digital clock project, what is the frequency of the MOD-6 counter in the minutes section?", "opta": "1 pulse per minute", "optb": "6 pulses per minute", "optc": "10 pulses per minute", "optd": "1 pulse per hour", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why should a real hardware functional test be performed on the HDL stepper motor design?", "opta": "To check the speed of the software", "optb": "To check the current levels in the motor", "optc": "To check the voltage levels of the real outputs", "optd": "To provide a fully operational system", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does the major block of an HDL code emulation of a keypad include?", "opta": "A sequencer", "optb": "A clock", "optc": "A multiplexer", "optd": "A ring counter", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The accuracy of the frequency counter depends on the:", "opta": "system clock frequency.", "optb": "number of displayed digits.", "optc": "sampling rate.", "optd": "display update rate.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the frequency counter, if the clock generator produces a 100 kHz system clock signal, how many decade counters are required to measure 1 Hz?", "opta": "6", "optb": "5", "optc": "4", "optd": "3", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What must a stepper motor HDL application include?", "opta": "Variables and processes", "optb": "Types and bits", "optc": "Counters and decoders", "optd": "Sequencers and multiplexers", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a step in strategic planning for HDL development?", "opta": "There must be a way to test each piece.", "optb": "Each block must fit together to make up the whole system.", "optc": "The names of each input and output must be known.", "optd": "The exact operation of each block must be thoroughly defined and understood.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the frequency counter, when is the new count stored in the display register?", "opta": "After disabling the counter", "optb": "When the count buffer is full", "optc": "After the sample interval is set", "optd": "When the timing and control block has put it there", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are two ways to remember the current state of a counter in VHDL?", "opta": "With FUNCTIONS and PROCESS", "optb": "With counters and timers", "optc": "With SIGNAL and VARIABLE", "optd": "With bit types", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the digital clock project, what type of counter is used to count to 59 seconds?", "opta": "MOD-60", "optb": "MOD-6", "optc": "BCD", "optd": "BCD followed by a MOD-6", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the keypad application, when all columns are HIGH, the ring counter is enabled and counting, and dav is LOW, what is the status of the d outputs?", "opta": "On", "optb": "Off", "optc": "Hi-Z", "optd": "1011", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the frequency counter, what is the function of the Schmitt trigger circuit?", "opta": "To reduce input noise", "optb": "To condition the input signal", "optc": "To convert non-square waveforms", "optd": "To provide a usable signal to the display unit", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "List three basic blocks in the digital clock project.", "opta": "MOD-60, MOD-12 counters", "optb": "MOD-5, MOD-10, MOD-12 counters", "optc": "MOD-60, MOD-10 counters", "optd": "MOD-6, MOD-12, and MOD-10 counters", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When designing an HDL digital system, which is the worst mistake one can make?", "opta": "Concluding that a fundamental block works perfectly", "optb": "Failing to provide proper documentation", "optc": "Adding blocks of code prior to testing them", "optd": "Overlooking a possible VARIABLE", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the keypad application, just after the 4 ms mark the simulation imitates the release of the key by changing the column value back to F hex, which causes the d output to go into its Hi-Z state. On the next rising clock edge, what happens to dav?", "opta": "It goes HIGH.", "optb": "It goes LOW.", "optc": "It goes to Hi-Z.", "optd": "It goes to 1111H.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the frequency counter, which is not a control signal from the control and timing block?", "opta": "Clear", "optb": "Enable", "optc": "Reset", "optd": "Store", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Select the statement that best describes the parity method of error detection:", "opta": "Parity checking is best suited for detecting double-bit errors that occur during the transmission of codes from one location to another.", "optb": "Parity checking is not suitable for detecting single-bit errors in transmitted codes.", "optc": "Parity checking is best suited for detecting single-bit errors in transmitted codes.", "optd": "Parity checking is capable of detecting and correcting errors in transmitted codes.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A logic circuit that provides a HIGH output for both inputs HIGH or both inputs LOW is a(n):", "opta": "Ex-NOR gate", "optb": "OR gate", "optc": "Ex-OR gate", "optd": "NAND gate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A logic circuit that provides a HIGH output if one input or the other input, but not both, is HIGH, is a(n):", "opta": "Ex-NOR gate", "optb": "OR gate", "optc": "Ex-OR gate", "optd": "NAND gate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Identify the type of gate below from the equation", "opta": "Ex-NOR gate", "optb": "OR gate", "optc": "Ex-OR gate", "optd": "NAND gate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is odd parity generated differently from even parity?", "opta": "The first output is inverted.", "optb": "The last output is inverted.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Parity systems are defined as either________ or ________ and will add an extra ________ to the digital information being transmitted.", "opta": "positive, negative, byte", "optb": "odd, even, bit", "optc": "upper, lower, digit", "optd": "on, off, decimal", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of gate can be used to add two bits?", "opta": "Ex-OR", "optb": "Ex-NOR", "optc": "Ex-NAND", "optd": "NOR", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why is an exclusive-NOR gate also called an equality gate?", "opta": "The output is false if the inputs are equal.", "optb": "The output is true if the inputs are opposite.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Show from the truth table how an exclusive-OR gate can be used to invert the data on one input if the other input is a special control function.", "opta": "Using A as the control, when A = 0, X is the same as B. When A = 1, X is the same as B.", "optb": "Using A as the control, when A = 0, X is the same as B. When A = 1, X is the inverse of B.", "optc": "Using A as the control, when A = 0, X is the inverse of B. When A = 1, X is the same as B.", "optd": "Using A as the control, when A = 0, X is the inverse of B. When A = 1, X is the inverse of B.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Determine odd parity for each of the following data words: 1011101\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a011110111\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a01001101", "opta": "P = 1, P = 1, P = 0", "optb": "P = 0, P = 0, P = 0", "optc": "P = 1, P = 1, P = 1", "optd": "P = 0, P = 0, P = 1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Ex-NOR is sometimes called the ________.", "opta": "parity gate", "optb": "equality gate", "optc": "inverted OR", "optd": "parity gate or the equality gate", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following logic families has the highest maximum clock frequency?", "opta": "S-TTL", "optb": "AS-TTL", "optc": "HS-TTL", "optd": "HCMOS", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why is the fan-out of CMOS gates frequency dependent?", "opta": "Each CMOS input gate has a specific propagation time and this limits the number of different gates that can be connected to the output of a CMOS gate.", "optb": "When the frequency reaches the critical value, the gate will only be capable of delivering 70% of the normal output voltage and consequently the output power will be one-half of normal; this defines the upper operating frequency.", "optc": "The higher the number of gates attached to the output, the more frequently they will have to be serviced, thus reducing the frequency at which each will be serviced with an input signal.", "optd": "The input gates of the FETs are predominantly capacitive, and as the signal frequency increases the capacitive loading also increases, thereby limiting the number of loads that may be attached to the output of the driving gate.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Logic circuits that are designated as buffers, drivers, or buffer/drivers are designed to have:", "opta": "a greater current/voltage capability than an ordinary logic circuit.", "optb": "greater input current/voltage capability than an ordinary logic circuit.", "optc": "a smaller output current/voltage capability than an ordinary logic.", "optd": "greater input and output current/voltage capability than an ordinary logic circuit.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following will not normally be found on a data sheet?", "opta": "Minimum HIGH level output voltage", "optb": "Maximum LOW level output voltage", "optc": "Minimum LOW level output voltage", "optd": "Maximum HIGH level input current", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following logic families has the shortest propagation delay?", "opta": "S-TTL", "optb": "AS-TTL", "optc": "HS-TTL", "optd": "HCMOS", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following summarizes the important features of ECL?", "opta": "Low noise margin, low output voltage swing, negative voltage operation, fast, and high power consumption", "optb": "Good noise immunity, negative logic, high frequency capability, low power dissipation, and short propagation time", "optc": "Slow propagation time, high frequency response, low power consumption, and high output voltage swings", "optd": "Poor noise immunity, positive supply voltage operation, good low frequency operation, and low power", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What must be done to interface TTL to CMOS?", "opta": "A dropping resistor must be used on the CMOS 12 V supply to reduce it to 5 V for the TTL.", "optb": "As long as the CMOS supply voltage is 5 V, they can be interfaced; however, the fan-out of the TTL is limited to five CMOS gates.", "optc": "A 5 V Zener diode must be placed across the inputs of the TTL gates in order to protect them from the higher output voltages of the CMOS gates.", "optd": "A pull-up resistor must be used between the TTL output-CMOS input node and Vcc; the value of RP will depend on the number of CMOS gates connected to the node.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What causes low-power Schottky TTL to use less power than the 74XX series TTL?", "opta": "The Schottky-clamped transistor", "optb": "Nothing. The 74XX series uses less power.", "optc": "A larger value resistor", "optd": "Using NAND gates", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the major differences between the 5400 and 7400 series of ICs?", "opta": "The 5400 series are military grade and require tighter supply voltages and temperatures.", "optb": "The 5400 series are military grade and allow for a wider range of supply voltages and temperatures.", "optc": "The 7400 series are an improvement over the original 5400s.", "optd": "The 7400 series was originally developed by Texas Instruments. The 5400 series was brought out by National Semiconductors after TI's patents expired, as a second supply source.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements apply to CMOS devices?", "opta": "The devices should not be inserted into circuits with the power on.", "optb": "All tools, test equipment, and metal workbenches should be tied to earth ground.", "optc": "The devices should be stored and shipped in antistatic tubes or conductive foam.", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What must be done to interface CMOS to TTL?", "opta": "A dropping resistor must be used on the CMOS 12 V supply to reduce it to 5 V for the TTL.", "optb": "As long as the CMOS supply voltage is 5 V, they can be interfaced; however, the fan-out of the CMOS is limited to two TTL gates.", "optc": "A 5 V Zener diode must be placed across the inputs of the TTL gates in order to protect them from the higher output voltages of the CMOS gates.", "optd": "The two series cannot be interfaced without the use of special interface buffers designed for that purpose, such as the open-collector buffers.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the static charge that can be stored by your body as you walk across a carpet?", "opta": "300 volts", "optb": "3,000 volts", "optc": "30,000 volts", "optd": "Over 30,000 volts", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of circuit is shown below, and how is the output ordinarily connected?", "opta": "It is an open-collector gate and is used to drive loads that cannot be connected directly to Vcc due to high noise levels.", "optb": "It represents an active-LOW inverter and is used in negative logic systems.", "optc": "It is an open-collector gate. An external load must be connected between the output terminal and an appropriate supply voltage.", "optd": "Any of the above could be correct, depending on the specific application involved.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of circuit is represented in the given figure, and which statement best describes its operation?", "opta": "It is a tristate inverter. When the ENABLE input is HIGH, the output is effectively an open circuit\u2014it is neither LOW nor HIGH.", "optb": "It is a programmable inverter. It can be programmed to function as either an active LOW or an active HIGH inverter.", "optc": "It is an active LOW buffer, which can be turned on and off by the ENABLE input.", "optd": "None of the above.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following logic families has the highest noise margin?", "opta": "TTL", "optb": "LS TTL", "optc": "CMOS", "optd": "HCMOS", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A \"floating\" TTL input may be defined as:", "opta": "unused input that is tied to Vcc through a 1 k  resistor.", "optb": "unused input that is tied to used inputs.", "optc": "unused input that is tied to the ground.", "optd": "unused input that is not connected.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the logic families listed below allows the highest operating frequency?", "opta": "74AS", "optb": "ECL", "optc": "HCMOS", "optd": "54S", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Refer to the given figure. What type of output arrangement is being used for the output?", "opta": "Complementary-symmetry", "optb": "Push-pull", "optc": "Quasi push-pull", "optd": "Totem-pole", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Refer the given figure. Which of the following describes the operation of the circuit?", "opta": "A LOW input turns Q1 and Q3 on; Q2 and Q4 are off.", "optb": "A LOW input turns Q1 and Q4 off; Q2 and Q3 are on.", "optc": "A HIGH input turns Q1, Q2, and Q3 off, and Q4 is on.", "optd": "A HIGH input turns Q1, Q2, and Q4 on; Q3 is off.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of logic circuit is shown below and what logic function is being performed?", "opta": "It is an NMOS AND gate.", "optb": "It is a CMOS AND gate.", "optc": "It is a CMOS NOR gate.", "optd": "It is a PMOS NAND gate.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Whenever a totem-pole TTL output goes from LOW to HIGH, a high-amplitude current spike is drawn from the Vcc supply. How is this effect corrected to a digital circuit?", "opta": "By connecting a radio-frequency capacitor from Vcc to ground.", "optb": "By using a switching power supply", "optc": "By connecting a capacitor from Vout to ground", "optd": "By connecting a large resistor from Vcc to Vout", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of circuit is shown below and which statement best describes its operation?", "opta": "It is a two-input CMOS AND gate with open drain.", "optb": "It is a two-input CMOS buffer with tristate output.", "optc": "It is a CMOS inverter with tristate output.", "optd": "It is a hybrid TTL-CMOS inverter with FET totem-pole output.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the increase in switching speed between 74LS series TTL and 74HC/HCT (High-Speed CMOS)?", "opta": "5", "optb": "10", "optc": "50", "optd": "100", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A logic signal experiences a delay in going through a circuit. The two propagation delay times are defined as:", "opta": "tPLH and tPHL.", "optb": "tDLH and tDHL.", "optc": "tHPL and tlph.", "optd": "tLDH and tHDL.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does ECL stand for?", "opta": "It stands for electron-coupled logic; all of the devices used within the gates are N-type transistors.", "optb": "It stands for emitter-coupled logic; all of the inputs are coupled into the device through the emitters of the input transistors.", "optc": "It stands for emitter-coupled logic; all of the emitters of the input transistors are connected together and each transistor functions as an emitter follower.", "optd": "It stands for energy-coupled logic; the input energy is amplified by the input transistors and allows the device to deliver higher output currents.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is unique about TTL devices such as the 74S00?", "opta": "The gate transistors are silicon (S), and the gates therefore have lower values of leakage current.", "optb": "The S denotes the fact that a single gate is present in the IC rather than the usual package of 2\u20136 gates.", "optc": "The S denotes a slow version of the device, which is a consequence of its higher power rating.", "optd": "The devices use Schottky transistors and diodes to prevent them from going into saturation; this results in faster turn on and turn off times, which translates into higher frequency operation.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Refer to the figure given below. What type of device is shown and what input levels are required to turn the LED off?", "opta": "The device is an open-collector AND gate and requires both inputs to be HIGH in order to turn the LED off.", "optb": "The device is a Schottky AND gate and requires only one low input to turn the LED off.", "optc": "The device is an open-collector AND gate and requires only one low input to turn the LED off.", "optd": "The device is a Schottky open-collector AND gate and requires a low on both inputs to turn the LED off.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Generally, the voltage measured at an unused TTL input would typically be measured between:", "opta": "1.4 to 1.8 V.", "optb": "0 to 5 V.", "optc": "0 to 1.8 V.", "optd": "0.8 to 5 V.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The IEEE/ANSI notation of an internal underlined diamond denotes:", "opta": "totem-pole outputs.", "optb": "open-collector outputs.", "optc": "quadrature amplifiers.", "optd": "tristate buffers.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bipolar TTL logic family that was developed to increase switching speed by preventing transistor saturation is:", "opta": "emitter-coupled logic (ECL).", "optb": "current-mode logic (CML).", "optc": "transistor-transistor logic (TTL).", "optd": "emitter-coupled logic (ECL) and transistor-transistor logic (TTL).", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a MOSFET terminal?", "opta": "Gate", "optb": "Drain", "optc": "Source", "optd": "Base", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a CMOS gate, which is the best speed-power product?", "opta": "1.4 pJ", "optb": "1.6 pJ", "optc": "2.4 pJ", "optd": "3.3 pJ", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which transistor element is used in CMOS logic?", "opta": "FET", "optb": "MOSFET", "optc": "Bipolar", "optd": "Unijunction", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a TTL circuit, if an excessive number of load gate inputs are connected, ________.", "opta": "VOH(min) drops below VOH", "optb": "VOH drops below VOH(min)", "optc": "VOH exceeds VOH(min)", "optd": "VOH and VOH(min) are unaffected", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The greater the propagation delay, the ________.", "opta": "lower the maximum frequency", "optb": "higher the maximum frequency", "optc": "maximum frequency is unaffected", "optd": "minimum frequency is unaffected", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An open-drain gate is the CMOS counterpart of ________.", "opta": "an open-collector TTL gate", "optb": "a tristate TTL gate", "optc": "a bipolar junction transistor", "optd": "an emitter-coupled logic gate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A TTL NAND gate with IIL(max) of \u20131.6 mA per input drives eight TTL inputs. How much current does the drive output sink?", "opta": "\u201312.8 mA", "optb": "\u20138 mA", "optc": "\u20131.6 mA", "optd": "\u201325.6 mA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The nominal value of the dc supply voltage for TTL and CMOS is ________.", "opta": "+3 V", "optb": "+5 V", "optc": "+9 V", "optd": "+12 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which logic family combines the advantages of CMOS and TTL?", "opta": "BiCMOS", "optb": "TTL/CMOS", "optc": "ECL", "optd": "TTL/MOS", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which equation is correct?", "opta": "VNL = VIL(max) + VOL(max)", "optb": "VNH = VOH(min) + VIH(min)", "optc": "VNL = VOH(min) \u2013 VIH(min)", "optd": "VNH = VOH(min) \u2013 VIH(min)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The active switching element used in all TTL circuits is the ________.", "opta": "bipolar junction transistor (BJT)", "optb": "field-effect transistor (FET)", "optc": "metal-oxide semiconductor field-effect transistor (MOSFET)", "optd": "unijunction transistor (UJ)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An open-collector output requires ________.", "opta": "a pull-down resistor", "optb": "a pull-up resistor", "optc": "no output resistor", "optd": "an output resistor", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most TTL logic used today is some form of ________.", "opta": "Schottky TTL", "optb": "tristate TTL", "optc": "low-power TTL", "optd": "open-collector TTL", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A standard TTL circuit with a totem-pole output can sink, in the LOW state (IOL(max)), ________.", "opta": "16 mA", "optb": "20 mA", "optc": "16 A", "optd": "20 A", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One output structure of a TTL gate is often referred to as a ________.", "opta": "totem-pole arrangement", "optb": "diode arrangement", "optc": "JBT arrangement", "optd": "base, emitter, collector arrangement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It is best not to leave unused TTL inputs unconnected (open) because of TTL's ________.", "opta": "noise sensitivity", "optb": "low-current requirement", "optc": "open-collector outputs", "optd": "tristate construction", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not an output state for tristate logic?", "opta": "HIGH", "optb": "LOW", "optc": "High-Z", "optd": "Low-Z", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "TTL is alive and well, particularly in ________.", "opta": "industrial applications", "optb": "educational applications", "optc": "military applications", "optd": "commercial applications", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A TTL NAND gate with IIH(max) of 40 A per input drives ten TTL inputs. How much current does the drive output source?", "opta": "40 A", "optb": "200 A", "optc": "400 A", "optd": "800 A", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A certain gate draws 1.8 A when its output is HIGH and 3.3 \u00b5A when its output is LOW. VCC is 5 V and the gate is operated on a 50% duty cycle. What is the average power dissipation (PD)?", "opta": "2.55 W", "optb": "1.27 W", "optc": "12.75 W", "optd": "5 W", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "PMOS and NMOS circuits are used largely in ________.", "opta": "MSI functions", "optb": "LSI functions", "optc": "diode functions", "optd": "TTL functions", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If ICCH is specified as 1.1 mA when VCC is 5 V and if the gate is in a static (noncharging) HIGH output state, the power dissipation (PD) of the gate is ________.", "opta": "5.5 mW", "optb": "5.5 W", "optc": "5 mW", "optd": "1.1 mW", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a precaution for handling CMOS?", "opta": "Devices should be placed with pins down on a grounded surface, such as a metal plate.", "optb": "All tools, test equipment, and metal workbenches should be earth grounded.", "optc": "CMOS devices should not be inserted into sockets or PC boards with the power on.", "optd": "Wear wool clothes at all times.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which factor does not affect CMOS loading?", "opta": "Charging time associated with the output resistance of the driving gate", "optb": "Discharging time associated with the output resistance of the driving gate", "optc": "Output capacitance of the load gates", "optd": "Input capacitance of the load gates", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not part of emitter-coupled logic (ECL)?", "opta": "Differential amplifier", "optb": "Bias circuit", "optc": "Emitter-follower circuit", "optd": "Totem-pole circuit", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of an AND gate with three inputs, A, B, and C, is HIGH when ________.", "opta": "A = 1, B = 1, C = 0", "optb": "A = 0, B = 0, C = 0", "optc": "A = 1, B = 1, C = 1", "optd": "A = 1, B = 0, C = 1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a 3-input NOR gate has eight input possibilities, how many of those possibilities will result in a HIGH output?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "7", "optd": "8", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a signal passing through a gate is inhibited by sending a LOW into one of the inputs, and the output is HIGH, the gate is a(n):", "opta": "AND", "optb": "NAND", "optc": "NOR", "optd": "OR", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A device used to display one or more digital signals so that they can be compared to expected timing diagrams for the signals is a:", "opta": "DMM", "optb": "spectrum analyzer", "optc": "logic analyzer", "optd": "frequency counter", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When used with an IC, what does the term \"QUAD\" indicate?", "opta": "2 circuits", "optb": "4 circuits", "optc": "6 circuits", "optd": "8 circuits", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of an OR gate with three inputs, A, B, and C, is LOW when ________.", "opta": "A = 0, B = 0, C = 0", "optb": "A = 0, B = 0, C = 1", "optc": "A = 0, B = 1, C = 1", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following logical operations is represented by the + sign in Boolean algebra?", "opta": "inversion", "optb": "AND", "optc": "OR", "optd": "complementation", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Output will be a LOW for any case when one or more inputs are zero for a(n):", "opta": "OR gate", "optb": "NOT gate", "optc": "AND gate", "optd": "NOR gate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many pins does the 4049 IC have?", "opta": "14", "optb": "16", "optc": "18", "optd": "20", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following choices meets the minimum requirement needed to create specialized waveforms that are used in digital control and sequencing circuits?", "opta": "basic gates, a clock oscillator, and a repetitive waveform generator", "optb": "basic gates, a clock oscillator, and a Johnson shift counter", "optc": "basic gates, a clock oscillator, and a DeMorgan pulse generator", "optd": "basic gates, a clock oscillator, a repetitive waveform generator, and a Johnson shift counter", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "TTL operates from a ________.", "opta": "9-volt supply", "optb": "3-volt supply", "optc": "12-volt supply", "optd": "5-volt supply", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of a NOR gate is HIGH if ________.", "opta": "all inputs are HIGH", "optb": "any input is HIGH", "optc": "any input is LOW", "optd": "all inputs are LOW", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The switching speed of CMOS is now ________.", "opta": "competitive with TTL", "optb": "three times that of TTL", "optc": "slower than TTL", "optd": "twice that of TTL", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The format used to present the logic output for the various combinations of logic inputs to a gate is called a(n):", "opta": "Boolean constant", "optb": "Boolean variable", "optc": "truth table", "optd": "input logic function", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The power dissipation, PD, of a logic gate is the product of the ________.", "opta": "dc supply voltage and the peak current", "optb": "dc supply voltage and the average supply current", "optc": "ac supply voltage and the peak current", "optd": "ac supply voltage and the average supply current", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A logic probe is again applied to the pins of a 7421 IC with the following results. Is there a problem with the circuit and if so, what is the problem?", "opta": "Pin 6 should be ON.", "optb": "Pin 8 should be ON.", "optc": "Pin 8 should be pulsing.", "optd": "no problem", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a 3-input AND gate has eight input possibilities, how many of those possibilities will result in a HIGH output?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "7", "optd": "8", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Boolean expression for a 3-input AND gate is ________.", "opta": "X = AB", "optb": "X = ABC", "optc": "X = A + B + C", "optd": "X = AB + C", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A CMOS IC operating from a 3-volt supply will consume ________.", "opta": "less power than a TTL IC", "optb": "more power than a TTL IC", "optc": "the same power as a TTL IC", "optd": "no power at all", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does the small bubble on the output of the NAND gate logic symbol mean?", "opta": "open collector output", "optb": "tristate", "optc": "The output is inverted.", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the pin numbers of the outputs of the gates in a 7432 IC?", "opta": "3, 6, 10, and 13", "optb": "1, 4, 10, and 13", "optc": "3, 6, 8, and 11", "optd": "1, 4, 8, and 11", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of a NOT gate is HIGH when ________.", "opta": "the input is LOW", "optb": "the input is HIGH", "optc": "power is applied to the gate's IC", "optd": "power is removed from the gate's IC", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the input to a NOT gate is A and the output is X, then ________.", "opta": "X = A", "optb": "", "optc": "X = 0", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A logic probe is used to test the pins of a 7411 IC with the following results. Is there a problem with the chip and if so, what is the problem?", "opta": "Pin 6 should be ON.", "optb": "Pin 6 should be pulsing.", "optc": "Pin 8 should be ON.", "optd": "no problem", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many inputs of a four-input AND gate must be HIGH in order for the output of the logic gate to go HIGH?", "opta": "any one of the inputs", "optb": "any two of the inputs", "optc": "any three of the inputs", "optd": "all four inputs", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the output of a three-input AND gate must be a logic LOW, what must the condition of the inputs be?", "opta": "All inputs must be LOW.", "optb": "All inputs must be HIGH.", "optc": "At least one input must be LOW.", "optd": "At least one input must be HIGH.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Logically, the output of a NOR gate would have the same Boolean expression as a(n):", "opta": "NAND gate immediately followed by an inverter", "optb": "OR gate immediately followed by an inverter", "optc": "AND gate immediately followed by an inverter", "optd": "NOR gate immediately followed by an inverter", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A logic probe is placed on the output of a gate and the display indicator is dim. A pulser is used on each of the input terminals, but the output indication does not change. What is wrong?", "opta": "The dim indication on the logic probe indicates that the supply voltage is probably low.", "optb": "The output of the gate appears to be open.", "optc": "The dim indication is the result of a bad ground connection on the logic probe.", "optd": "The gate is a tristate device.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the Boolean expression for a three-input AND gate?", "opta": "X = A + B + C", "optb": "X = A  \u00b7 B \u00b7 C", "optc": "A \u2013 B \u2013 C", "optd": "A $ B $ C", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following gates has the exact inverse output of the OR gate for all possible input combinations?", "opta": "NOR", "optb": "NOT", "optc": "NAND", "optd": "AND", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between a 7400 and a 7411 IC?", "opta": "7400 has two four-input NAND gates; 7411 has three three-input AND gates", "optb": "7400 has four two-input NAND gates; 7411 has three three-input AND gates", "optc": "7400 has two four-input AND gates; 7411 has three three-input NAND gates", "optd": "7400 has four two-input AND gates; 7411 has three three-input NAND gates", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Write the Boolean expression for an inverter logic gate with input C and output Y.", "opta": "Y = C", "optb": "Y =", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of an exclusive-OR gate is HIGH if ________.", "opta": "all inputs are LOW", "optb": "all inputs are HIGH", "optc": "the inputs are unequal", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A clock signal with a period of 1 s is applied to the input of an enable gate. The output must contain six pulses. How long must the enable pulse be active?", "opta": "Enable must be active for 0 s.", "optb": "Enable must be active for 3 s.", "optc": "Enable must be active for 6 s.", "optd": "Enable must be active for 12 s.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The AND function can be used to ________ and the OR function can be used to ________ .", "opta": "enable, disable", "optb": "disable, enable", "optc": "enable or disable, enable or disable", "optd": "detect, invert", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One advantage TTL has over CMOS is that TTL is ________.", "opta": "less expensive", "optb": "not sensitive to electrostatic discharge", "optc": "faster", "optd": "more widely available", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 2-input NOR gate is equivalent to a ________.", "opta": "negative-OR gate", "optb": "negative-AND gate", "optc": "negative-NAND gate", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a 3-input OR gate has eight input possibilities, how many of those possibilities will result in a HIGH output?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "7", "optd": "8", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fan-out is specified in terms of ________.", "opta": "voltage", "optb": "current", "optc": "wattage", "optd": "unit loads", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many input combinations would a truth table have for a six-input AND gate?", "opta": "32", "optb": "48", "optc": "64", "optd": "128", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the circuit number of the IC that contains four two-input AND gates in standard TTL?", "opta": "7402", "optb": "7404", "optc": "7408", "optd": "7432", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The terms \"low speed\" and \"high speed,\" applied to logic circuits, refer to the ________.", "opta": "rise time", "optb": "fall time", "optc": "propagation delay time", "optd": "clock speed", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The NOR logic gate is the same as the operation of the ________ gate with an inverter connected to the output.", "opta": "OR", "optb": "AND", "optc": "NAND", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The logic expression for a NOR gate is ________.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With regard to an AND gate, which statement is true?", "opta": "An AND gate has two inputs and one output.", "optb": "An AND gate has two or more inputs and two outputs.", "optc": "If one input to a 2-input AND gate is HIGH, the output reflects the other input.", "optd": "A 2-input AND gate has eight input possibilities.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The term \"hex inverter\" refers to:", "opta": "an inverter that has six inputs", "optb": "six inverters in a single package", "optc": "a six-input symbolic logic device", "optd": "an inverter that has a history of failure", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many inputs are on the logic gates of a 74HC21 IC?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The basic logic gate whose output is the complement of the input is the:", "opta": "OR gate", "optb": "AND gate", "optc": "inverter", "optd": "comparator", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When reading a Boolean expression, what does the word \"NOT\" indicate?", "opta": "the same as", "optb": "inversion", "optc": "high", "optd": "low", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of an exclusive-NOR gate is HIGH if ________.", "opta": "the inputs are equal", "optb": "one input is HIGH, and the other input is LOW", "optc": "the inputs are unequal", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many AND gates are found in a 7411 IC?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following equations would accurately describe a four-input OR gate when A = 1, B = 1, C = 0, and D = 0?", "opta": "1 + 1 + 0 + 0 = 01", "optb": "1 + 1 + 0 + 0 = 1", "optc": "1 + 1 + 0 + 0 = 0", "optd": "1 + 1 + 0 + 0 = 00", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the name of a digital circuit that produces several repetitive digital waveforms?", "opta": "an inverter", "optb": "an OR gate", "optc": "a Johnson shift counter", "optd": "an AND gate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The basic types of programmable arrays are made up of ________.", "opta": "AND gates", "optb": "OR gates", "optc": "NAND and NOR gates", "optd": "AND gates and OR gates", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The logic gate that will have HIGH or \"1\" at its output when any one (or more) of its inputs is HIGH is a(n):", "opta": "OR gate", "optb": "AND gate", "optc": "NOR gate", "optd": "NOT operation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "CMOS IC packages are available in ________.", "opta": "DIP configuration", "optb": "SOIC configuration", "optc": "DIP and SOIC configurations", "optd": "neither DIP nor SOIC configurations", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a basic Boolean operation?", "opta": "OR", "optb": "NOT", "optc": "AND", "optd": "FOR", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following gates is described by the expression ?", "opta": "OR", "optb": "AND", "optc": "NOR", "optd": "NAND", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the Boolean expression for a four-input OR gate?", "opta": "Y = A + B + C + D", "optb": "Y = A\u00b7 B \u00b7 C \u00b7 D", "optc": "Y = A \u2013 B \u2013 C \u2013 D", "optd": "Y = A $ B $ C $ D", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many truth table entries are necessary for a four-input circuit?", "opta": "4", "optb": "8", "optc": "12", "optd": "16", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many entries would a truth table for a four-input NAND gate have?", "opta": "2", "optb": "8", "optc": "16", "optd": "32", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Boolean expression for a 3-input OR gate is ________.", "opta": "X = A + B", "optb": "X = A + B + C", "optc": "X = ABC", "optd": "X = A + BC", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "From the truth table for a three-input NOR gate, what is the only condition of inputs A, B, and C that will make the output X high?", "opta": "A = 1, B = 1, C = 1", "optb": "A = 1, B = 0, C = 0", "optc": "A = 0, B = 0, C = 1", "optd": "A = 0, B = 0, C = 0", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The logic gate that will have a LOW output when any one of its inputs is HIGH is the:", "opta": "NAND gate", "optb": "AND gate", "optc": "NOR gate", "optd": "OR gate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of a NAND gate is LOW if ________.", "opta": "all inputs are LOW", "optb": "all inputs are HIGH", "optc": "any input is LOW", "optd": "any input is HIGH", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The devices that provide the means for a computer to communicate with the user or other computers are referred to as:", "opta": "CPU", "optb": "ALU", "optc": "I/O", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The software used to drive microprocessor-based systems is called:", "opta": "assembly language", "optb": "firmware", "optc": "machine language code", "optd": "BASIC interpreter instructions", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The circuits in the 8085A that provide the arithmetic and logic functions are called the:", "opta": "CPU", "optb": "ALU", "optc": "I/O", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many buses are connected as part of the 8085A microprocessor?", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "5", "optd": "8", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ________ ensures that only one IC is active at a time to avoid a bus conflict caused by two ICs writing different data to the same bus.", "opta": "control bus", "optb": "control instructions", "optc": "address decoder", "optd": "CPU", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many bits are used in the data bus?", "opta": "7", "optb": "8", "optc": "9", "optd": "16", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The items that you can physically touch in a computer system are called:", "opta": "software", "optb": "firmware", "optc": "hardware", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Single-bit indicators that may be set or cleared to show the results of logical or arithmetic operations are the:", "opta": "flags", "optb": "registers", "optc": "monitors", "optd": "decisions", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When referring to instruction words, a mnemonic is:", "opta": "a short abbreviation for the operand address", "optb": "a short abbreviation for the operation to be performed", "optc": "a short abbreviation for the data word stored at the operand address", "optd": "shorthand for machine language", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The technique of assigning a memory address to each I/O device in the computer system is called:", "opta": "memory-mapped I/O", "optb": "ported I/O", "optc": "dedicated I/O", "optd": "wired I/O", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When was the first 8-bit microprocessor introduced?", "opta": "1969", "optb": "1974", "optc": "1979", "optd": "1985", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of circuit is used at the interface point of an output port?", "opta": "decoder", "optb": "latch", "optc": "tristate buffer", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I/O mapped systems identify their input/output devices by giving them a(n) ________.", "opta": "8-bit port number", "optb": "16-bit port number", "optc": "8-bit buffer number", "optd": "8-bit instruction", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of circuit is used at the interface point of an input port?", "opta": "decoder", "optb": "latch", "optc": "tristate buffer", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The register in the 8085A that is used to keep track of the memory address of the next op-code to be run in the program is the:", "opta": "stack pointer", "optb": "program counter", "optc": "instruction pointer", "optd": "accumulator", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The control bus and memories share a bidirectional bus in a typical microprocessor system.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All computer programs for a machine are called:", "opta": "software", "optb": "firmware", "optc": "hardware", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 8085A is a(n):", "opta": "16-bit parallel CPU", "optb": "8-bit serial CPU", "optc": "8-bit parallel CPU", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Because microprocessor CPUs do not understand mnemonics as they are, they have to be converted to ________.", "opta": "hexadecimal machine code", "optb": "binary machine code", "optc": "assembly language", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A register in the microprocessor that keeps track of the answer or results of any arithmetic or logic operation is the:", "opta": "stack pointer", "optb": "program counter", "optc": "instruction pointer", "optd": "accumulator", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between a mnemonic code and machine code?", "opta": "There is no difference.", "optb": "Machine codes are in binary, mnemonic codes are in shorthand English.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which bus is a bidirectional bus?", "opta": "address bus", "optb": "data bus", "optc": "address bus and data bus", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following buses is primarily used to carry signals that direct other ICs to find out what type of operation is being performed?", "opta": "data bus", "optb": "control bus", "optc": "address bus", "optd": "address decoder bus", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What kind of computer program is used to convert mnemonic code to machine code?", "opta": "debug", "optb": "assembler", "optc": "C++", "optd": "Fortran", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following are the three basic sections of a microprocessor unit?", "opta": "operand, register, and arithmetic/logic unit (ALU)", "optb": "control and timing, register, and arithmetic/logic unit (ALU)", "optc": "control and timing, register, and memory", "optd": "arithmetic/logic unit (ALU), memory, and input/output", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which statement below best describes the function of a decoder?", "opta": "A decoder will convert a decimal number into the proper binary equivalent.", "optb": "A decoder will convert a binary number into a specific output representing a particular character or digit.", "optc": "Decoders are used to prevent improper operation of digital systems.", "optd": "Decoders are special ICs that are used to make it possible for one brand of computer to talk to another.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One can safely state that the output lines for a demultiplexer are under the direct control of the:", "opta": "input data select lines.", "optb": "the internal AND gates.", "optc": "the internal OR gate.", "optd": "Input data line.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Refer to the figure given below. The logic function generator being implemented with the multiplexer in this circuit produces a constant LOW on the output. The ABC inputs are checked and appear to be pulsing; also, the 0\u20137 and EN inputs are checked with the scope and all appear to be at 0 V. A check with the DMM confirms that power is on. What is the problem, and what should be done to correct it?", "opta": "The output is shorted to Vcc; replace the IC.", "optb": "The scope's vertical input is in the AC mode and the common connection for the 0,2,3 and 5 inputs is bad. Set the scope's vertical input mode to DC, and repair the bad solder connection.", "optc": "Power has not been applied to the circuit; apply power.", "optd": "The output is shorted to ground; replace the IC.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Refer to the keyboard encoder in figure (a). Sometimes when the 5 key is pressed, the system attached to the keypad does not respond. The 5 input on the 74147 is monitored with a digital storage scope while repeatedly pressing the 5 key, and the waveform in figure (b) is obtained; the P above the trace indicates the points at which the technician pressed the key. What is most likely wrong with the circuit?", "opta": "The switches on the 5 key are intermittent; the contacts need to be cleaned or the switch replaced.", "optb": "The pull-up resistor connected to the 5 key is bad and should be replaced.", "optc": "The common ground connection at the bottom of the 0 key has a bad solder connection; repair the connection.", "optd": "The 74147 is intermittent, possibly due to high temperature, and should be replaced.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The BCD/DEC decoder shown in figure (a) is examined with a logic analyzer and the results are shown in the waveforms in figure (b). What, if anything, is wrong with the circuit?", "opta": "The \"2\" output is shorted to Vcc.", "optb": "The A1 input is internally open.", "optc": "The A1 input node is internally stuck LOW.", "optd": "Nothing is wrong with the circuit.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 16-input multiplexer is to be used to perform parallel-to-serial data conversion. Which of the following counters would be required to provide the data select inputs?", "opta": "MOD 8", "optb": "MOD 16", "optc": "MOD 4", "optd": "MOD 2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A breadboard-circuit design using a BCD-to-decimal decoder has a problem wherein the operation of the system is erratic. The technician uses his scope to examine the waveforms throughout the system and doesn't really see any problems. While he's scratching his head, what helpful advice can you offer him as to what might be wrong and what to do to correct the problem?", "opta": "The decoder is thermally intermittent; replace it.", "optb": "There is probably a bad connection on the wire wrap protoboard; recheck the wiring.", "optc": "Glitches are probably the culprit; strobe the decoder.", "optd": "The decoder is thermally intermittent and must be replaced; or there is probably a bad connection on the wire wrap protoboard, and the wiring must be rechecked.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Output 5 of a 74138 octal decoder is selected when it is enabled by a data input of:", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is the number one (1) indicated on the outputs of a 7447 BCD-to-seven-segment code converter?", "opta": "Segment a is active.", "optb": "Segment b is active.", "optc": "Segments a and b are active.", "optd": "Segments b and c are active.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the input values (A0\u2013A3, B0\u2013B3, Data Select = 1) given for the circuit  given below, what will be indicated on the displays?", "opta": "A = 0, B = 5", "optb": "A = 5, B = 0", "optc": "A = 6, B = 0", "optd": "A = 0, B = 6", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It is suspected that the comparator in the figure given below has a problem. The inputs are activated in the table shown below and the corresponding outputs noted. What is most likely wrong with the circuit? For P0 \u2013 P3 = 1 and Q0 \u2013 Q3 = 0, P > Q = 1, P = Q = 1, P < Q = 0 For P0 \u2013 P3 = 0 and Q0 \u2013 Q3 = 1, P > Q = 0, P = Q = 1, P < Q = 1 For P0 \u2013 P3 = 1 and Q0 \u2013 Q3 = 1, P > Q = 0, P = Q = 1, P < Q = 0", "opta": "The P0\u2013P3 inputs are defective.", "optb": "One or more of the Q inputs is bad.", "optc": "The P = Q output is shorted to Vcc.", "optd": "Nothing is wrong; the circuit is functioning properly.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which statement best describes the given figure, and what is the function of the terminal labeled EN?", "opta": "Quad two-input multiplexer. EN is the enable input, which requires an active LOW for the device to work.", "optb": "Quad two-bit multiplier, EN is the active HIGH trigger.", "optc": "Dual quad-input multiplexer, which requires an active LOW on the EN terminal for the device to work.", "optd": "Quad two-input AND gate, which requires an active LOW on the EN input to enable all the gates.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The data transmission system shown in below has a problem; the parity error output is always high. A logic analyzer is used to examine the system and shows that the DATA IN on the left matches the DATA OUT on right. What might be causing the problem?", "opta": "The error gate could be defective.", "optb": "The storage circuit could be defective.", "optc": "The parity checker could be bad.", "optd": "Any of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The IEEE/ANSI symbol for a decoder has the internal designation bcd/dec. This means the decoder is a:", "opta": "decimal-to-BCD decoder with ten inputs and four outputs.", "optb": "BCD-to-decimal decoder with ten inputs and four outputs.", "optc": "decimal-to-BCD decoder with four inputs and ten outputs.", "optd": "BCD-to-decimal decoder with four inputs and ten outputs.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Multiplexing of digital signals is usually required when:", "opta": "moving data internally within a microprocessor.", "optb": "moving data between memory and storage registers in a microprocessor.", "optc": "moving data over long distance transmission lines.", "optd": "moving data internally within a microprocessor or between memory and storage registers.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Referring to the figure given below, what output code will appear on the output (A3,A2,A1,A0) when the 5 key is pressed?", "opta": "1010", "optb": "0101", "optc": "1101", "optd": "1011", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of device is shown in the given figure, and what inputs (A3,A2,A1,A0) are required to produce the output levels as shown?", "opta": "A binary-to-decimal encoder; 0,1,1,1", "optb": "A decimal-to-binary decoder; 1,1,1,0", "optc": "A BCD-to-decimal decoder; 0,1,1,1", "optd": "A decimal-to-BCD encoder; 1,1,1,0", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the outputs of a 7485 four-bit magnitude comparator when the inputs are A = 1001 and B = 1010?", "opta": "A < B is 1 A = B is 0 A > B is 1", "optb": "A < B is 0 A = B is 1 A > B is 0", "optc": "A < B is 0 A = B is 0 A > B is 1", "optd": "A < B is 1 A = B is 0 A > B is 0", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Determine the correct output for the multiplexer and its associated timing diagram given below.", "opta": "Ya", "optb": "Yb", "optc": "Yc", "optd": "Yd", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is the decimal number for the BCD number, 10110110?", "opta": "182", "optb": "36", "optc": "116", "optd": "10110110 is not a valid BCD number.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an AHDL BCD to binary code converter, how is multiplication by 10 accomplished?", "opta": "By using the shifting of bits", "optb": "By using the library multiplication function", "optc": "By using integer types", "optd": "By using the multiplication operator", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the HDL key issue in the design of the MUX and DEMUX?", "opta": "Having the MUX and DEMUX part of the library", "optb": "Using the case statement in the process", "optc": "Describing the functions", "optd": "Assigning signals under certain conditions", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why are control inputs included in an HDL magnitude comparator?", "opta": "For cascading the chips", "optb": "For control signal input", "optc": "For signal control", "optd": "For internal interconnections", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What VHDL techniques are used to describe a priority encoder?", "opta": "Integer outputs and priority coding", "optb": "Signal outputs and priority coding", "optc": "Tristate outputs and priority coding", "optd": "Variables and priority coding", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is an important attribute of the conditional signal assignment statement?", "opta": "Its tristate outputs", "optb": "Its sequential evaluation", "optc": "Its use of library components", "optd": "Its fast activation times", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "There appears to be a problem with a 7-segment display on a DMM sometimes skipping certain numbers. How would you test the display?", "opta": "Remove the display unit and check each segment diode with an ohmmeter. Replace the defective segments.", "optb": "Apply 5 V directly to each segment of the display and check for individual segment operation. Replace any segment that has voltage applied but is not lit.", "optc": "Tie all of the segments together and connect to Vcc; the number 8 should appear on the display. Now check the display supply voltage to determine if the display is receiving the correct voltage.", "optd": "Connect the DMM to a variable supply and very slowly increase the voltage, while observing for missing digits. Then check the segment voltage to determine whether the display or the display driver is bad.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the purpose of a decoder's inputs?", "opta": "To allow the decoder to respond to the inputs to activate the correct output gate.", "optb": "To disable the decoder outputs so that all outputs will be inactive.", "optc": "To disable the inputs and activate all outputs.", "optd": "To allow the decoder to respond to the inputs to activate the correct output gate, and to disable the inputs and activate all outputs.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Refer to the display multiplexer given below. The MSD display is blank, while the LSD seems to be OK. The input and output lines to the 74157 and 7449 are checked with a scope and can be seen changing levels. The A input on the 74139 also changes; however, the 0 output on the 74139 is always LOW and the 1 output is always HIGH. The B and EN inputs on the 74139 are always LOW. What could cause the problem and what should be done to correct it?", "opta": "The 74139 is defective; replace it.", "optb": "The EN pin on the 74139 could have a bad connection; check the connection.", "optc": "The 74139 is defective and must be replaced; or the EN pin on the 74139 could have a bad connection, which should be checked.", "optd": "The MSD display is bad; replace it.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The circuit in Figure 9-8 is defective; data is not appearing on the output lines. A check with the scope shows data pulses on the serial data line and multiplex control lines, S0\u2013S2; no parity error is indicated. A further check with a logic probe indicates that Vcc and ground appear to be present. What might be wrong with the circuit?", "opta": "The demultiplexer may be bad.", "optb": "The parity checker is defective.", "optc": "The parity generator may be bad.", "optd": "The parity checker is defective, or the parity generator may be bad.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What must be done in the given figure in order to use two 7485 4-bit comparators to compare two 8-bit numbers?", "opta": "The P < Q, P = Q, and P > Q outputs of COMP A must be connected to the same outputs of COMP B.", "optb": "The P < Q, P = Q, and P > Q outputs of COMP A must be connected to the <, =, and > inputs of COMP B.", "optc": "The = input of COMP A must be connected to Vcc, and the < and > inputs must be connected to ground.", "optd": "The P < Q, P = Q, and P > Q outputs of COMP A must be connected to the <, =, and > inputs of COMP B, the = input of COMP A must be connected to Vcc, and the <\u00a0and\u00a0> inputs must be connected to ground.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert hexadecimal value 16 to decimal.", "opta": "2210", "optb": "1610", "optc": "1010", "optd": "2010", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following decimal number to 8-bit binary.187", "opta": "101110112", "optb": "110111012", "optc": "101111012", "optd": "101111002", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert binary 111111110010 to hexadecimal.", "opta": "EE216", "optb": "FF216", "optc": "2FE16", "optd": "FD216", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following binary number to decimal. 010112", "opta": "11", "optb": "35", "optc": "15", "optd": "10", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the binary number 1001.00102 to decimal.", "opta": "90.125", "optb": "9.125", "optc": "125", "optd": "12.5", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Decode the following ASCII message. 1010011101010010101011000100101100101000001001000100000110100101000100", "opta": "STUDYHARD", "optb": "STUDY HARD", "optc": "stydyhard", "optd": "study hard", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The voltages in digital electronics are continuously variable.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One hex digit is sometimes referred to as a(n):", "opta": "byte", "optb": "nibble", "optc": "grouping", "optd": "instruction", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the most widely used alphanumeric code for computer input and output?", "opta": "Gray", "optb": "ASCII", "optc": "Parity", "optd": "EBCDIC", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a typical PC uses a 20-bit address code, how much memory can the CPU address?", "opta": "20 MB", "optb": "10 MB", "optc": "1 MB", "optd": "580 MB", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 59.7210 to BCD.", "opta": "111011", "optb": "01011001.01110010", "optc": "1110.11", "optd": "0101100101110010", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 8B3F16 to binary.", "opta": "35647", "optb": "011010", "optc": "1011001111100011", "optd": "1000101100111111", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is typically the longest: bit, byte, nibble, word?", "opta": "Bit", "optb": "Byte", "optc": "Nibble", "optd": "Word", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Assign the proper odd parity bit to the code 111001.", "opta": "1111011", "optb": "1111001", "optc": "0111111", "optd": "0011111", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert decimal 64 to binary.", "opta": "01010010", "optb": "01000000", "optc": "00110110", "optd": "01001000", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert hexadecimal value C1 to binary.", "opta": "11000001", "optb": "1000111", "optc": "111000100", "optd": "111000001", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following octal number to decimal. 178", "opta": "51", "optb": "82", "optc": "57", "optd": "15", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following binary number to octal. 0101111002", "opta": "1728", "optb": "2728", "optc": "1748", "optd": "2748", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many binary digits are required to count to 10010?", "opta": "7", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "100", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The BCD number for decimal 347 is ________.", "opta": "1100 1011 1000", "optb": "0011 0100 0111", "optc": "0011 0100 0001", "optd": "1100 1011 0110", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary number for octal 458 is ________.", "opta": "100010", "optb": "100101", "optc": "110101", "optd": "100100", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The sum of 11101 + 10111 equals ________.", "opta": "110011", "optb": "100001", "optc": "110100", "optd": "100100", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following binary number to decimal. 100110102", "opta": "154", "optb": "155", "optc": "153", "optd": "157", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The decimal number 188 is equal to the binary number ________.", "opta": "10111100", "optb": "0111000", "optc": "1100011", "optd": "1111000", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following binary number to octal. 0011010112", "opta": "1538", "optb": "3518", "optc": "2538", "optd": "3528", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many bits are in an ASCII character?", "opta": "16", "optb": "8", "optc": "7", "optd": "4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A binary number's value changes most drastically when the ________ is changed.", "opta": "MSB", "optb": "frequency", "optc": "LSB", "optd": "duty cycle", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert decimal 213 to binary.", "opta": "11001101", "optb": "11010101", "optc": "01111001", "optd": "11100011", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The decimal number for octal 748 is ________.", "opta": "74", "optb": "60", "optc": "22", "optd": "62", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The sum of the two BCD numbers, 0011 + 0011, is ________.", "opta": "0110", "optb": "0111", "optc": "0011", "optd": "1100", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert binary 01001110 to decimal.", "opta": "4E", "optb": "78", "optc": "76", "optd": "116", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a word size?", "opta": "64", "optb": "28", "optc": "16", "optd": "8", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The octal numbering system:", "opta": "simplifies tasks", "optb": "groups binary numbers in groups of 4", "optc": "saves time", "optd": "simplifies tasks and saves time", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary number 1110 is equal to the decimal number ________.", "opta": "3", "optb": "1", "optc": "7", "optd": "14", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following octal number to binary.768", "opta": "1101112", "optb": "1111102", "optc": "1111002", "optd": "1001112", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 11001010001101012 to hexadecimal.", "opta": "121035", "optb": "CA35", "optc": "53AC1", "optd": "530121", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following decimal number to octal.281", "opta": "1348", "optb": "4318", "optc": "3318", "optd": "1338", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When using even parity, where is the parity bit placed?", "opta": "Before the MSB", "optb": "After the LSB", "optc": "In the parity word", "optd": "After the odd parity bit", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following octal number to decimal. 358", "opta": "71", "optb": "17", "optc": "92", "optd": "29", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert binary 11001111 to hexadecimal.", "opta": "8F16", "optb": "CE16", "optc": "DF16", "optd": "CF16", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 17318 to decimal.", "opta": "216.4", "optb": "985", "optc": "3D9", "optd": "1123", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An analog signal has a range from 0 V to 5 V. What is the total number of analog possibilities within this range?", "opta": "5", "optb": "50", "optc": "250", "optd": "infinite", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hexadecimal letters A through F are used for decimal equivalent values from:", "opta": "1 through 6", "optb": "9 through 14", "optc": "10 through 15", "optd": "11 through 17", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following decimal number to 8-bit binary.35", "opta": "000100102", "optb": "000100112", "optc": "001000112", "optd": "001000102", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following hexadecimal number to binary.C916", "opta": "101110012", "optb": "101110112", "optc": "100111002", "optd": "110010012", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following decimal number to hexadecimal.125", "opta": "7D16", "optb": "D716", "optc": "7C16", "optd": "C716", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A decimal 11 in BCD is ________.", "opta": "00001011", "optb": "00001100", "optc": "00010001", "optd": "00010010", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the resultant binary of the decimal problem 49 + 01 = ?", "opta": "01010101", "optb": "00110101", "optc": "00110010", "optd": "00110001", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The difference of 111 \u2013 001 equals ________.", "opta": "100", "optb": "111", "optc": "001", "optd": "110", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the binary number 1100 to Gray code.", "opta": "0011", "optb": "1010", "optc": "1100", "optd": "1001", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary number 11101011000111010 can be written in hexadecimal as ________.", "opta": "DD63A16", "optb": "1D63A16", "optc": "1D33A16", "optd": "1D63116", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an invalid BCD code?", "opta": "0011", "optb": "1101", "optc": "0101", "optd": "1001", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What decimal number does 25 represent?", "opta": "10", "optb": "31", "optc": "25", "optd": "32", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the Gray code 1011 to binary.", "opta": "1011", "optb": "1010", "optc": "0100", "optd": "1101", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Determine the decimal equivalent of the signed binary number 11110100 in 1's complement.", "opta": "116", "optb": "\u201312", "optc": "11", "optd": "128", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between binary coding and binary-coded decimal?", "opta": "BCD is pure binary.", "optb": "Binary coding has a decimal format.", "optc": "BCD has no decimal format.", "optd": "Binary coding is pure binary.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following decimal number to BCD.127", "opta": "011100100001", "optb": "111010001", "optc": "001010111", "optd": "000100100111", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Digital electronics is based on the ________ numbering system.", "opta": "decimal", "optb": "octal", "optc": "binary", "optd": "hexadecimal", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An informational signal that makes use of binary digits is considered to be:", "opta": "solid state", "optb": "digital", "optc": "analog", "optd": "non-oscillating", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 1's complement of 10011101 is ________.", "opta": "01100010", "optb": "10011110", "optc": "01100001", "optd": "01100011", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary number 101110101111010 can be written in octal as ________.", "opta": "515628", "optb": "565778", "optc": "656278", "optd": "565728", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 45710 to hexadecimal.", "opta": "711", "optb": "2C7", "optc": "811", "optd": "1C9", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the decimal number 151.75 to binary.", "opta": "10000111.11", "optb": "11010011.01", "optc": "00111100.00", "optd": "10010111.11", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following octal number to binary.1048", "opta": "0010001002", "optb": "1000000012", "optc": "00101002", "optd": "10000012", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "3 \u00d7 101 + 7 \u00d7 100 is equal to ________.", "opta": "3.7", "optb": "37", "optc": "10", "optd": "370", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "3428 is the decimal value for which of the following binary-coded decimal (BCD) groupings?", "opta": "11010001001000", "optb": "11010000101000", "optc": "011010010000010", "optd": "110100001101010", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary-coded decimal (BCD) system can be used to represent each of the 10 decimal digits as a(n):", "opta": "4-bit binary code", "optb": "8-bit binary code", "optc": "16-bit binary code", "optd": "ASCII code", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The decimal number 18 is equal to the binary number ________.", "opta": "11110", "optb": "10001", "optc": "10010", "optd": "1111000", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 2's complement of 11100111 is ________.", "opta": "11100110", "optb": "00011001", "optc": "00011000", "optd": "00011010", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following decimal number to BCD.469", "opta": "100101101000", "optb": "010001101001", "optc": "100001101001", "optd": "100101100100", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Express the decimal number \u201337 as an 8-bit number in sign-magnitude.", "opta": "10100101", "optb": "00100101", "optc": "11011000", "optd": "11010001", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following BCD number to decimal.010101101001bcd", "opta": "539", "optb": "2551", "optc": "569", "optd": "1552", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary number 11001110 is equal to the decimal number ________.", "opta": "12", "optb": "206", "optc": "127", "optd": "66", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary number for F3A16 is ________.", "opta": "111100111010", "optb": "111100111110", "optc": "000000111010", "optd": "000011000100", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following BCD number to decimal.100000000011bcd", "opta": "8003", "optb": "803", "optc": "1003", "optd": "103", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following hexadecimal number to binary. 14B16", "opta": "1011010000012", "optb": "0001010010112", "optc": "0001010011012", "optd": "1101010000012", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the result when a decimal 5238 is converted to base 16?", "opta": "327.375", "optb": "12.166", "optc": "1388", "optd": "1476", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The octal number for binary 1101110101110110 is ________.", "opta": "6545218", "optb": "5565618", "optc": "1566568", "optd": "1565668", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following hexadecimal number to decimal.1CF16", "opta": "463", "optb": "4033", "optc": "479", "optd": "4049", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the binary number 1011010 to hexadecimal.", "opta": "5B", "optb": "5F", "optc": "5A", "optd": "5C", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following decimal number to hexadecimal.74", "opta": "A416", "optb": "B416", "optc": "4A16", "optd": "4B16", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert hexadecimal C0B to binary.", "opta": "110000001011", "optb": "110000001001", "optc": "110000001100", "optd": "110100001011", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert binary 1001 to hexadecimal.", "opta": "916", "optb": "1116", "optc": "10116", "optd": "1016", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 73116 to decimal.", "opta": "216.4", "optb": "985", "optc": "3D9", "optd": "1841", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the decimal value of the hexadecimal number 777?", "opta": "191", "optb": "1911", "optc": "19", "optd": "19111", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 110010012 (binary) to decimal.", "opta": "201", "optb": "2001", "optc": "20", "optd": "210", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following decimal number to octal.39", "opta": "638", "optb": "368", "optc": "478", "optd": "748", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The American Standard Code for Information Interchange (ASCII) uses how many individual pulses for any given character?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "7", "optd": "8", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following hexadecimal number to decimal.B516", "opta": "212", "optb": "197", "optc": "165", "optd": "181", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The BCD number for decimal 16 is ________.", "opta": "00010110", "optb": "00010000", "optc": "00010010", "optd": "11100000", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Alphanumeric codes should include as a minimum:", "opta": "the capacity to represent the alphabet upper- and lowercase characters and the decimal numbers in a straight binary format.", "optb": "the capacity to code all possible decimal numbers in a direct octal representation of BCD codes.", "optc": "the alphabet upper- and lowercase letters, the decimal digits, the seven punctuation marks, and other characters or symbols.", "optd": "the ability to represent decimal numbers greater than 12810 in a straight binary format.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 52716 to binary.", "opta": "343", "optb": "001101000111", "optc": "010100100111", "optd": "011100100101", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 5278 to binary.", "opta": "011100111", "optb": "101010111", "optc": "343", "optd": "111010101", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The base of the hexadecimal system is:", "opta": "eight.", "optb": "sixteen.", "optc": "ten.", "optd": "two.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Assign the proper even parity bit to the code 1100001.", "opta": "11100001", "optb": "1100001", "optc": "01100001", "optd": "01110101", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Select one of the following statements that best describes the parity method of error detection.", "opta": "Parity checking is best suited for detecting single-bit errors in transmitted codes.", "optb": "Parity checking is not suitable for detecting single-bit errors in transmitted codes.", "optc": "Parity checking is capable of detecting and correcting errors in transmitted codes.", "optd": "Parity checking is best suited for detecting double-bit errors that occur during the transmission of codes from one location to another.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the primary advantage of using the BCD code instead of straight binary coding?", "opta": "Fewer bits are required to represent a decimal number with the BCD code.", "optb": "The relative ease of converting to and from decimal.", "optc": "BCD codes are easily converted to hexadecimal codes.", "optd": "BCD codes are easily converted to straight binary codes.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many BCD code bits and how many straight binary bits would be required to represent the decimal number 643?", "opta": "12 BCD, 12 binary", "optb": "12 BCD, 10 binary", "optc": "12 BCD, 9 binary", "optd": "16 BCD, 9 binary", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When using the repeated division by 2 method of converting from decimal to binary, one must write the first remainder as the:", "opta": "MSB", "optb": "MSB, provided the following sequence of remainders are written in descending order until the final remainder is achieved.", "optc": "LSB", "optd": "LSB, provided the final remainder is used to replace the original LSB, which is then moved to the MSB position.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The difference between a PLA and a PAL is:", "opta": "The PLA has a programmable OR plane and a programmable AND plane, while the PAL only has a programmable AND plane.", "optb": "The PAL has a programmable OR plane and a programmable AND plane, while the PLA only has a programmable AND plane.", "optc": "The PAL has more possible product terms than the PLA.", "optd": "PALs and PLAs are the same thing.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "ALM is the acronym for ________.", "opta": "Array Logic Matrix", "optb": "Arithmetic Logic Module", "optc": "Asynchronous Local Modulator", "optd": "Adaptive Logic Module", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The GAL16V8 has:", "opta": "16 dedicated inputs.", "optb": "8 special function pins.", "optc": "8 pins that are used as inputs or outputs.", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "PALs tend to execute ________ logic.", "opta": "SAP", "optb": "SOP", "optc": "PLA", "optd": "SPD", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many pins are in an EDF10K70 package?", "opta": "70", "optb": "140", "optc": "240", "optd": "532", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A GAL is essentially a ________.", "opta": "non-reprogrammable PAL", "optb": "PAL that is programmed only by the manufacturer", "optc": "very large PAL", "optd": "reprogrammable PAL", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is an OTP device?", "opta": "Optical transporting port", "optb": "Octal transmitting pixel", "optc": "Operational topical portable", "optd": "One-time programmable", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many product terms can a MAX+Plus II compiler borrow from adjacent macrocells in the same LAB?", "opta": "0", "optb": "5", "optc": "10", "optd": "20", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Each programmable array logic (PAL) gate product is applied to an OR gate and, if combinational logic is desired, the product is ORed and then:", "opta": "the polarity fuse is restored", "optb": "sent to an inverter for output", "optc": "sent immediately to an output pin", "optd": "passed to the AND function for output", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "________ are used at the inputs of PAL/GAL devices in order to prevent input loading from a large number of AND gates.", "opta": "Simplified AND gates", "optb": "Fuses", "optc": "Buffers", "optd": "Latches", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A(n) ________ consists of a programmable array of AND gates that connects to a fixed array of OR gates and is usually OTP.", "opta": "GAL", "optb": "CPLD", "optc": "PAL", "optd": "SPLD", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is another name for digital circuitry called sequential logic?", "opta": "logic macrocell", "optb": "logic array", "optc": "flip-flop memory circuitry", "optd": "inverter", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When did the first PLD appear?", "opta": "More than 10 years ago", "optb": "More than 20 years ago", "optc": "More than 30 years ago", "optd": "More than 40 years ago", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "SPLDs, CPLDs, and FPGAs are all which type of device?", "opta": "PAL", "optb": "PLD", "optc": "EPROM", "optd": "SRAM", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cascade chains are closely associated with ________.", "opta": "CLBs", "optb": "SOP functions", "optc": "logic expansion", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "FPLA is:", "opta": "a nonmemory programmable device.", "optb": "a programmable AND array.", "optc": "a programmable OR array.", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A(n) ________ is a section of embedded logic that is commonly found in FPGAs.", "opta": "LUT", "optb": "core", "optc": "DSP", "optd": "PI", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a FLEX10K, what two outputs will the LE produce?", "opta": "The LAB and the fast track", "optb": "ON and OFF", "optc": "Hi-Z and ON", "optd": "Hi-Z and OFF", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the major downfall of microprocessor/DSP systems?", "opta": "Speed\u2014they are too fast", "optb": "Speed\u2014they are too slow", "optc": "Too much flexibility", "optd": "Not enough flexibility", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "ASIC stands for:", "opta": "advanced speed integrated circuit.", "optb": "advanced standard integrated circuit.", "optc": "application specific integrated circuit.", "optd": "application speedy integrated circuit.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A look-up table is simply a truth table with all the possible output connections listed with their desired input response.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The final step in the device programming sequence is ________.", "opta": "compiling", "optb": "downloading", "optc": "simulation", "optd": "synthesis", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most look-up tables in field-programmable gate arrays (FGPAs) use ________ inputs, resulting in ________ possible outputs.", "opta": "4,16", "optb": "8,16", "optc": "4,12", "optd": "6,12", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the defining difference between microprocessor/DSP systems and other digital systems?", "opta": "The digital system follows a programmed sequence of instructions that the designer specified.", "optb": "The microprocessor follows a programmed sequence of instructions that the designer specified.", "optc": "The digital system is faster.", "optd": "The microprocessor/DSP is faster.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why have PLDs taken over so much of the market?", "opta": "One PLD does the work of many ICs.", "optb": "The PLDs are cheaper.", "optc": "Less power is required.", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "CLB is the acronym for ________.", "opta": "Configurable Logic Block", "optb": "Configurable Logic Buffer", "optc": "Critical Logic Buffer", "optd": "Constant Logic Buffer", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What can the GAL22V10 do that the GAL16V8 cannot?", "opta": "It has an extra-large array.", "optb": "It is in-system programmable.", "optc": "It has twice the special function pins.", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of this circuit is always ________.", "opta": "1", "optb": "0", "optc": "A", "optd": "A", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A circuit that implements a combinational logic function by storing a list of output values that correspond to all possible input combinations is a(n) ________.", "opta": "output logic macrocell", "optb": "look-up table", "optc": "parallel logic expander", "optd": "logic element", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "By adding an OR gate to a simple programmable logic device (SPLD) the foundation for a(n) ________ is made possible.", "opta": "PAL", "optb": "PLA", "optc": "CPLD", "optd": "EEPROM", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does the Altera FLEX10K PLD use in place of AND and OR arrays?", "opta": "Nothing, it uses AND and OR arrays.", "optb": "Look-up tables", "optc": "SRAM-based memory", "optd": "HPLD architecture", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "PIA is an acronym for ________.", "opta": "Programmable Interface Array", "optb": "Post Integrated Array", "optc": "Programmable Input Array", "optd": "Programmable Interconnect Array", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following is an embedded function of the Stratix II FPGA?", "opta": "AND-OR logic", "optb": "Programmable SOP", "optc": "Digital signal processing", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an OLMC, where does the FMUX signal go?", "opta": "OMUX", "optb": "D flip-flop", "optc": "Matrix", "optd": "PAL", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following testing procedures has one or more external moving parts?", "opta": "Bed-of-nails", "optb": "Flying probe", "optc": "EXTEST", "optd": "Boundary scan", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Field-programmable gate arrays (FGPAs) use ________ memory technology, which is ________.", "opta": "DRAM, nonvolatile", "optb": "SRAM, nonvolatile", "optc": "SRAM, volatile", "optd": "RAM, volatile", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A PAL16L8 has:", "opta": "10 inputs and 8 outputs.", "optb": "8 inputs and 8 outputs.", "optc": "16 inputs and 16 outputs.", "optd": "16 inputs and 8 outputs.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Now many times can a GAL be erased and reprogrammed?", "opta": "0", "optb": "At least 100", "optc": "At least 1000", "optd": "Over 10,000", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "MPGA stands for:", "opta": "mass produced gated array.", "optb": "Morgan-Phillips gated array.", "optc": "memory programmed ROM.", "optd": "mask programmed ROM.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following increases the number of product terms by borrowing unused product from other macrocells?", "opta": "Shared expander", "optb": "Parallel expander", "optc": "Series expander", "optd": "Slice expander", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is a mode of operation of the GAL16V8?", "opta": "Simple mode", "optb": "Complex mode", "optc": "Registered mode", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following testing procedures uses the JTAG IEEE standard?", "opta": "Bed-of-nails", "optb": "Flying probe", "optc": "EXTEST", "optd": "Boundary scan", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The macrocells in a PAL/GAL are located ________.", "opta": "after the programmable AND arrays", "optb": "ahead of the programmable AND arrays", "optc": "at the input terminals", "optd": "at the output terminals", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The content of a simple programmable logic device (PLD) consists of:", "opta": "fuse-link arrays", "optb": "thousands of basic logic gates", "optc": "advanced sequential logic functions", "optd": "thousands of basic logic gates and advanced sequential logic functions", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is a major digital system category?", "opta": "Standard logic devices", "optb": "ASICs", "optc": "Microprocessor/DSP devices", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the input/output pin configuration of the GAL22V10?", "opta": "10 output pins and 12 input pins", "optb": "2 special-purpose pins", "optc": "8 pins that are either inputs or outputs", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of this circuit is always ________.", "opta": "1", "optb": "0", "optc": "A", "optd": "A", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does a dot mean when placed on a PLD circuit diagram?", "opta": "A point that is programmable", "optb": "A point that cannot change", "optc": "An intersection of logic blocks", "optd": "An input or output point", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "FPGA is the acronym for ________.", "opta": "Flexible Programming [of] Generic Assemblies", "optb": "Field Programmable Generic Array", "optc": "Field Programmable Gate Array", "optd": "Field Programmer's Gate Assembly", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many combinations are handled in an LUT?", "opta": "4", "optb": "8", "optc": "16", "optd": "32", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true?", "opta": "Altera uses PAL architecture and Xilinx uses PLA architecture.", "optb": "Altera uses PLA architecture and Xilinx uses PAL architecture.", "optc": "Altera and Xilinx both use PAL architecture.", "optd": "Altera and Xilinx both use PLA architecture.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the status of a tristate output buffer on a MAX7000S family device?", "opta": "It is permanently enabled or disabled.", "optb": "It is controlled by one of the two global output enable pins.", "optc": "It is controlled by other inputs or functions generated by other macrocells.", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "GAL is an acronym for ________.", "opta": "Generic Array Logic", "optb": "General Array Logic", "optc": "Giant Array Logic", "optd": "Generic Analysis Logic", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What gives a GAL its flexibility?", "opta": "Its speed", "optb": "Its reprogrammable EPROM", "optc": "Its large logic arrays", "optd": "Its programmable OLMCs", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What programmable technology is used in FPGA devices?", "opta": "SRAM", "optb": "FLASH", "optc": "Antifuse", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is an EPM7128S?", "opta": "An Altera MAX7000S CPLD", "optb": "An Altera UP2", "optc": "A DeVry eSOC", "optd": "A BSR PL DT-2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An SPLD listed as 22V10 has ________.", "opta": "10 inputs, 10 outputs, and requires a 22 V power source", "optb": "11 inputs, 11 outputs, and requires a 10 V power source", "optc": "22 inputs and 10 outputs", "optd": "10 inputs and 22 outputs", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Altera MAX 7000 series ________.", "opta": "uses an E2PROM process technology", "optb": "can have between 2 and 16 LABS and I/O control blocks", "optc": "is available with DC supply voltages between 2.5 V and 5 V", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A macrocell basically contains ________.", "opta": "a programmable AND-OR gate array and some input buffers", "optb": "an OR-gate array and some output logic", "optc": "an AND-OR gate array and some output logic", "optd": "licensed programming", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The complex programmable logic device (CPLD) features a(n) ________ type of memory.", "opta": "volatile", "optb": "nonvolatile", "optc": "EPROM", "optd": "volitile EPROM", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many macrocells are in a MAX700S LAB?", "opta": "8", "optb": "16", "optc": "32", "optd": "64", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a type of PLD?", "opta": "SPLD", "optb": "HPLD", "optc": "CPLD", "optd": "FPGA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An SPLD listed as 16H8 would have ________.", "opta": "active-HIGH outputs", "optb": "active-LOW outputs", "optc": "variable-level outputs", "optd": "latches at the outputs", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of PLD could be used to program basic logic functions?", "opta": "PLA", "optb": "PAL", "optc": "CPLD", "optd": "all the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The complex programmable logic device (CPLD) contains several PAL-type simple programmable logic devices (SPLDs) called:", "opta": "macrocells", "optb": "microcells", "optc": "AND/OR arrays", "optd": "fuse-link arrays", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a part of a GAL16V8's OLMC?", "opta": "TSMUX", "optb": "OMUX", "optc": "FMUX", "optd": "PSMUX", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is PROM?", "opta": "SPLD", "optb": "QPLD", "optc": "HPLD", "optd": "PLD", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A slice consists of ________.", "opta": "only two logic cells", "optb": "between 2 and 8 logic cells", "optc": "up to 16 logic cells", "optd": "a single CLB", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Product terms are the outputs of which type of gate within a PLD array?", "opta": "OR", "optb": "XOR", "optc": "AND", "optd": "flip-flop", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "On the fifth clock pulse, a 4-bit Johnson sequence is Q0 = 0, Q1 = 1, Q2 = 1, and Q3 = 1. On the sixth clock pulse, the sequence is ________.", "opta": "Q0 = 1, Q1 = 0, Q2 = 0, Q3 = 0", "optb": "Q0 = 1, Q1 = 1, Q2 = 1, Q3 = 0", "optc": "Q0 = 0, Q1 = 0, Q2 = 1, Q3 = 1", "optd": "Q0 = 0, Q1 = 0, Q2 = 0, Q3 = 1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bit sequence 0010 is serially entered (right-most bit first) into a 4-bit parallel out shift register that is initially clear. What are the Q outputs after two clock pulses?", "opta": "0000", "optb": "0010", "optc": "1000", "optd": "1111", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is a shift register that will accept a parallel input, or a bidirectional serial load and internal shift features, called?", "opta": "tristate", "optb": "end around", "optc": "universal", "optd": "conversion", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "On the third clock pulse, a 4-bit Johnson sequence is Q0 = 1, Q1 = 1, Q2 = 1, and Q3 = 0. On the fourth clock pulse, the sequence is ________.", "opta": "Q0 = 1, Q1 = 1, Q2 = 1, Q3 = 1", "optb": "Q0 = 1, Q1 = 1, Q2 = 0, Q3 = 0", "optc": "Q0 = 1, Q1 = 0, Q2 = 0, Q3 = 0", "optd": "Q0 = 0, Q1 = 0, Q2 = 0, Q3 = 0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A bidirectional 4-bit shift register is storing the nibble 1101. Its  input is HIGH. The nibble 1011 is waiting to be entered on the serial data-input line. After three clock pulses, the shift register is storing ________.", "opta": "1101", "optb": "0111", "optc": "0001", "optd": "1110", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How can parallel data be taken out of a shift register simultaneously?", "opta": "Use the Q output of the first FF.", "optb": "Use the Q output of the last FF.", "optc": "Tie all of the Q outputs together.", "optd": "Use the Q output of each FF.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is meant by parallel load of a shift register?", "opta": "All FFs are preset with data.", "optb": "Each FF is loaded with data, one at a time.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does the output enable do on the 74395A chip?", "opta": "It determines when data can be loaded.", "optb": "It forces all outputs to go HIGH.", "optc": "It forces all outputs to go LOW.", "optd": "It activates the three-state buffer.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To operate correctly, starting a ring shift counter requires:", "opta": "clearing all the flip-flops", "optb": "presetting one flip-flop and clearing all others", "optc": "clearing one flip-flop and presetting all others", "optd": "presetting all the flip-flops", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a 6-bit Johnson counter sequence there are a total of how many states, or bit patterns?", "opta": "2", "optb": "6", "optc": "12", "optd": "24", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A modulus-12 ring counter requires a minimum of ________.", "opta": "10 flip-flops", "optb": "12 flip-flops", "optc": "6 flip-flops", "optd": "2 flip-flops", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Stepper motors have become popular in digital automation systems because ________.", "opta": "of their low cost", "optb": "they are driven by sequential digital signals", "optc": "they can be used to provide repetitive mechanical movement", "optd": "they are driven by sequential digital signals and can be used to provide repetitive mechanical movement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The group of bits 11001 is serially shifted (right-most bit first) into a 5-bit parallel output shift register with an initial state 01110. After three clock pulses, the register contains ________.", "opta": "01110", "optb": "00001", "optc": "00101", "optd": "00110", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Assume that a 4-bit serial in/serial out shift register is initially clear. We wish to store the nibble 1100. What will be the 4-bit pattern after the second clock pulse? (Right-most bit first.)", "opta": "1100", "optb": "0011", "optc": "0000", "optd": "1111", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A serial in/parallel out, 4-bit shift register initially contains all 1s. The data nibble 0111 is waiting to enter. After four clock pulses, the register contains ________.", "opta": "0000", "optb": "1111", "optc": "0111", "optd": "1000", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a 200 kHz clock frequency, eight bits can be serially entered into a shift register in ________.", "opta": "4 \u03bcs", "optb": "40 \u03bcs", "optc": "400 \u03bcs", "optd": "40 ms", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An 8-bit serial in/serial out shift register is used with a clock frequency of 2 MHz to achieve a time delay (td) of ________.", "opta": "16 s", "optb": "8 s", "optc": "4 s", "optd": "2 s", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A sequence of equally spaced timing pulses may be easily generated by which type of counter circuit?", "opta": "ring shift", "optb": "clock", "optc": "Johnson", "optd": "binary", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bit sequence 10011100 is serially entered (right-most bit first) into an 8-bit parallel out shift register that is initially clear. What are the Q outputs after four clock pulses?", "opta": "10011100", "optb": "11000000", "optc": "00001100", "optd": "11110000", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If an 8-bit ring counter has an initial state 10111110, what is the state after the fourth clock pulse?", "opta": "11101011", "optb": "00010111", "optc": "11110000", "optd": "00000000", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How would a latch circuit be used in a microprocessor system?", "opta": "as transportation for Intel employees", "optb": "for a group of data that is the same", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 4-bit shift register that receives 4 bits of parallel data will shift to the ________ by ________ position(s) for each clock pulse.", "opta": "right, one", "optb": "right, two", "optc": "left, one", "optd": "left, three", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many clock pulses will be required to completely load serially a 5-bit shift register?", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is a strobe signal used when serially loading a shift register?", "opta": "to turn the register on and off", "optb": "to control the number of clocks", "optc": "to determine which output Qs are used", "optd": "to determine the FFs that will be used", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An 8-bit serial in/serial out shift register is used with a clock frequency of 150 kHz. What is the time delay between the serial input and the Q3 output?", "opta": "1.67 s", "optb": "26.67 s", "optc": "26.7 ms", "optd": "267 ms", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the three output conditions of a three-state buffer?", "opta": "HIGH, LOW, float", "optb": "1, 0, float", "optc": "both of the above", "optd": "neither of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The primary purpose of a three-state buffer is usually:", "opta": "to provide isolation between the input device and the data bus", "optb": "to provide the sink or source current required by any device connected to its output without loading down the output device", "optc": "temporary data storage", "optd": "to control data flow", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between a ring shift counter and a Johnson shift counter?", "opta": "There is no difference.", "optb": "A ring is faster.", "optc": "The feedback is reversed.", "optd": "The Johnson is faster.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is a recirculating register?", "opta": "serial out connected to serial in", "optb": "all Q outputs connected together", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When is it important to use a three-state buffer?", "opta": "when two or more outputs are connected to the same input", "optb": "when all outputs are normally HIGH", "optc": "when all outputs are normally LOW", "optd": "when two or more outputs are connected to two or more inputs", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A bidirectional 4-bit shift register is storing the nibble 1110. Its  input is LOW. The nibble 0111 is waiting to be entered on the serial data-input line. After two clock pulses, the shift register is storing ________.", "opta": "1110", "optb": "0111", "optc": "1000", "optd": "1001", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a parallel in/parallel out shift register, D0 = 1, D1 = 1, D2 = 1, and D3 = 0. After three clock pulses, the data outputs are ________.", "opta": "1110", "optb": "0001", "optc": "1100", "optd": "1000", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The group of bits 10110111 is serially shifted (right-most bit first) into an 8-bit parallel output shift register with an initial state 11110000. After two clock pulses, the register contains ________.", "opta": "10111000", "optb": "10110111", "optc": "11110000", "optd": "11111100", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "By adding recirculating lines to a 4-bit parallel-in, serial-out shift register, it becomes a ________, ________, and ________-out register.", "opta": "parallel-in, serial, parallel", "optb": "serial-in, parallel, serial", "optc": "series-parallel-in, series, parallel", "optd": "bidirectional in, parallel, series", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of register would have a complete binary number shifted in one bit at a time and have all the stored bits shifted out one at a time?", "opta": "parallel-in, parallel-out", "optb": "parallel-in, serial-out", "optc": "serial-in, parallel-out", "optd": "serial-in, serial-out", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When an 8-bit serial in/serial out shift register is used for a 20 s time delay, the clock frequency is ________.", "opta": "40 kHz", "optb": "50 kHz", "optc": "400 kHz", "optd": "500 kHz", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ring shift and Johnson counters are:", "opta": "synchronous counters", "optb": "aynchronous counters", "optc": "true binary counters", "optd": "synchronous and true binary counters", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between a shift-right register and a shift-left register?", "opta": "There is no difference.", "optb": "the direction of the shift", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is a transceiver circuit?", "opta": "a buffer that transfers data from input to output", "optb": "a buffer that transfers data from output to input", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 74HC195 4-bit parallel access shift register can be used for ________.", "opta": "serial in/serial out operation", "optb": "serial in/parallel out operation", "optc": "parallel in/serial out operation", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of device may be used to interface a parallel data format with external equipment's serial format?", "opta": "key matrix", "optb": "UART", "optc": "memory chip", "optd": "series in, parallel out", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the function of a buffer circuit?", "opta": "to provide an output that is inverted from that on the input", "optb": "to provide an output that is equal to its input", "optc": "to clean up the input", "optd": "to clean up the output", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the preset condition for a ring shift counter?", "opta": "all FFs set to 1", "optb": "all FFs cleared to 0", "optc": "a single 0, the rest 1", "optd": "a single 1, the rest 0", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not characteristic of a shift register?", "opta": "Serial in/parallel in", "optb": "Serial in/parallel out", "optc": "Parallel in/serial out", "optd": "Parallel in/parallel out", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To keep output data accurate, 4-bit series-in, parallel-out shift registers employ a ________.", "opta": "divide-by-4 clock pulse", "optb": "sequence generator", "optc": "strobe line", "optd": "multiplexer", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a 50 kHz clock frequency, six bits can be serially entered into a shift register in ________.", "opta": "12 s", "optb": "120 s", "optc": "12 ms", "optd": "120 ms", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Another way to connect devices to a shared data bus is to use a ________.", "opta": "circulating gate", "optb": "transceiver", "optc": "bidirectional encoder", "optd": "strobed latch", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To serially shift a nibble (four bits) of data into a shift register, there must be ________.", "opta": "one clock pulse", "optb": "four clock pulses", "optc": "eight clock pulses", "optd": "one clock pulse for each 1 in the data", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Computers operate on data internally in a ________ format.", "opta": "tristate", "optb": "universal", "optc": "parallel", "optd": "serial", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a 4-bit Johnson counter sequence there are a total of how many states, or bit patterns?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "8", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a 10-bit ring counter has an initial state 1101000000, what is the state after the second clock pulse?", "opta": "1101000000", "optb": "0011010000", "optc": "1100000000", "optd": "0000000000", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How much storage capacity does each stage in a shift register represent?", "opta": "One bit", "optb": "Two bits", "optc": "Four bits (one nibble)", "optd": "Eight bits (one byte)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When the output of a tristate shift register is disabled, the output level is placed in a:", "opta": "float state", "optb": "LOW state", "optc": "high-impedance state", "optd": "float or high-impedance state", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The internal RAM memory of the 8051 is:", "opta": "32 bytes", "optb": "64 bytes", "optc": "128 bytes", "optd": "256 bytes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This program code will be executed continuously:  STAT: MOV A, #01H \u00a0JNZ STAT", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 8051 has ________ 16-bit counter/timers.", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The address space of the 8051 is divided into four distinct areas: internal data, external data, internal code, and external code.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Data transfer from I/O to external data memory can only be done with the MOVX command.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 8051 can handle ________ interrupt sources.", "opta": "3", "optb": "4", "optc": "5", "optd": "6", "ans": "C", "explanation": "There are five interrupt sources for the 8051, which means that they can recognize 5 different events that can interrupt regular program execution. Each interrupt can be enabled or disabled by setting bits of the IE register. Likewise, the whole interrupt system can be disabled by clearing the EA bit of the same register."}, {"question": "The special function registers are maintained in the next 128 locations after the general-purpose data storage and stack.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This statement will set the address of the bit to 1 (8051 Micro-controller):  SETB 01H", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "MOV A, @ R1 will:", "opta": "copy R1 to the accumulator", "optb": "copy the accumulator to R1", "optc": "copy the contents of memory whose address is in R1 to the accumulator", "optd": "copy the accumulator to the contents of memory whose address is in R1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A label is used to name a single line of code.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following program will receive data from port 1, determine whether bit 2 is high, and then send the number FFH to port 3:  READ: MOV A,P1 ANL A,#2H CJNE A,#02H,READ MOV P3,#FFH", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Device pins XTAL1 and XTAL2 for the 8051 are used for connections to an external oscillator or crystal.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When the 8051 is reset and the  line is HIGH, the program counter points to the first program instruction in the:", "opta": "internal code memory", "optb": "external code memory", "optc": "internal data memory", "optd": "external data memory", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An alternate function of port pin P3.4 in the 8051 is:", "opta": "Timer 0", "optb": "Timer 1", "optc": "interrupt 0", "optd": "interrupt 1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Both registers TL0 and TL1 are needed to start Timer 0.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The I/O ports that are used as address and data for external memory are:", "opta": "ports 1 and 2", "optb": "ports 1 and 3", "optc": "ports 0 and 2", "optd": "ports 0 and 3", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The last 96 locations in the internal data memory are reserved for general-purpose data storage and stack.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Microcontrollers often have:", "opta": "CPUs", "optb": "RAM", "optc": "ROM", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 8051 has ________ parallel I/O ports.", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The total external data memory that can be interfaced to the 8051 is:", "opta": "32K", "optb": "64K", "optc": "128K", "optd": "256K", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following instructions will load the value 35H into the high byte of timer 0?", "opta": "MOV TH0, #35H", "optb": "MOV TH0, 35H", "optc": "MOV T0, #35H", "optd": "MOV T0, 35H", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bit-addressable memory locations are:", "opta": "10H through 1FH", "optb": "20H through 2FH", "optc": "30H through 3FH", "optd": "40H through 4FH", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 8-bit address bus allows access to an address range of:", "opta": "0000 to FFFFH", "optb": "000 to FFFH", "optc": "00 to FFH", "optd": "0 to FH", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The contents of the accumulator after this operation  MOV A,#0BH ANL A,#2CH will be", "opta": "11010111", "optb": "11011010", "optc": "00001000", "optd": "00101000", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The start-conversion on the ADC0804 is done by using the:", "opta": "", "optb": "CS line", "optc": "INTR line", "optd": "V ref/2 line", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This program code will be executed once:  STAT: MOV A, #01H \u00a0JNZ STAT", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following instructions will move the contents of register 3 to the accumulator?", "opta": "MOV 3R, A", "optb": "MOV R3, A", "optc": "MOV A, R3", "optd": "MOV A, 3R", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements will add the accumulator and register 3?", "opta": "ADD @R3, @A", "optb": "ADD @A, R3", "optc": "ADD R3, A", "optd": "ADD A, R3", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Data transfer from I/O to external data memory can only be done with the MOV command.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands will move the number 27H into the accumulator?", "opta": "MOV A, P27", "optb": "MOV A, #27H", "optc": "MOV A, 27H", "optd": "MOV A, @27", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This program code will read data from port 0 and write it to port 2, and it will stop looping when bit 3 of port 2 is set:  STAT: MOV A, PO \u00a0MOV P2,A \u00a0JNB P2.3, STAT", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands will move the value at port 3 to register 2?", "opta": "MOV P2, R3", "optb": "MOV R3, P2", "optc": "MOV 3P, R2", "optd": "MOV R2, P3", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The number of data registers is:", "opta": "8", "optb": "16", "optc": "32", "optd": "64", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When the 8051 is reset and the EA line is LOW, the program counter points to the first program instruction in the:", "opta": "internal code memory", "optb": "external code memory", "optc": "internal data memory", "optd": "external data memory", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The designs of a centigrade thermometer and a PWM speed-control circuit can be implemented by the 8051.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between the 8031 and the 8051?", "opta": "The 8031 has no interrupts.", "optb": "The 8031 is ROM-less.", "optc": "The 8051 is ROM-less.", "optd": "The 8051 has 64 bytes more memory.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The I/O port that does not have a dual-purpose role is:", "opta": "port 0", "optb": "port 1", "optc": "port 2", "optd": "port 3", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To interface external EPROM memory for applications, it is necessary to demultiplex the address/data lines of the 8051.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following command will copy the accumulator to the location whose address is 23H: MOV 23H,A", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The special function registers can be referred to by their hex addresses or by their register names.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The contents of the accumulator after this operation  MOV A,#2BH ORL A,00H will be:", "opta": "1B H", "optb": "2B H", "optc": "3B H", "optd": "4B H", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following program will cause the 8051 to be stuck in a loop:  LOOP: MOV A, #00H \u00a0JNZ LOOP", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands will copy the contents of RAM whose address is in register 0 to port 1?", "opta": "MOV @ P1, R0", "optb": "MOV @ R0, P1", "optc": "MOV P1, @ R0", "optd": "MOV P1, R0", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The statement LCALL READ passes control to the line labelled READ.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands will copy the contents of location 4H to the accumulator?", "opta": "MOV A, 04H", "optb": "MOV A, L4", "optc": "MOV L4, A", "optd": "MOV 04H, A", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The microcontroller is useful in systems that have nonvariable programs for dedicated applications.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The total amount of external code memory that can be interfaced to the 8051 is:", "opta": "32K", "optb": "64K", "optc": "128K", "optd": "256K", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ADC0804 has ________ resolution.", "opta": "4-bit", "optb": "8-bit", "optc": "16-bit", "optd": "32-bit", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A HIGH on which pin resets the 8051 microcontroller?", "opta": "RESET", "optb": "RST", "optc": "PSEN", "optd": "RSET", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An alternate function of port pin P3.1 in the 8051 is:", "opta": "serial port input", "optb": "serial port output", "optc": "memory write strobe", "optd": "memory read strobe", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following instructions will move the contents of the accumulator to register 6?", "opta": "MOV 6R, A", "optb": "MOV R6, A", "optc": "MOV A, 6R", "optd": "MOV A, R6", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following command will rotate the 8 bits of the accumulator one position to the left:  RL A", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An alternate function of port pin P3.0 (RXD) in the 8051 is:", "opta": "serial port input", "optb": "serial port output", "optc": "memory write strobe", "optd": "memory read strobe", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of waveform is shown in the given circuit?", "opta": "Sine wave", "optb": "Square wave", "optc": "Triangle wave", "optd": "Sawtooth wave", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In both induction and synchronous ac motors", "opta": "the operating speed is very steady", "optb": "the stator magnetic field is stationary", "optc": "the stator magnetic field rotates", "optd": "the \"squirrel cage\" forms the rotor", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the peak-to-peak voltage of the waveform in the given circuit?", "opta": "2 V", "optb": "4 V", "optc": "6 V", "optd": "8 V", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most practical alternators generate electricity from", "opta": "a coil rotating within a magnetic field", "optb": "a magnetic field rotating around fixed windings", "optc": "a permanent magnet rotating within a varying electromagnetic field", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A half-cycle average voltage of 12 V is equal to what rms voltage?", "opta": "13.33 V", "optb": "8.48 V", "optc": "18.84 V", "optd": "7.64 V", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the instantaneous peak voltage at 250\u00b0 on a 6 V peak sine wave?", "opta": "+5.64 V", "optb": "\u20135.64 V", "optc": "+26.13 V", "optd": "\u201326.13 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Calculate the positive-going slope of the waveform in the given circuit.", "opta": "5 V/ms", "optb": "2.5 V/ms", "optc": "2.5 V/s", "optd": "5 V/s", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A rectangular wave that has a duty cycle of 50% could be called a", "opta": "\"c\" wave", "optb": "sawtooth wave", "optc": "square wave", "optd": "triangular wave", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Calculate the duty cycle of the repetitive pulse waveform in the given circuit.", "opta": "8.33%", "optb": "0%", "optc": "33.33%", "optd": "25%", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The effective value of a sine wave is equal to", "opta": "0.707 of peak voltage", "optb": "0.636 of peak voltage", "optc": "sin 45\u00b0 of peak voltage", "optd": "both 0.707 of peak voltage and sin 45\u00b0 of peak voltage", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the dc voltage of the waveform in the given circuit?", "opta": "2 V", "optb": "4 V", "optc": "6 V", "optd": "8 V", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the fourth harmonic of a fundamental frequency of 400 Hz?", "opta": "100 Hz", "optb": "4 kHz", "optc": "4 Hz", "optd": "1.6 kHz", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the peak voltage across R3 in the given circuit?", "opta": "1.2 V", "optb": "5 V", "optc": "7 V", "optd": "12 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which point is the trailing edge of the repetitive pulse waveform in the given circuit?", "opta": "Point A", "optb": "Point B", "optc": "Point C", "optd": "Point D", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A single-phase induction motor", "opta": "is self-starting", "optb": "operates at a fixed speed", "optc": "is less reliable than a three-phase synchronous motor", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the average voltage when a rectangular wave's base line voltage is 20 V, its peak-to-peak voltage is 50 V, and its duty cycle is 20%?", "opta": "26 V", "optb": "30 V", "optc": "40 V", "optd": "45 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the two main applications for ac?", "opta": "direct, pulsating", "optb": "electric, magnetic", "optc": "power, information", "optd": "static, dynamic", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The distance that a signal's energy can travel in the time it takes for one cycle to occur is called the signal's:", "opta": "amplitude", "optb": "frequency", "optc": "wavelength", "optd": "period", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One oscilloscope selector knob that allows the major and minor divisions of the graticule to be used to determine a signal amplitude value is called the:", "opta": "time/cm control", "optb": "position control", "optc": "intensity control", "optd": "volts/cm control", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If current varies periodically from zero to a maximum, back to zero, and then repeats, the signal is:", "opta": "direct", "optb": "alternating", "optc": "pulsating", "optd": "repetitive", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What voltage will an ac voltmeter display?", "opta": "rms", "optb": "average", "optc": "peak", "optd": "peak-to-peak", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the peak value of a household appliance that uses a 230 V ac source?", "opta": "163 V", "optb": "230 V", "optc": "325 V", "optd": "480 V", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the waveform period difference between the 60 Hz electricity used in this country and the 50 Hz used in Europe?", "opta": "3 ms", "optb": "16 ms", "optc": "4 ms", "optd": "20 ms", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Test equipment selection enables the technician to both generate signals and:", "opta": "change circuit conditions", "optb": "inject signals", "optc": "sense circuit conditions", "optd": "change signal frequencies", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why is ac current transfer more effective than dc current transfer over long distances?", "opta": "due to the height of power lines", "optb": "due to the use of ac generators", "optc": "due to step-up and step-down transformers reducing I2R losses", "optd": "due to very high voltages", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A sine wave reaches maximum positive voltage at:", "opta": "90\u00b0", "optb": "0\u00b0", "optc": "\u201390\u00b0", "optd": "360\u00b0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which percentages of full-amplitude rise time are used for a pulse wave?", "opta": "0 to 50 percent", "optb": "0 to 100 percent", "optc": "5 to 95 percent", "optd": "10 to 90 percent", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the average value of a 12 V peak wave?", "opta": "3.82 V", "optb": "4.24 V", "optc": "7.64 V", "optd": "9.42 V", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A test equipment item that has the ability to produce either square, triangular, or sawtooth waveforms is called:", "opta": "a function generator", "optb": "a radio frequency generator", "optc": "an audio frequency generator", "optd": "a frequency meter or counter", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The current is flowing in what direction?", "opta": "clockwise", "optb": "counterclockwise", "optc": "in both directions at the same time", "optd": "50% of the time clockwise and 50% of the time counterclockwise", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does the CRT oscilloscope display?", "opta": "voltage and period", "optb": "current and frequency", "optc": "rms voltage and current", "optd": "frequency and voltage", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Power companies supply ac, not dc, because:", "opta": "it is easier to transmit ac", "optb": "there is no longer a need for dc", "optc": "dc is more dangerous", "optd": "there are not enough batteries", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a waveform period is determined to be 10 microseconds in duration, what is the frequency of the signal?", "opta": "100 Hz", "optb": "1000 Hz", "optc": "10 kHz", "optd": "100 kHz", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The phase difference between sine waves of different frequencies is:", "opta": "equal to their frequency differences", "optb": "the difference in their fixed time displacement", "optc": "the same throughout time", "optd": "constantly changing", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a sine wave signal is 100 mV peak-to-peak, how many volts would be measured by a voltmeter?", "opta": "14.14 mV", "optb": "35.4 mV", "optc": "63.7 mV", "optd": "70.7 mV", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What term expresses the frequency of a rectangular wave?", "opta": "Hz", "optb": "period", "optc": "PRF", "optd": "PRT", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "AC effective voltage is named:", "opta": "average", "optb": "peak", "optc": "peak-to-peak", "optd": "root mean square", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a voltmeter measures a sine wave as 500 mV, what would be its average value?", "opta": "159.0 mV", "optb": "318.5 mV", "optc": "353.5 mV", "optd": "451.0 mV", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Some AC Voltage Conversion: \n\nPeak to rms:     multiply peak by 0.707.\nPeak to average: multiply peak by 0.637.\nRms to peak:     multiply rms  by 1.414.\nRms to average:  multiply rms  by 0.9.\nAverage to rms:  multiply avg  by 1.111.\nAverage to peak: multiply avg  by 1.567.\n\nMostly voltmeter shows rms value. So, Vav = 0.9*Vrms \n = 0.9*500.\n = 450mV ~ [D] 451 mV."}, {"question": "One adjustable knob on the oscilloscope that allows the trace to be aligned with a reference graticule is called the:", "opta": "position control", "optb": "focus control", "optc": "intensity control", "optd": "volts/cm control", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Signal comparisons may be most easily seen when using which item of test equipment?", "opta": "spectrum analyzer", "optb": "multimeter", "optc": "function generator", "optd": "dual trace oscilloscope", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The magnitude that an alternation varies from zero is called its:", "opta": "altitude", "optb": "amplitude", "optc": "attitude", "optd": "polarity", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The power that is distributed from a power plant to your home is:", "opta": "high voltage to high voltage", "optb": "low voltage to high voltage", "optc": "high voltage to low voltage", "optd": "low voltage to low voltage", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A rectangular wave that has a duty cycle of 50 percent could be called a:", "opta": "c wave", "optb": "sawtooth wave", "optc": "square wave", "optd": "triangle wave", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A triangle wave consists of repeating:", "opta": "positive ramps only", "optb": "negative ramps only", "optc": "positive and negative ramps of equal value", "optd": "positive and negative ramps of unequal value", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the name of a device used to directly measure the frequency of a periodic wave?", "opta": "oscilloscope", "optb": "frequency meter or counter", "optc": "audio frequency generator", "optd": "radio frequency generator", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which control should be moved to display more cycles of a signal on an oscilloscope?", "opta": "horizontal position to left or right", "optb": "volts/cm to a smaller number", "optc": "vertical position to top or bottom", "optd": "time/cm to a higher setting", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the name of a device that converts sound waves to electrical waves?", "opta": "an amplifier", "optb": "an antenna", "optc": "a filter", "optd": "a microphone", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the frequency of a radio wave is increased, then its wavelength will:", "opta": "increase", "optb": "decrease", "optc": "remain the same", "optd": "cannot tell", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the rms voltage value of an ac signal whose peak oscilloscope display uses 3 major divisions above the zero setting? (V/cm = 5)", "opta": "5.3 V", "optb": "10.6 V", "optc": "15.0 V", "optd": "21.2 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the peak-to-peak current value when an ammeter measures a 20 mA value?", "opta": "14 mA", "optb": "28 mA", "optc": "40 mA", "optd": "57 mA", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How long would it take to transmit an electromagnetic wave to a receiving antenna 1,000 miles away?", "opta": "5.38 ms", "optb": "10.8 ms", "optc": "53.8 ms", "optd": "108 ms", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the waveform period of a square wave signal that horizontally covers 3 major divisions per cycle? (time/cm = 50 ms)", "opta": "50 ms", "optb": "100 ms", "optc": "150 ms", "optd": "200 ms", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A sine wave has:", "opta": "four quadrants", "optb": "two alternations", "optc": "one period", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the peak-to peak voltage of a 56 Vrms ac voltage?", "opta": "158 V", "optb": "164 V", "optc": "82 V", "optd": "79 V", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One oscilloscope selector knob that allows the major and minor divisions of the graticule to be used to determine a waveform period is called a:", "opta": "focus control", "optb": "time/cm control", "optc": "intensity control", "optd": "volts/cm control", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the period of a 16 MHz sine wave?", "opta": "196 ns", "optb": "62.5 ns", "optc": "31.25 ns", "optd": "19.9 ns", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a type of error associated with digital-to-analog converters (DACs)?", "opta": "nonmonotonic error", "optb": "incorrect output codes", "optc": "offset error", "optd": "nonmonotonic and offset error", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 4-bit R/2R digital-to-analog (DAC) converter has a reference of 5 volts. What is the analog output for the input code 0101.", "opta": "0.3125 V", "optb": "3.125 V", "optc": "0.78125 V", "optd": "\u20133.125 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A binary-weighted digital-to-analog converter has an input resistor of 100 k. If the resistor is connected to a 5 V source, the current through the resistor is:", "opta": "50 A", "optb": "5 mA", "optc": "500 A", "optd": "50 mA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the resolution of a digital-to-analog converter (DAC)?", "opta": "It is the comparison between the actual output of the converter and its expected output.", "optb": "It is the deviation between the ideal straight-line output and the actual output of the converter.", "optc": "It is the smallest analog output change that can occur as a result of an increment in the digital input.", "optd": "It is its ability to resolve between forward and reverse steps when sequenced over its entire range.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The practical use of binary-weighted digital-to-analog converters is limited to:", "opta": "R/2R ladder D/A converters", "optb": "4-bit D/A converters", "optc": "8-bit D/A converters", "optd": "op-amp comparators", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The difference between analog voltage represented by two adjacent digital codes, or the analog step size, is the:", "opta": "quantization", "optb": "accuracy", "optc": "resolution", "optd": "monotonicity", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The primary disadvantage of the flash analog-to digital converter (ADC) is that:", "opta": "it requires the input voltage to be applied to the inputs simultaneously", "optb": "a long conversion time is required", "optc": "a large number of output lines is required to simultaneously decode the input voltage", "optd": "a large number of comparators is required to represent a reasonable sized binary number", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A binary-weighted digital-to-analog converter has a feedback resistor, Rf, of 12 k. If 50 A of current is through the resistor, the voltage out of the circuit is:", "opta": "0.6 V", "optb": "\u20130.6 V", "optc": "0.1 V", "optd": "\u20130.1 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the major advantage of the R/2R ladder digital-to-analog (DAC), as compared to a binary-weighted digital-to-analog DAC converter?", "opta": "It only uses two different resistor values.", "optb": "It has fewer parts for the same number of inputs.", "optc": "Its operation is much easier to analyze.", "optd": "The virtual ground is eliminated and the circuit is therefore easier to understand and troubleshoot.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The resolution of a 0\u20135 V 6-bit digital-to-analog converter (DAC) is:", "opta": "63%", "optb": "64%", "optc": "1.56%", "optd": "15.6%", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a flash analog-to-digital converter, the output of each comparator is connected to an input of a:", "opta": "decoder", "optb": "priority encoder", "optc": "multiplexer", "optd": "demultiplexer", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not an analog-to-digital (ADC) conversion error?", "opta": "differential nonlinearity", "optb": "missing code", "optc": "incorrect code", "optd": "offset", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sample-and-hold circuits in analog-to digital converters (ADCs) are designed to:", "opta": "sample and hold the output of the binary counter during the conversion process", "optb": "stabilize the comparator's threshold voltage during the conversion process", "optc": "stabilize the input analog signal during the conversion process", "optd": "sample and hold the D/A converter staircase waveform during the conversion process", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The two basic types of signals are analog and:", "opta": "digilog", "optb": "digital", "optc": "vetilog", "optd": "sine wave", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following characterizes an analog quantity?", "opta": "Discrete levels represent changes in a quantity.", "optb": "Its values follow a logarithmic response curve.", "optc": "It can be described with a finite number of steps.", "optd": "It has a continuous set of values over a given range.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "ASCII stands for:", "opta": "American Serial Communication Interface", "optb": "Additive Signal Coupling Interface", "optc": "American Standard Code for Information Interchange", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of signal is represented by discrete values?", "opta": "noisy signal", "optb": "nonlinear", "optc": "analog", "optd": "digital", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A data conversion system may be used to interface a digital computer system to:", "opta": "an analog output device", "optb": "a digital output device", "optc": "an analog input device", "optd": "a digital printer", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When 1100010 is divided by 0101, what will be the decimal remainder?", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "4", "optd": "6", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the two types of basic adder circuits?", "opta": "half adder and full adder", "optb": "half adder and parallel adder", "optc": "asynchronous and synchronous", "optd": "one's complement and two's complement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Adding the two's complement of \u201311 + (\u20132) will yield which two's complement answer?", "opta": "1110 1101", "optb": "1111 1001", "optc": "1111 0011", "optd": "1110 1001", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The two's complement system is to be used to add the signed numbers 11110010 and 11110011. Determine, in decimal, the sign and value of each number and their sum.", "opta": "\u201314 and \u201313; \u201327", "optb": "\u2013113 and \u2013114; 227", "optc": "\u201327 and \u201313; 40", "optd": "\u201311 and \u201316; \u201327", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The fast carry or look-ahead carry circuits found in most 4-bit parallel-adder circuits:", "opta": "increase ripple delay", "optb": "add a 1 to complemented inputs", "optc": "reduce propagation delay", "optd": "determine sign and magnitude", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many basic binary subtraction operations are possible?", "opta": "4", "optb": "3", "optc": "2", "optd": "1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many basic binary subtraction combinations are possible?", "opta": "4", "optb": "3", "optc": "2", "optd": "1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Use the two's complement system to add the signed numbers 11110010 and 11110011. Determine, in decimal, the sign and value of each number and  \ntheir sum.", "opta": "\u201314 and \u201313; \u201327", "optb": "\u2013113 and \u2013114; 227", "optc": "\u201327 and \u201313; 40", "optd": "\u201311 and \u201316; \u201327", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The selector inputs to an arithmetic-logic unit (ALU) determine the:", "opta": "selection of the IC", "optb": "arithmetic or logic function", "optc": "data word selection", "optd": "clock frequency to be used", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Adding in binary, the decimal values 26 + 27 will produce a sum of:", "opta": "111010", "optb": "110110", "optc": "110101", "optd": "101011", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Binary subtraction of a decimal 15 from 43 will utilize which two's complement?", "opta": "101011", "optb": "110000", "optc": "011100", "optd": "110001", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When multiplying in binary the decimal values 13 \u00d7 11, what is the third partial product?", "opta": "100000", "optb": "100001", "optc": "0000", "optd": "1011", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The range of an 8-bit two's complement word is from:", "opta": "+12810 to \u201312810", "optb": "\u201312810 to +12710", "optc": "+12810 to \u201312710", "optd": "+12710 to \u201312710", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The center frequency of a band-pass filter is always equal to the", "opta": "bandwidth", "optb": "\u20133 dB frequency", "optc": "bandwidth divided by Q", "optd": "geometric average of the critical frequencies", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The formula  shows that for a given capacitor, if the voltage changes at a constant rate with respect to time, the current will", "opta": "increase", "optb": "decrease", "optc": "be constant", "optd": "decrease logarithmically", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A zero-level detector is a", "opta": "comparator with a sine-wave output", "optb": "comparator with a trip point referenced to zero", "optc": "peak detector", "optd": "limiter", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A digital-to-analog converter is an application of the", "opta": "scaling adder", "optb": "voltage-to-current converter", "optc": "noninverting amplifier", "optd": "adjustable bandwidth circuit", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the value of resistor Rf in an averaging amplifier circuit is equal to the value of one input resistor divided by the number of inputs, the output will be equal to", "opta": "the average of the individual inputs", "optb": "the inverted sum of the individual inputs", "optc": "the sum of the individual inputs", "optd": "the inverted average of the individual inputs", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the input to a comparator is a sine wave, the output is a", "opta": "ramp voltage", "optb": "sine wave", "optc": "rectangular wave", "optd": "sawtooth wave", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A basic series regulator has", "opta": "an error detector", "optb": "a load", "optc": "a reference voltage", "optd": "both an error detector and a reference voltage", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A comparator is an example of a(n)", "opta": "active filter", "optb": "current source", "optc": "linear circuit", "optd": "nonlinear circuit", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Initially, the closed-loop gain (Acl) of a Wien-bridge oscillator should be", "opta": "Acl < 3", "optb": "Acl > 3", "optc": "0", "optd": "Acl  1", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an averaging amplifier, the input resistances are", "opta": "equal to the feedback resistance", "optb": "less than the feedback resistance", "optc": "greater than the feedback resistance", "optd": "unequal", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A triangular-wave oscillator can consist of an op-amp comparator, followed by a(n)", "opta": "differentiator", "optb": "amplifier", "optc": "integrator", "optd": "multivibrator", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ramp voltage at the output of an op-amp integrator", "opta": "increases or decreases at a linear rate", "optb": "increases or decreases exponentially", "optc": "is always increasing and never decreasing", "optd": "is constant", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A two-pole high-pass active filter would have a roll-off rate of", "opta": "40 dB/decade", "optb": "\u201340 dB/decade", "optc": "20 dB/decade", "optd": "\u201320 dB/decade", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When transistors are used in digital circuits they usually operate in the:", "opta": "active region", "optb": "breakdown region", "optc": "saturation and cutoff regions", "optd": "linear region", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Three different Q points are shown on a dc load line. The upper Q point represents the:", "opta": "minimum current gain", "optb": "intermediate current gain", "optc": "maximum current gain", "optd": "cutoff point", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A transistor has a  of 250 and a base current, IB, of 20  A. The collector current, IC, equals:", "opta": "500  A", "optb": "5 mA", "optc": "50 mA", "optd": "5 A", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A current ratio of IC/IE is usually less than one and is called:", "opta": "beta", "optb": "theta", "optc": "alpha", "optd": "omega", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With the positive probe on an NPN base, an ohmmeter reading between the other transistor terminals should be:", "opta": "open", "optb": "infinite", "optc": "low resistance", "optd": "high resistance", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a C-E configuration, an emitter resistor is used for:", "opta": "stabilization", "optb": "ac signal bypass", "optc": "collector bias", "optd": "higher gain", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Voltage-divider bias provides:", "opta": "an unstable Q point", "optb": "a stable Q point", "optc": "a Q point that easily varies with changes in the transistor's current gain", "optd": "a Q point that is stable and easily varies with changes in the transistor\u0092s current gain", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To operate properly, a transistor's base-emitter junction must be forward biased with reverse bias applied to which junction?", "opta": "collector-emitter", "optb": "base-collector", "optc": "base-emitter", "optd": "collector-base", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ends of a load line drawn on a family of curves determine:", "opta": "saturation and cutoff", "optb": "the operating point", "optc": "the power curve", "optd": "the amplification factor", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If VCC = +18 V, voltage-divider resistor R1 is 4.7 k, and R2 is 1500, what is the base bias voltage?", "opta": "8.70 V", "optb": "4.35 V", "optc": "2.90 V", "optd": "0.7 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The C-B configuration is used to provide which type of gain?", "opta": "voltage", "optb": "current", "optc": "resistance", "optd": "power", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Q point on a load line may be used to determine:", "opta": "VC", "optb": "VCC", "optc": "VB", "optd": "IC", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A transistor may be used as a switching device or as a:", "opta": "fixed resistor", "optb": "tuning device", "optc": "rectifier", "optd": "variable resistor", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If an input signal ranges from 20\u201340 A (microamps), with an output signal ranging from .5\u20131.5 mA (milliamps), what is the ac beta?", "opta": "0.05", "optb": "20", "optc": "50", "optd": "500", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is beta's current ratio?", "opta": "IC/IB", "optb": "IC/IE", "optc": "IB/IE", "optd": "IE/IB", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A collector characteristic curve is a graph showing:", "opta": "emitter current (IE) versus collector-emitter voltage (VCE) with (VBB) base bias voltage held constant", "optb": "collector current (IC) versus collector-emitter voltage (VCE) with (VBB) base bias voltage held constant", "optc": "collector current (IC) versus collector-emitter voltage (VC) with (VBB) base bias voltage held constant", "optd": "collector current (IC) versus collector-emitter voltage (VCC) with (VBB) base bias voltage held constant", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With low-power transistor packages, the base terminal is usually the:", "opta": "tab end", "optb": "middle", "optc": "right end", "optd": "stud mount", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a silicon diode is forward biased, what is VBE for a C-E configuration?", "opta": "voltage-divider bias", "optb": "0.4 V", "optc": "0.7 V", "optd": "emitter voltage", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the current gain for a common-base configuration where IE = 4.2 mA and IC = 4.0 mA?", "opta": "16.80", "optb": "1.05", "optc": "0.20", "optd": "0.95", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a PNP circuit, the most positive voltage is probably:", "opta": "ground", "optb": "VC", "optc": "VBE", "optd": "VCC", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a 2 mV signal produces a 2 V output, what is the voltage gain?", "opta": "0.001", "optb": "0.004", "optc": "100", "optd": "1000", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The symbol hfe is the same as:", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "hi-fi", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most of the electrons in the base of an NPN transistor flow:", "opta": "out of the base lead", "optb": "into the collector", "optc": "into the emitter", "optd": "into the base supply", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a transistor, collector current is controlled by:", "opta": "collector voltage", "optb": "base current", "optc": "collector resistance", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Total emitter current is:", "opta": "IE \u2013 IC", "optb": "IC + IE", "optc": "IB + IC", "optd": "IB \u2013 IC", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Often a common-collector will be the last stage before the load; the main function(s) of this stage is to:", "opta": "provide voltage gain", "optb": "provide phase inversion", "optc": "provide a high-frequency path to improve the frequency response", "optd": "buffer the voltage amplifiers from the low-resistance load and provide impedance matching for maximum power transfer", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a C-C configuration to operate properly, the collector-base junction should be reverse biased, while forward bias should be applied to which junction?", "opta": "collector-emitter", "optb": "base-emitter", "optc": "collector-base", "optd": "cathode-anode", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The input/output relationship of the common-collector and common-base amplifiers is:", "opta": "270 degrees", "optb": "180 degrees", "optc": "90 degrees", "optd": "0 degrees", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a transistor operates at the middle of the dc load line, a decrease in the current gain will move the Q point:", "opta": "off the load line", "optb": "nowhere", "optc": "up", "optd": "down", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is the higher gain provided by a C-E configuration?", "opta": "voltage", "optb": "current", "optc": "resistance", "optd": "power", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the collector current for a C-E configuration with a beta of 100 and a base current of 30 A?", "opta": "30 A", "optb": ".3 A", "optc": "3 mA", "optd": "3 MA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a 20 Vac series RC circuit, if 20 V is measured across the resistor and 40 V is measured across the capacitor, the applied voltage is:", "opta": "45 V", "optb": "50 V", "optc": "55 V", "optd": "60 V", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Select the equation below that represents the relationship between charge, capacitance, and voltage for a capacitor.", "opta": "Q = CV", "optb": "C = QV", "optc": "", "optd": "V = IR", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When is a capacitor fully charged?", "opta": "when the voltage across its plates is  of the voltage from ground to one of its plates", "optb": "when the current through the capacitor is the same as when the capacitor is discharged", "optc": "when the voltage across the plates is 0.707 of the input voltage", "optd": "when the current through the capacitor is directly proportional to the area of the plates", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the reactive power in the given circuit?", "opta": "0 VAR", "optb": "691 VAR", "optc": "44.23 mVAR", "optd": "1.45 kVAR", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the angle theta value for a 5.6 F capacitor and a 50-ohm resistor in series with a 1.1 kHz, 5 Vac source?", "opta": "27.3 degrees", "optb": "62.7 degrees", "optc": "\u201327.3 degrees", "optd": "\u201362.7 degrees", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a 4.7 F capacitor is connected to a 1 kHz source, what is its capacitive reactance?", "opta": "4.7 ohms", "optb": "29.5 ohms", "optc": "34 ohms", "optd": "213 ohms", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total capacitance?", "opta": "1 F", "optb": "12 F", "optc": "0.615 F", "optd": "8 F", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is this circuit?", "opta": "bandpass filter", "optb": "high-pass filter", "optc": "low-pass filter", "optd": "differentiator", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "After which time constant can a capacitor be considered to be fully charged?", "opta": "first", "optb": "third", "optc": "fifth", "optd": "seventh", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "You could increase the time constant of an RC circuit by", "opta": "adding a resistor in parallel with the circuit resistance", "optb": "adding a capacitor in parallel with the circuit capacitance", "optc": "increasing the amplitude of the input voltage", "optd": "exchanging the position of the resistor and capacitor in the circuit", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A capacitor's rate of charge is considered:", "opta": "magnetic", "optb": "a current block", "optc": "linear", "optd": "exponential", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A resistor and an output capacitor form a series circuit with a square wave applied. The circuit is:", "opta": "an integrator", "optb": "a differentiator", "optc": "a multiplier", "optd": "a divider", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If an open capacitor is checked with an ohmmeter, the needle will:", "opta": "stay on zero", "optb": "stay on infinity", "optc": "move from zero to infinity", "optd": "move from infinity to zero", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the circuit's total current?", "opta": "4.57 mA", "optb": "9.327 mA", "optc": "11.570 mA", "optd": "13.830 mA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As a capacitor is being charged, current flowing into the capacitor will:", "opta": "increase", "optb": "decrease", "optc": "remain the same", "optd": "cannot tell", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the phase shift between the voltage across the resistor and the voltage from the source?", "opta": "VR leads VS by 17\u00b0", "optb": "VR leads VS by 73\u00b0", "optc": "VR lags VS by 73\u00b0", "optd": "VR lags VS by 17\u00b0", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A capacitor stores energy within a dielectric between the conducting plates in the form of:", "opta": "a magnetic field", "optb": "positive voltage", "optc": "negative voltage", "optd": "an electric field", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As a capacitor is being charged, the voltage across its terminals will:", "opta": "increase", "optb": "decrease", "optc": "remain the same", "optd": "oppose the source", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a 500 kHz signal source, what would be the value of a capacitor yielding a capacitive reactance of 1 k ?", "opta": "318 pF", "optb": "2 nF", "optc": "3.18 F", "optd": "2 F", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "After a capacitor has charged for 1 tc, what percentage of current remains in the resistor?", "opta": "63.2", "optb": "36.8", "optc": "13.5", "optd": "5.0", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a current of 40 mA flows through a series circuit consisting of a 0.4 F capacitor and a resistor in series with a 4 kHz, 40 Vac source, what is the total circuit impedance?", "opta": "10", "optb": "100", "optc": "1 k", "optd": "1 M", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the capacitance of the circuit shown in the given circuit?", "opta": "0.066 F", "optb": "0.9 F", "optc": "65.97 pF", "optd": "900 pF", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an ac circuit, an output capacitor and a resistor are connected in series with an ac signal. What filter action will be the result?", "opta": "bandpass", "optb": "low-pass", "optc": "high-pass", "optd": "band-stop", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total opposition to current in a series RC circuit called?", "opta": "impedance", "optb": "inductance", "optc": "reactance", "optd": "resistance", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is true?", "opta": "The voltage to which a capacitor is charged can change instantaneously.", "optb": "The current in a capacitive circuit takes time to change.", "optc": "A fully charged capacitor appears as a short to dc current.", "optd": "An uncharged capacitor appears as a short to an instantaneous change in current.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a capacitive circuit, current flow is limited to", "opta": "charging periods", "optb": "discharging periods", "optc": "neither charging periods nor discharging periods", "optd": "both charging periods and discharging periods", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What circuit has the following frequency response?", "opta": "bandpass filter", "optb": "high-pass filter", "optc": "low-pass filter", "optd": "integrator", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A capacitor is constructed of two parallel:", "opta": "conductors", "optb": "semiconductors", "optc": "inductors", "optd": "dielectrics", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following determines the capacitance of a capacitor?", "opta": "Plate area, dielectric strength, and plate separation", "optb": "Voltage rating, dielectric constant, and temperature coefficient", "optc": "Temperature coefficient, plate area, and plate separation", "optd": "Plate area, dielectric constant, and plate separation", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most older types of paper capacitors have been replaced by which type of construction?", "opta": "electrolytic", "optb": "plastic film", "optc": "oxide casing", "optd": "waxed paper", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If C1, a 4.7 F capacitor, and C2, a 3.3 F capacitor are in series with 18 Vdc applied, what is the voltage across C1?", "opta": "3.3 V", "optb": "7.4 V", "optc": "6.6 V", "optd": "9.4 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the impedance of a series RC circuit that consists of a 0.22 F capacitor and a 200-ohm resistor connected to a 3 kHz source?", "opta": "214 ohms", "optb": "313 ohms", "optc": "414 ohms", "optd": "880 ohms", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the reactance value for a capacitor installed in a dc circuit?", "opta": "zero", "optb": "moderate", "optc": "infinite", "optd": "cannot tell", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a purely capacitive circuit,", "opta": "current leads voltage by 90\u00b0", "optb": "voltage leads current by 90\u00b0", "optc": "current lags voltage by 90\u00b0", "optd": "current and voltage have a phase relationship of 0\u00b0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How long would it take the capacitor in the given circuit to completely discharge if the switch was in position 2?", "opta": "22 ms", "optb": "69 ms", "optc": "345 ms", "optd": "420 ms", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the capacitive reactance if I = 1 amp, V = 2 volts, C = 5 F, and frequency = 10 Hz?", "opta": "0.2", "optb": "0.5", "optc": "0.02", "optd": "0.003", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is wrong with a leaky capacitor?", "opta": "It is open.", "optb": "It is shorted.", "optc": "The dielectric resistance has increased.", "optd": "The dielectric resistance has decreased.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the value of a capacitor labeled 102?", "opta": "10,000 pF", "optb": "1000 pF", "optc": "1000 F", "optd": "10,000 F", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the dielectric constant of a capacitor is decreased, then its capacitance will:", "opta": "increase", "optb": "decrease", "optc": "remain the same", "optd": "be destroyed", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the dielectric constant for ceramic?", "opta": "between 6 and 8000", "optb": "5.0", "optc": "between 5 and 1000", "optd": "3000", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the voltage across a capacitor after being charged from a 100 V source for a period of one time constant?", "opta": "37.8 V", "optb": "38 V", "optc": "63 V", "optd": "101 V", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the dc charging/discharging time constant for the circuit?", "opta": "294 ps", "optb": "13.5 ms", "optc": "21.25 ms", "optd": "2.16 Gs", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Power stored from the source and then returned to the source is called:", "opta": "apparent power", "optb": "impedance power", "optc": "reactive power", "optd": "true power", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Capacitor value markings are usually:", "opta": "alphanumeric", "optb": "color dabs", "optc": "standard", "optd": "white print", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A source voltage across a capacitor will:", "opta": "lead the current by 90 degrees", "optb": "lead the current by 180 degrees", "optc": "lag the current by 90 degrees", "optd": "lag the current by 180 degrees", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How long would it take the capacitor in the given circuit to completely charge if the switch was in position 1?", "opta": "22 ms", "optb": "69 ms", "optc": "345 ms", "optd": "440 ms", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An 8 V power source is charging a capacitor. How many volts will be across the capacitor at the second time constant?", "opta": "1 volt", "optb": "3 volts", "optc": "5 volts", "optd": "7 volts", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The material used between the plates of a capacitor is called its:", "opta": "insulation material", "optb": "dielectric material", "optc": "separation material", "optd": "plate-divider material", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a circuit consists of a capacitor and a resistor in series with a voltage source, and the voltage across the resistor is zero, then the capacitor is:", "opta": "charging", "optb": "discharging", "optc": "fully charged", "optd": "fully discharged", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which material has the highest dielectric strength?", "opta": "Air", "optb": "Paper", "optc": "Mica", "optd": "Oil", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the circuit's impedance?", "opta": "1192", "optb": "843", "optc": "723", "optd": "511", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an ac circuit, a capacitor and an output resistor are connected in series with an ac signal. What filter action will be the result?", "opta": "bandpass", "optb": "low-pass", "optc": "high-pass", "optd": "band-stop", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the impedance of this circuit?", "opta": "5928", "optb": "2000", "optc": "1902", "optd": "1798", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Impedance Cannot be Directly Measured, We Need to find Xc first.\nSo,\nXc = 1/2\u03c0fC.\nXc = 1/( 2 x 3.14 x 5000 x 0.01 x 10-6 ).\nXc = 3184.7.\nZ = Sqrt( Xc2 + R2 ).\nZ = Sqrt( 3184.72 + 50002 ).\nZ = 5928 &ohm;."}, {"question": "What is the reactive power?", "opta": "6.8 mW", "optb": "9.8 mW", "optc": "12.8 mW", "optd": "15.8 mW", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A practical capacitor", "opta": "is a short to dc", "optb": "looks like a capacitor in parallel with a resistor", "optc": "is an open to ac", "optd": "stores energy in a magnetic field", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the reference vector for parallel RC circuits?", "opta": "R", "optb": "I", "optc": "C", "optd": "V", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do variable capacitors use for dielectric?", "opta": "ceramic, electrolytic, mica, or paper", "optb": "air, ceramic, mica, or plastic", "optc": "ceramic, paper, plastic, or mica", "optd": "mica, ceramic, plastic, or electrolytic", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a charged capacitor is disconnected from a circuit, it will:", "opta": "immediately discharge", "optb": "recharge", "optc": "remain charged", "optd": "leak the charge", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total current for a 5 MHz, 1 Vac circuit that consists of a 27 pF capacitor and a 1 k resistor connected in parallel?", "opta": "459 A", "optb": "647 A", "optc": "1.31 mA", "optd": "1.85 mA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the value of a capacitor that can store two coulombs of charge when 500 volts is applied across its plates?", "opta": "4 F", "optb": "250 F", "optc": "4,000 F", "optd": "250 F", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The strength of an electric field at a given point is proportional to the potential difference on the plates and inversely proportional to the:", "opta": "plate separation", "optb": "negative plate only", "optc": "field strength", "optd": "charge difference", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is ac current related to ac voltage in a purely capacitive circuit?", "opta": "AC current is 0.707 of the ac voltage.", "optb": "AC current lags ac voltage.", "optc": "AC current is 0.637 of the ac voltage.", "optd": "AC current leads ac voltage.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the voltage across the capacitor?", "opta": "7.07 V", "optb": "1.11 V", "optc": "111 mV", "optd": "7.07 mV", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a given charge difference, electrostatic field strength varies according to:", "opta": "plate differential", "optb": "plate area", "optc": "plate distance", "optd": "dielectric quantity", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A capacitor has 25 V across its plates and a stored charge of 1500 C. What is the capacitance value?", "opta": "60 pF", "optb": "60 F", "optc": "16.67 mF", "optd": "37.5 mF", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A capacitor and an output resistor form a series circuit with a square wave applied. The circuit is:", "opta": "an integrator", "optb": "a differentiator", "optc": "a multiplier", "optd": "a divider", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Capacitive reactance values connected in series offer", "opta": "an increase in total XC", "optb": "a decrease in total XC", "optc": "no change in total XC", "optd": "total opposition to voltage in the circuit", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The quantity that represents an ideal capacitor dissipating 0 W of power is", "opta": "instantaneous power", "optb": "true power", "optc": "reactive power", "optd": "resistive power", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a capacitor is placed across a 20 V source, what will be the amount of charge after 5 tc?", "opta": "5.0 V", "optb": "12.8 V", "optc": "13.5 V", "optd": "20 V", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the impedance of an ac RC parallel circuit if the resistance is 12 ohms and the capacitive reactance equals 5 ohms?", "opta": "0.2 ohms", "optb": "3.5 ohms", "optc": "4.6 ohms", "optd": "13 ohms", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What will a 1 F capacitor store?", "opta": "one coulomb of charge", "optb": "6.24 x 1012 electrons", "optc": "one volt", "optd": "one A of current", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an RC circuit, true power (PR) equals:", "opta": "", "optb": "VS \u00d7 I", "optc": "I2R", "optd": "VT \u00d7 RT", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the power factor if the apparent power of a circuit is 5 W, while the true power is 4 W?", "opta": "0.0 W", "optb": "0.8 W", "optc": "1.0 W", "optd": "1.25 W", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the reactive power of a circuit is 50 mW while the apparent power is 64 mW, then what is the true power of the circuit?", "opta": "14 mW", "optb": "36 mW", "optc": "40 mW", "optd": "114 mW", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many inputs are required for a 1-of-10 BCD decoder?", "opta": "4", "optb": "8", "optc": "10", "optd": "1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most demultiplexers facilitate which of the following?", "opta": "decimal to hexadecimal", "optb": "single input, multiple outputs", "optc": "ac to dc", "optd": "odd parity to even parity", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One application of a digital multiplexer is to facilitate:", "opta": "code conversion", "optb": "parity checking", "optc": "parallel-to-serial data conversion", "optd": "data generation", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Select one of the following statements that best describes the parity method of error detection:", "opta": "Parity checking is best suited for detecting single-bit errors in transmitted codes.", "optb": "Parity checking is best suited for detecting double-bit errors that occur during the transmission of codes from one location to another.", "optc": "Parity checking is not suitable for detecting single-bit errors in transmitted codes.", "optd": "Parity checking is capable of detecting and correcting errors in transmitted codes.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A multiplexed display:", "opta": "accepts data inputs from one line and passes this data to multiple output lines", "optb": "uses one display to present two or more pieces of information", "optc": "accepts data inputs from multiple lines and passes this data to multiple output lines", "optd": "accepts data inputs from several lines and multiplexes this input data to four BCD lines", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When two or more inputs are active simultaneously, the process is called:", "opta": "first-in, first-out processing", "optb": "priority encoding", "optc": "ripple blanking", "optd": "priority decoding", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of decoder will select one of sixteen outputs, depending on the 4-bit binary input value?", "opta": "hexadecimal", "optb": "dual octal outputs", "optc": "binary-to-hexadecimal", "optd": "hexadecimal-to-binary", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A magnitude comparator determines:", "opta": "A  B and if A  B or A >> B", "optb": "A   B and if A > B or A < b", "optc": "A = B and if A > B or A < b", "optd": "A  B and if A < b or a > B", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A circuit that responds to a specific set of signals to produce a related digital signal output is called a(n):", "opta": "BCD matrix", "optb": "display driver", "optc": "encoder", "optd": "decoder", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which digital system translates coded characters into a more intelligible form?", "opta": "encoder", "optb": "display", "optc": "counter", "optd": "decoder", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A basic multiplexer principle can be demonstrated through the use of a:", "opta": "single-pole relay", "optb": "DPDT switch", "optc": "rotary switch", "optd": "linear stepper", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a BCD-to-seven-segment converter, why must a code converter be utilized?", "opta": "No conversion is necessary.", "optb": "to convert the 4-bit BCD into gray code", "optc": "to convert the 4-bit BCD into 10-bit code", "optd": "to convert the 4-bit BCD into 7-bit code", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When referring to instruction words, a mnemonic is:", "opta": "a short abbreviation for the operand address", "optb": "a short abbreviation for the operation to be performed", "optc": "a short abbreviation for the data word stored at the operand address", "optd": "shorthand for machine language", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between mnemonic codes and machine codes?", "opta": "There is no difference.", "optb": "Machine codes are in binary, mnemonic codes are in shorthand English.", "optc": "Machine codes are in shorthand English, mnemonic codes are in binary.", "optd": "Machine codes are in shorthand English, mnemonic codes are a high-level language.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which bus is bidirectional?", "opta": "data bus", "optb": "control bus", "optc": "address bus", "optd": "multiplexed bus", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The software used to drive microprocessor-based systems is called:", "opta": "assembly language programs", "optb": "firmware", "optc": "BASIC interpreter instructions", "optd": "flowchart instructions", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A microprocessor unit, a memory unit, and an input/output unit form a:", "opta": "CPU", "optb": "compiler", "optc": "microcomputer", "optd": "ALU", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many buses are connected as part of the 8085 microprocessor?", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "5", "optd": "8", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a computer bus?", "opta": "data bus", "optb": "timer bus", "optc": "control bus", "optd": "address bus", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The technique of assigning a memory address to each I/O device in the SAM system is called:", "opta": "wired I/O", "optb": "I/O mapping", "optc": "dedicated I/O", "optd": "memory-mapped I/O", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many bits are used in the data bus?", "opta": "7", "optb": "8", "optc": "9", "optd": "16", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A port can be:", "opta": "strictly for input", "optb": "strictly for output", "optc": "bidirectional", "optd": "all the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a basic element within the microprocessor?", "opta": "microcontroller", "optb": "arithmetic-logic unit (ALU)", "optc": "temporary register", "optd": "accumulator", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many bits are used in the address bus?", "opta": "7", "optb": "8", "optc": "9", "optd": "16", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Exceptions to the 8085 microprocessor normal operation are called:", "opta": "jump instructions", "optb": "decoding", "optc": "interrupts", "optd": "jump instructions or interrupts", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is a varistor?", "opta": "a voltage-dependent resistor", "optb": "a voltage-dependent diode", "optc": "a current-dependent resistor", "optd": "a current-dependent diode", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of transformer is required to create a 180 degree input to a rectifier?", "opta": "center-tapped secondary", "optb": "step-down secondary", "optc": "stepped-up secondary", "optd": "split winding primary", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What circuit activity may shift a characteristic curve so that diode operating points are different?", "opta": "higher power (heat)", "optb": "higher resistance", "optc": "lower voltage", "optd": "lower current", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is wrong with this diode?", "opta": "open", "optb": "short", "optc": "nothing", "optd": "not enough data", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The dc current through each diode in a bridge rectifier equals:", "opta": "the load current", "optb": "half the dc load current", "optc": "twice the dc load current", "optd": "one-fourth the dc load current", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When matching polarity connections have been made and the potential difference (PD) is above 0.7 V, the diode is considered to be:", "opta": "not working", "optb": "forward biased", "optc": "reverse biased", "optd": "an open switch", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a power supply diagram, which block indicates a smooth dc output?", "opta": "transformer", "optb": "filter", "optc": "rectifier", "optd": "regulator", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a 169.7 V half-wave peak has an average voltage of 54 V, what is the average of two full-wave peaks?", "opta": "119.9 V", "optb": "108.0 V", "optc": "115.7 V", "optd": "339.4 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the current through the LED?", "opta": "0 mA", "optb": "23 mA", "optc": "18 mA", "optd": "13 mA", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The characteristic curve for the complex model of a silicon diode shows that", "opta": "the barrier potential is 0 V", "optb": "the barrier potential stays fixed at 0.7 V", "optc": "the barrier potential increases slightly with an increase in current", "optd": "the barrier potential decreases slightly with an increase in current", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Since diodes are destroyed by excessive current, circuits must have:", "opta": "higher voltage sources", "optb": "current limiting resistors", "optc": "more dopants", "optd": "higher current sources", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A diode for which you can change the reverse bias, and thus vary the capacitance is called a", "opta": "varactor diode", "optb": "tunnel diode", "optc": "zener diode", "optd": "switching diode", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A filtered full-wave rectifier voltage has a smaller ripple than does a half-wave rectifier voltage for the same load resistance and capacitor values because:", "opta": "there is a shorter time between peaks", "optb": "there is a longer time between peaks", "optc": "the larger the ripple, the better the filtering action", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Testing a good diode with an ohmmeter should indicate", "opta": "high resistance when forward or reverse biased", "optb": "low resistance when forward or reverse biased", "optc": "high resistance when reverse biased and low resistance when forward biased", "optd": "high resistance when forward biased and low resistance when reverse biased", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The peak inverse voltage (PIV) across a nonconducting diode in a bridge rectifier equals approximately:", "opta": "half the peak secondary voltage", "optb": "twice the peak secondary voltage", "optc": "the peak value of the secondary voltage", "optd": "four times the peak value of the secondary voltage", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the current through the diode?", "opta": "1 mA", "optb": "0.975 mA", "optc": "0.942 mA", "optd": "0.0 mA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Electrons in the outermost orbit or shell of an atom are called", "opta": "free electrons", "optb": "negative ions", "optc": "valence electrons", "optd": "conduction band electrons", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Shunting the ac component away from the load is the task of a:", "opta": "transformer", "optb": "filter", "optc": "regulator", "optd": "rectifier", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A pn junction allows current flow when", "opta": "the p-type material is more positive than the n-type material", "optb": "the n-type material is more positive than the p-type material", "optc": "both the n-type and p-type materials have the same potential", "optd": "there is no potential on the n-type or p-type materials", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the current through the zener diode?", "opta": "0 mA", "optb": "7 mA", "optc": "8.3 mA", "optd": "13 mA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a diode is forward biased, the voltage across it", "opta": "is directly proportional to the current", "optb": "is inversely proportional to the current", "optc": "is directly proportional to the source voltage", "optd": "remains approximately the same", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why is heat produced in a diode?", "opta": "due to current passing through the diode", "optb": "due to voltage across the diode", "optc": "due to the power rating of the diode", "optd": "due to the PN junction of the diode", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The arrow in the schematic symbol of a diode points to", "opta": "the n-type material, which is called the anode", "optb": "the n-type material, which is called the cathode", "optc": "the p-type material, which is called the anode", "optd": "the p-type material, which is called the cathode", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The diode schematic arrow points to the:", "opta": "trivalent-doped material", "optb": "positive axial lead", "optc": "anode lead", "optd": "cathode lead", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When checking a diode, low resistance readings both ways indicate the diode is:", "opta": "open", "optb": "satisfactory", "optc": "faulty", "optd": "not the problem", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a diode schematic, the anode is represented by a(n):", "opta": "triangle", "optb": "vertical line", "optc": "zig-zag line", "optd": "element indicator", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An IC regulator receives an overload; it will:", "opta": "shut down", "optb": "compensate for heat", "optc": "provide more voltage", "optd": "sample and adjust", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With full-wave rectification, current through the load resistor must be:", "opta": "in opposite directions", "optb": "to the external load", "optc": "from the reverse biased diode", "optd": "in the same direction", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A characteristic curve is the result of a current versus voltage plot of diode activity, which begins at the:", "opta": "3rd quadrant", "optb": "current plot", "optc": "graph origin", "optd": "voltage plot", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Rectifier output polarity depends upon:", "opta": "cycles of input", "optb": "capacitor polarity", "optc": "half or full wave", "optd": "diode installation", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a 12 V supply, a silicon diode, and a 370-ohm resistor in series, what voltage will be dropped across the diode?", "opta": "0.3 V", "optb": "0.7 V", "optc": "0.9 V", "optd": "1.4 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the frequency of the applied ac signal to a half-wave rectifier is 60 Hz, the frequency of the pulsating dc output will be", "opta": "30 pps", "optb": "60 pps", "optc": "90 pps", "optd": "120 pps", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the peak output voltage for this half-wave rectifier?", "opta": "1 V", "optb": "7.8 V", "optc": "10.9 V", "optd": "15.6 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Thermal shutdown occurs in an IC regulator if:", "opta": "power dissipation is too high", "optb": "internal temperature is too high", "optc": "current through the device is too high", "optd": "load resistance increases", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The conduction band is closest to the valence band in", "opta": "semiconductors", "optb": "conductors", "optc": "insulators", "optd": "The distance is the same for all of the above.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the percent of regulation if Vnl = 20 V and Vfl = 19.8 V?", "opta": "0%", "optb": "1%", "optc": ".1%", "optd": "5%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a half-wave rectified voltage across the load resistor, load current flows for what part of a cycle?", "opta": "0 degrees", "optb": "90 degrees", "optc": "180 degrees", "optd": "360 degrees", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following circuits would require the least amount of filtering?", "opta": "A half-wave rectifier", "optb": "A full-wave rectifier", "optc": "A bridge rectifier", "optd": "A full-wave rectifier and a bridge rectifier", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is wrong with this circuit?", "opta": "The zener is open.", "optb": "The zener is shorted.", "optc": "nothing", "optd": "not enough data", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The voltage where current may start to flow in a reverse-biased pn junction is called the", "opta": "breakdown voltage", "optb": "barrier potential", "optc": "forward voltage", "optd": "biasing voltage", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Providing a constant output regardless of ac input or load resistance changes is the function of a:", "opta": "transformer", "optb": "filter", "optc": "regulator", "optd": "rectifier", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a diode is destroyed it has infinite impedance. When damaged by heat it will probably:", "opta": "short", "optb": "conduct more", "optc": "conduct less", "optd": "open", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The area at the junction of p-type and n-type materials that has lost its majority carriers is called the", "opta": "barrier potential", "optb": "depletion region", "optc": "n region", "optd": "p region", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DC power should be connected to forward bias a diode as follows:", "opta": "\u2013 anode, + cathode", "optb": "\u2013 cathode, \u2013 anode", "optc": "+ anode, \u2013 cathode", "optd": "+ cathode, + anode", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "At any given time in an intrinsic piece of semiconductor material at room temperature", "opta": "electrons drift randomly", "optb": "recombination occurs", "optc": "holes are created", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a power supply diagram, which block indicates a pulsating dc output?", "opta": "transformer", "optb": "filter", "optc": "rectifier", "optd": "regulator", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "List three diode packages:", "opta": "clip package, DIP, small current package", "optb": "DIP, small current package, large current package", "optc": "small current package, large current package, and SIP", "optd": "small current package, large current package, clip package", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The mimicking of an open/closed switch by a diode allows alternating current to be:", "opta": "rectified", "optb": "regulated", "optc": "controlled", "optd": "attenuated", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Junction Field Effect Transistors (JFET) contain how many diodes?", "opta": "4", "optb": "3", "optc": "2", "optd": "1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When an input delta of 2 V produces a transconductance of 1.5 mS, what is the drain current delta?", "opta": "666 mA", "optb": "3 mA", "optc": "0.75 mA", "optd": "0.5 mA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When not in use, MOSFET pins are kept at the same potential through the use of:", "opta": "shipping foil", "optb": "nonconductive foam", "optc": "conductive foam", "optd": "a wrist strap", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "D-MOSFETs are sometimes used in series to construct a cascode high-frequency amplifier to overcome the loss of:", "opta": "low output impedance", "optb": "capacitive reactance", "optc": "high input impedance", "optd": "inductive reactance", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A \"U\" shaped, opposite-polarity material built near a JFET-channel center is called the:", "opta": "gate", "optb": "block", "optc": "drain", "optd": "heat sink", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When testing an n-channel D-MOSFET, resistance G to D = , resistance G to S = , resistance D to SS =  and 500 , depending on the polarity of the ohmmeter, and resistance D to S = 500 . What is wrong?", "opta": "short D to S", "optb": "open G to D", "optc": "open D to SS", "optd": "nothing", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the constant-current region, how will the IDS change in an n-channel JFET?", "opta": "As VGS decreases ID decreases.", "optb": "As VGS increases ID increases.", "optc": "As VGS decreases ID remains constant.", "optd": "As VGS increases ID remains constant.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A MOSFET has how many terminals?", "opta": "2 or 3", "optb": "3", "optc": "4", "optd": "3 or 4", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "IDSS can be defined as:", "opta": "the minimum possible drain current", "optb": "the maximum possible current with VGS held at \u20134 V", "optc": "the maximum possible current with VGS held at 0 V", "optd": "the maximum drain current with the source shorted", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the input impedance of a common-gate configured JFET?", "opta": "very low", "optb": "low", "optc": "high", "optd": "very high", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "JFET terminal \"legs\" are connections to the drain, the gate, and the:", "opta": "channel", "optb": "source", "optc": "substrate", "optd": "cathode", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A very simple bias for a D-MOSFET is called:", "opta": "self biasing", "optb": "gate biasing", "optc": "zero biasing", "optd": "voltage-divider biasing", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With the E-MOSFET, when gate input voltage is zero, drain current is:", "opta": "at saturation", "optb": "zero", "optc": "IDSS", "optd": "widening the channel", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a 30-volt VDD, and an 8-kilohm drain resistor, what is the E-MOSFET Q point voltage, with ID = 3 mA?", "opta": "6 V", "optb": "10 V", "optc": "24 V", "optd": "30 V", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When an input signal reduces the channel size, the process is called:", "opta": "enhancement", "optb": "substrate connecting", "optc": "gate charge", "optd": "depletion", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which JFET configuration would connect a high-resistance signal source to a low-resistance load?", "opta": "source follower", "optb": "common-source", "optc": "common-drain", "optd": "common-gate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How will electrons flow through a p-channel JFET?", "opta": "from source to drain", "optb": "from source to gate", "optc": "from drain to gate", "optd": "from drain to source", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When VGS = 0 V, a JFET is:", "opta": "saturated", "optb": "an analog device", "optc": "an open switch", "optd": "cut off", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When applied input voltage varies the resistance of a channel, the result is called:", "opta": "saturization", "optb": "polarization", "optc": "cutoff", "optd": "field effect", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When is a vertical channel E-MOSFET used?", "opta": "for high frequencies", "optb": "for high voltages", "optc": "for high currents", "optd": "for high resistances", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When the JFET is no longer able to control the current, this point is called the:", "opta": "breakdown region", "optb": "depletion region", "optc": "saturation point", "optd": "pinch-off region", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a JFET, a ratio of output current change against an input voltage change is called:", "opta": "transconductance", "optb": "siemens", "optc": "resistivity", "optd": "gain", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of JFET bias requires a negative supply voltage?", "opta": "feedback", "optb": "source", "optc": "gate", "optd": "voltage divider", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How will a D-MOSFET input impedance change with signal frequency?", "opta": "As frequency increases input impedance increases.", "optb": "As frequency increases input impedance is constant.", "optc": "As frequency decreases input impedance increases.", "optd": "As frequency decreases input impedance is constant.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The type of bias most often used with E-MOSFET circuits is:", "opta": "constant current", "optb": "drain-feedback", "optc": "voltage-divider", "optd": "zero biasing", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The transconductance curve of a JFET is a graph of:", "opta": "IS versus VDS", "optb": "IC versus VCE", "optc": "ID versus VGS", "optd": "ID \u00d7 RDS", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The common-source JFET amplifier has:", "opta": "a very high input impedance and a relatively low voltage gain", "optb": "a high input impedance and a very high voltage gain", "optc": "a high input impedance and a voltage gain less than 1", "optd": "no voltage gain", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Using voltage-divider biasing, what is the voltage at the gate VGS?", "opta": "5.2 V", "optb": "4.2 V", "optc": "3.2 V", "optd": "2.2 V", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The overall input capacitance of a dual-gate D-MOSFET is lower because the devices are usually connected:", "opta": "in parallel", "optb": "with separate insulation", "optc": "with separate inputs", "optd": "in series", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the transconductance of an FET when ID = 1 mA and VGS = 1 V?", "opta": "1 kS", "optb": "1 mS", "optc": "1 k", "optd": "1 m", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which component is considered to be an \"OFF\" device?", "opta": "transistor", "optb": "JFET", "optc": "D-MOSFET", "optd": "E-MOSFET", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an n-channel JFET, what will happen at the pinch-off voltage?", "opta": "the value of VDS at which further increases in VDS will cause no further increase in ID", "optb": "the value of VGS at which further decreases in VGS will cause no further increases in ID", "optc": "the value of VDG at which further decreases in VDG will cause no further increases in ID", "optd": "the value of VDS at which further increases in VGS will cause no further increases in ID", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct for a gated D-type flip-flop?", "opta": "The Q output is either SET or RESET as soon as the D input goes HIGH or LOW.", "optb": "The output complement follows the input when enabled.", "optc": "Only one of the inputs can be HIGH at a time.", "optd": "The output toggles if one of the inputs is held HIGH.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When both inputs of a J-K flip-flop cycle, the output will:", "opta": "be invalid", "optb": "not change", "optc": "change", "optd": "toggle", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Latches constructed with NOR and NAND gates tend to remain in the latched condition due to which configuration feature?", "opta": "asynchronous operation", "optb": "low input voltages", "optc": "gate impedance", "optd": "cross coupling", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 555 timer can be used in which of the following configurations?", "opta": "astable, monostable", "optb": "monostable, bistable", "optc": "astable, toggled", "optd": "bistable, tristable", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A basic S-R flip-flop can be constructed by cross-coupling which basic logic gates?", "opta": "AND or OR gates", "optb": "XOR or XNOR gates", "optc": "NOR or NAND gates", "optd": "AND or NOR gates", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One example of the use of an S-R flip-flop is as a(n):", "opta": "transition pulse generator", "optb": "astable oscillator", "optc": "racer", "optd": "switch debouncer", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If both inputs of an S-R NAND latch are LOW, what will happen to the output?", "opta": "The output would become unpredictable.", "optb": "The output will toggle.", "optc": "The output will reset.", "optd": "No change will occur in the output.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The equation for the output frequency of a 555 timer operating in the astable mode is: . What value of C1 will be required if R1 = 1 k, R2 = 1 k, and f = 1 kHz?", "opta": "0.33 F", "optb": "0.48 F", "optc": "480 F", "optd": "33 nF", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An astable multivibrator is a circuit that:", "opta": "has two stable states", "optb": "is free-running", "optc": "produces a continuous output signal", "optd": "is free-running and produces a continuous output signal", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is another name for a one-shot?", "opta": "monostable", "optb": "bistable", "optc": "astable", "optd": "tristable", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The truth table for an S-R flip-flop has how many VALID entries?", "opta": "3", "optb": "1", "optc": "4", "optd": "2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the significance of the J and K terminals on the J-K flip-flop?", "opta": "There is no known significance in their designations.", "optb": "The J represents \"jump,\" which is how the Q output reacts whenever the clock goes HIGH and the J input is also HIGH.", "optc": "The letters represent the initials of Johnson and King, the co-inventors of the J-K flip-flop.", "optd": "All of the other letters of the alphabet are already in use.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following describes the operation of a positive edge-triggered D-type flip-flop?", "opta": "If both inputs are HIGH, the output will toggle.", "optb": "The output will follow the input on the leading edge of the clock.", "optc": "When both inputs are LOW, an invalid state exists.", "optd": "The input is toggled into the flip-flop on the leading edge of the clock and is passed to the output on the trailing edge of the clock.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is one disadvantage of an S-R flip-flop?", "opta": "It has no Enable input.", "optb": "It has a RACE condition.", "optc": "It has no clock input.", "optd": "It has only a single output.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Electricity may be generated by a wire:", "opta": "carrying current", "optb": "wrapped as a coil", "optc": "that has neutral domains", "optd": "passing through a flux field", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the given circuit, what will the voltage be across R3 25 s after the switch is moved to position 2?", "opta": "2.88 V", "optb": "5.9 V", "optc": "8.34 V", "optd": "14 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The electrical energy consumed by a coil is stored in the form of:", "opta": "an electrical field", "optb": "a force field", "optc": "an electrostatic field", "optd": "a magnetic field", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is magnetic flux?", "opta": "the number of lines of force in webers", "optb": "the number of lines of force in maxwells", "optc": "the number of lines of force in teslas", "optd": "the number of lines of force in flux density", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As current travels within a conductor:", "opta": "the magnetic field aids the current", "optb": "a magnetic field is developed around it", "optc": "the wire tries to point north", "optd": "an electrostatic field opposes the current", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of device consists of a coil with a moveable iron core?", "opta": "solenoid", "optb": "reed switch", "optc": "relay", "optd": "armature", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is hysteresis?", "opta": "lead between cause and effect", "optb": "lag between cause and effect", "optc": "lead between voltage and current", "optd": "lag between voltage and current", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a purely inductive circuit,", "opta": "current leads voltage by 90\u00b0", "optb": "voltage lags current by 90\u00b0", "optc": "voltage leads current by 90\u00b0", "optd": "voltage and current are in phase (0\u00b0)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A series RL filter circuit with an output across the inductor will result in what type of filtering?", "opta": "passing of the higher frequencies", "optb": "passing of the lower frequencies", "optc": "blocking of the higher frequencies", "optd": "blocking of a certain range of frequencies", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total inductance in the given circuit?", "opta": "160 mH", "optb": "300 mH", "optc": "900 mH", "optd": "1700 mH", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "On a schematic, dashed lines between two vertical coils usually mean the transformer has:", "opta": "an air core", "optb": "an iron core", "optc": "a nonmetallic core", "optd": "a ferrite core", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Faraday's law states that the:", "opta": "direction of the induced voltage produces an opposition", "optb": "direction of an induced current produces an aiding effect", "optc": "emf depends on the rate of cutting flux", "optd": "emf is related to the direction of the current", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A henry value divided by a circuit resistive value provides the:", "opta": "counter emf value", "optb": "induced voltage amplitude", "optc": "rise or decay time constant", "optd": "quality factor of the coil", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does Faraday's law concern?", "opta": "a magnetic field in a coil", "optb": "a magnetic field cutting a conductor", "optc": "a magnetic field hystersis", "optd": "a magnetic field in a conductor", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The polarity of induced voltage while a field is collapsing is:", "opta": "independent of the force creating it", "optb": "opposite to the force creating it", "optc": "identical to the force creating the field", "optd": "present only if the force is stationary", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the permeability of transformer iron?", "opta": "50", "optb": "450", "optc": "1,500", "optd": "5,500", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Electromagnetism is the:", "opta": "magnetic field caused by a permanent magnet", "optb": "action between a permanent and an artificial magnet", "optc": "magnetic field action with a current-carrying wire", "optd": "current in the coil", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A magnetic field has:", "opta": "polar fields", "optb": "lines of force", "optc": "magnetomotive force", "optd": "lines of reluctance", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which two values are plotted on a B-H curve graph?", "opta": "reluctance and flux density", "optb": "permeability and reluctance", "optc": "magnetizing force and permeability", "optd": "flux density and magnetizing force", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the number of turns required in the secondary winding for a transformer when 120 volts is applied to a 2400-turn primary to produce 7.5 Vac at the secondary?", "opta": "75 turns", "optb": "150 turns", "optc": "900 turns", "optd": "1920 turns", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The four factors determining inductance are the number of turns, coil length, coil area, and:", "opta": "permeability", "optb": "reluctance", "optc": "counter emf", "optd": "coefficient of coupling", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the inductive reactance if the Q of a coil is 60, and the winding resistance is 5 ?", "opta": "0.083", "optb": "12", "optc": "30", "optd": "300", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The time difference, or lag, between flux density and magnetizing force is known as:", "opta": "eddy current", "optb": "magnetic saturation", "optc": "hysteresis", "optd": "coercivity", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A magnetic circuit breaker will open to protect equipment only when:", "opta": "voltage is exceeded", "optb": "an open is in the equipment", "optc": "the equipment is operating properly", "optd": "current is exceeded", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Electromagnetic induction is the generation of:", "opta": "electricity from magnetism", "optb": "electricity from electricity", "optc": "magnetism from electricity", "optd": "magnetism from magnetism", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Inductance is:", "opta": "directly proportional to the length of the coil", "optb": "directly proportional to the number of turns on the coil", "optc": "inversely proportional to the cross-sectional area of the coil", "optd": "inversely proportional to the permeability", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Current will cause a magnetic field in a conductor as follows:", "opta": "An ac current causes a fixed polarity magnetic field.", "optb": "A dc current causes a fixed polarity magnetic field.", "optc": "A dc current causes an alternating magnetic field.", "optd": "An ac current causes a fixed polarity magnetic field and a dc current causes an alternating magnetic field.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total inductance, assuming no mutual inductance?", "opta": "12 mH", "optb": "6 mH", "optc": "0.73 mH", "optd": "0 mH", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During a current change, the ability of a conductor to produce counter emf within itself is called:", "opta": "back emf", "optb": "self-induction", "optc": "a henry", "optd": "impedance", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the switch is moved to position 1 in the given circuit, how long will it take for the current to reach its maximum value?", "opta": "72.5 s", "optb": "532 s", "optc": "610 s", "optd": "833 s", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a transformer secondary lead has been connected to a middle loop that is not an end connector, it is called a:", "opta": "multiple-tapped secondary", "optb": "center-tapped secondary", "optc": "multiple winding secondary", "optd": "single winding secondary", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 24 V peak source is connected across a 900 H inductor. If the frequency of the source is 22 kHz, what is the reactive power?", "opta": "2.3 VAR", "optb": "4.6 VAR", "optc": "9.3 VAR", "optd": "0 VAR", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the permeability of machine steel?", "opta": "1.1 x 10\u22124", "optb": "5.65 x 10\u22124", "optc": "6.9 x 10\u22123", "optd": "8.8 x 10\u22123", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What will happen when an inductor's magnetic field collapses?", "opta": "Current will double.", "optb": "Voltage will be induced.", "optc": "A new field will expand.", "optd": "Counter emf will be high.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a square wave input, an RL differentiator circuit with an output across the inductor will produce what type of waveform?", "opta": "dc", "optb": "short time-duration pulses", "optc": "exponential-shaped pulses", "optd": "only a phase shift", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How long until the current is at a maximum?", "opta": "0 s", "optb": "5 s", "optc": "15 s", "optd": "25 s", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Find VR and VL.", "opta": "VR = 41.6 V, VL = 78.4 V", "optb": "VR = 48 V, VL = 110 V", "optc": "VR = 56 V, VL = 106 V", "optd": "VR = 60 V, VL = 60 V", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If 360 Vac is the output of a 300-turn secondary winding, what is the input voltage when the primary winding has 150 turns?", "opta": "2.4 Vac", "optb": "150 Vac", "optc": "180 Vac", "optd": "720 Vac", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a magnet enters a coil and a voltage is induced, the process is known as:", "opta": "an alternation", "optb": "self-inductance", "optc": "counter emf", "optd": "flux linkage", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What term is used to describe the action of magnetic flux from one circuit that cuts across the conductors of another circuit?", "opta": "self-inductance", "optb": "rectification", "optc": "mutual inductance", "optd": "magnetism", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Reactance in an inductive circuit will:", "opta": "increase with frequency", "optb": "decrease with frequency", "optc": "be independent from frequency", "optd": "depend on the value of XC", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A turns ratio of 5 for a transformer implies:", "opta": "more primary turns than secondary turns", "optb": "more secondary current than primary current", "optc": "larger source impedance than load impedance", "optd": "more secondary turns than primary turns", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A practical inductor", "opta": "has inductance", "optb": "has winding resistance", "optc": "has winding capacitance", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When current in an inductor starts to change, it cannot react instantly due to:", "opta": "fixed coil resistance", "optb": "eddy current generation", "optc": "applied emf of the circuit", "optd": "the counter emf of the coil", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the approximate time for a complete decay of 400 mA of inductor current, when R = 10 ohms and L = 20 H?", "opta": "10 seconds", "optb": "8 seconds", "optc": "4 seconds", "optd": "2 seconds", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A utility pole transformer used to supply a residential customer with two phases uses:", "opta": "two phases on the primary", "optb": "a center tap on the secondary", "optc": "a separate ground for each phase", "optd": "a small coefficient of coupling", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the inductive reactance?", "opta": "5.2", "optb": "7.5", "optc": "1.3 k", "optd": "7.5 k", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a coil collapses the induced circuit current will:", "opta": "be in the same direction", "optb": "go to zero", "optc": "aid counter emf buildup", "optd": "be in the opposite direction", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a rate of one ampere per second causes an induced voltage of one volt, the unit of measure is", "opta": "a lenz", "optb": "an ohm", "optc": "a farad", "optd": "a henry", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If you wanted to decrease the inductance of a coil, you might increase the:", "opta": "number of turns", "optb": "permeability of the core", "optc": "spacing between turns", "optd": "area of the coil", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output phase for a transformer is:", "opta": "in phase with the input", "optb": "out of phase with the input", "optc": "dependent on the direction of the primary and secondary windings", "optd": "dependent on the frequency of the primary source", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Opposition to current flow without the dissipation of energy is called:", "opta": "resistance", "optb": "inductive reactance", "optc": "counter emf", "optd": "impedance", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With 100 Vac applied to the primary of a transformer so that it draws 500 mA, what will be the 300 Vac secondary current?", "opta": "1500 mA", "optb": "200 mA", "optc": "167 mA", "optd": "150 mA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which coil would be used as a step-up transformer primary if coil number 1 has 100 more turns than coil number 2?", "opta": "The coil windings must be the same.", "optb": "coil 1", "optc": "The coil ratio is too small.", "optd": "coil 2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Find IR and IL.", "opta": "IR = 50 mA, IL = 109 mA", "optb": "IR = 150 mA, IL = 9 mA", "optc": "IR = 50 mA, IL = 151 mA", "optd": "IR = 150 mA, IL = 53 mA", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When the transformer secondary is not loaded:", "opta": "secondary voltage increases", "optb": "no secondary current flows", "optc": "no secondary voltage is present", "optd": "secondary current increases", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the current rise after 2 time constants if Vs = 12 V dc, R = 60 , and the inductor is rated at 24 mH?", "opta": "79.9 mA", "optb": "126.4 mA", "optc": "173.0 mA", "optd": "198.6 mA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total inductance of a 5 H and a 100 mH coil connected in parallel?", "opta": "4.76 mH", "optb": "33.3 mH", "optc": "98.0 mH", "optd": "150.0 mH", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A transformer is used:", "opta": "to couple electric energy from one dc circuit to another", "optb": "to couple electric energy from an ac circuit to a dc circuit", "optc": "to couple electric energy from a dc circuit to an ac circuit", "optd": "to couple electric energy from one ac circuit to another", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the three major types of fixed inductor?", "opta": "air core", "optb": "ferrite core", "optc": "magnesium core", "optd": "iron core", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the impedance of a 1 kHz series RL circuit when R and XL are both 1000 ohms?", "opta": "500 ohms", "optb": "1000 ohms", "optc": "1414 ohms", "optd": "2000 ohms", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is remanence?", "opta": "reactance", "optb": "reluctance", "optc": "retentitivity", "optd": "resistance", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When an electromagnet reaches maximum strength, it is considered to be:", "opta": "in field condition", "optb": "at saturation", "optc": "inhibited", "optd": "at field strength", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "You could decrease the time constant of an RL circuit by", "opta": "adding a resistor in parallel with the circuit resistance", "optb": "adding an inductor in series with the circuit inductance", "optc": "decreasing the amplitude of the input voltage", "optd": "exchanging the position of the resistor and inductor in the circuit", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Indication of transformer primary and secondary voltage relationships is accomplished by:", "opta": "color-coded wires", "optb": "dot notation", "optc": "black, rather than gray, casings", "optd": "winding ratios", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As a generator armature passes the 270 degree point, the induced voltage is:", "opta": "at maximum negative", "optb": "between maximum negative and zero", "optc": "at maximum positive", "optd": "between zero and maximum positive", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A value of \"ten to the eighth power magnetic lines of force\" is for the term:", "opta": "field", "optb": "flux", "optc": "coulomb", "optd": "weber", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A change of one ampere per second in an inductor that induces a voltage of one volt is considered as which unit value?", "opta": "a lenz", "optb": "an ohm", "optc": "a farad", "optd": "a henry", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the name of the part inside a relay that is moved by the action of the electromagnet?", "opta": "armature", "optb": "conductor", "optc": "contacts", "optd": "solenoid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the primary of a 4:1 turns transformer dissipates 5 W, what is the secondary power?", "opta": "5.0 W", "optb": "1.25 pW", "optc": "9.5 W", "optd": "20.0 mW", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The unit of flux density is:", "opta": "magnetomotive force", "optb": "a weber", "optc": "a maxwell", "optd": "a tesla", "ans": "D", "explanation": "tesla or weber/m2 is the unit of flux density"}, {"question": "When used as a filter, an inductor is", "opta": "placed in series with the load and aids any current changes", "optb": "placed in parallel with the load and aids any current changes", "optc": "placed in parallel with the load and opposes any current changes", "optd": "placed in series with the load and opposes any current changes", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A loaded transformer will achieve mutual induction when:", "opta": "secondary current increase causes a primary current decrease", "optb": "primary current is increased by an increase in secondary current", "optc": "primary current is decreased by an increase in secondary current", "optd": "secondary current decrease causes a primary current increase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which transformer turns ratio is needed to match two 16-ohm parallel devices to an output of 22.2 ohms?", "opta": "1.38:1", "optb": "1.67:1", "optc": "0.72:1", "optd": "0.60:1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A transformer will have:", "opta": "primary and secondary windings", "optb": "primary and secondary current", "optc": "primary wattage producing secondary current", "optd": "different frequencies for the primary and secondary", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the phase angle of a 24 Vac parallel RL circuit when R = 45 ohms and XL = 1100 ohms?", "opta": "0.001 degrees", "optb": "2.300 degrees", "optc": "87.600 degrees", "optd": "89.900 degrees", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A winding of wire can be called", "opta": "an inductor", "optb": "a coil", "optc": "a choke", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What happens when moving expanding lines of force encounter a conductor?", "opta": "Current increases.", "optb": "Voltage is induced.", "optc": "Resistance is reduced.", "optd": "Power is increased.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fixed transformers have:", "opta": "a center-tapped secondary", "optb": "multiple windings", "optc": "turns ratios that cannot be changed", "optd": "a multiple-tapped secondary", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a B-H curve, magnetizing force is equal to:", "opta": "", "optb": "H = I \u00d7 N", "optc": "ampere-turns per weber", "optd": "webers per square meter", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following represents a true equivalent of an inductor?", "opta": "An inductance in series with a resistance and a capacitance", "optb": "A capacitance in parallel with the series combination of a resistance and an inductance", "optc": "An inductance in parallel with the series combination of a resistance and a capacitance", "optd": "The only quality a real inductor has is inductance.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a transformer, what will happen to the primary current if the secondary magnetic field increases?", "opta": "Ip will increase.", "optb": "Ip will be canceled.", "optc": "Ip will remain the same.", "optd": "Ip will decrease.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The time required for one weber of flux to cut a conductor and produce one volt is:", "opta": "one revolution", "optb": "one second", "optc": "one millisecond", "optd": "four revolutions", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the maximum source current for a transformer rated at 10 kVA, 1000/500 60 Hz?", "opta": "2 A", "optb": "5 A", "optc": "10 A", "optd": "20 A", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total inductance assuming no mutual inductance?", "opta": "0 mH", "optb": "0.69 mH", "optc": "12 mH", "optd": "24 mH", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A voltage is induced in a transformer secondary winding by the action of the:", "opta": "secondary magnetic field", "optb": "primary turns ratio", "optc": "primary magnetic field", "optd": "secondary counter emf", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is electromagnetism?", "opta": "the magnetic field generated around a conductor when a current passes through it", "optb": "the magnetic field generated in a conductor by an external voltage", "optc": "the voltage caused by a magnetic field in a conductor", "optd": "the current generated by an external magnetic field", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Counter emf or induced voltage is:", "opta": "inversely proportional to the change in current", "optb": "directly proportional to the change in time", "optc": "directly proportional to the inductance in henrys", "optd": "inversely proportional to the inductance in henrys", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the properties that determine the inductance of a coil?", "opta": "Length of wire, number of turns, type of core material, length of core", "optb": "Number of turns, type of wire, length of core, and cross-sectional area of core", "optc": "Type of core material, number of turns, cross-sectional area of core, and length of core", "optd": "Type of core material, type of wire, number of turns, and cross-sectional area of core", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An inductor is in series with a voltage source, an open switch, and a resistor. The instant the switch is closed, the inductor acts like", "opta": "a short", "optb": "an open", "optc": "a resistor", "optd": "a voltage source", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the phase angle between the source voltage and current, when a 100 mH inductor with a reactance of 6 k, and a 1 k resistor are in series with a source?", "opta": "0.1 degrees", "optb": "9.0 degrees", "optc": "61.0 degrees", "optd": "81.0 degrees", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a load is not connected to the secondary of a transformer:", "opta": "primary current is zero", "optb": "primary current is inversely proportional to primary impedance", "optc": "secondary voltage is zero", "optd": "secondary voltage is proportional to primary impedance", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which statement below best describes a Karnaugh map?", "opta": "It is simply a rearranged truth table.", "optb": "The Karnaugh map eliminates the need for using NAND and NOR gates.", "optc": "Variable complements can be eliminated by using Karnaugh maps.", "optd": "A Karnaugh map can be used to replace Boolean rules.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the examples below expresses the commutative law of multiplication?", "opta": "A + B = B + A", "optb": "A \u0095 B = B + A", "optc": "A \u0095 (B \u0095 C) = (A \u0095 B) \u0095 C", "optd": "A \u0095 B = B \u0095 A", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Boolean expression  is logically equivalent to what single gate?", "opta": "NAND", "optb": "NOR", "optc": "AND", "optd": "OR", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The observation that a bubbled input OR gate is interchangeable with a bubbled output AND gate is referred to as:", "opta": "a Karnaugh map", "optb": "DeMorgan's second theorem", "optc": "the commutative law of addition", "optd": "the associative law of multiplication", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The systematic reduction of logic circuits is accomplished by:", "opta": "symbolic reduction", "optb": "TTL logic", "optc": "using Boolean algebra", "optd": "using a truth table", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Logically, the output of a NOR gate would have the same Boolean expression as a(n):", "opta": "NAND gate immediately followed by an INVERTER", "optb": "OR gate immediately followed by an INVERTER", "optc": "AND gate immediately followed by an INVERTER", "optd": "NOR gate immediately followed by an INVERTER", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the examples below expresses the distributive law of Boolean algebra?", "opta": "A \u0095 (B \u0095 C) = (A \u0095 B) + C", "optb": "A + (B + C) = (A \u0095 B) + (A \u0095 C)", "optc": "A \u0095 (B + C) = (A \u0095 B) + (A \u0095 C)", "optd": "(A + B) + C = A + (B + C)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which output expression might indicate a product-of-sums circuit construction?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One of  DeMorgan's theorems states that . Simply stated, this means that logically there is no difference between:", "opta": "a NAND gate and an AND gate with a bubbled output", "optb": "a NOR gate and an AND gate with a bubbled output", "optc": "a NOR gate and a NAND gate with a bubbled output", "optd": "a NAND gate and an OR gate with a bubbled output", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The commutative law of addition and multiplication indicates that:", "opta": "the way we OR or AND two variables is unimportant because the result is the same", "optb": "we can group variables in an AND or in an OR any way we want", "optc": "an expression can be expanded by multiplying term by term just the same as in ordinary algebra", "optd": "the factoring of Boolean expressions requires the multiplication of product terms that contain like variables", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following expressions is in the sum-of-products (SOP) form?", "opta": "Y = (A + B)(C + D)", "optb": "Y = AB(CD)", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output will be a LOW for any case when one or more inputs are zero in a(n):", "opta": "OR gate", "optb": "NOT gate", "optc": "AND gate", "optd": "NAND gate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a signal passing through a gate is inhibited by sending a low into one of the inputs, and the output is HIGH, the gate is a(n):", "opta": "AND", "optb": "NAND", "optc": "NOR", "optd": "OR", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A single transistor can be used to build which of the following digital logic gates?", "opta": "AND gates", "optb": "OR gates", "optc": "NOT gates", "optd": "NAND gates", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The logic gate that will have HIGH or \"1\" at its output when any one of its inputs is HIGH is a(n):", "opta": "OR gate", "optb": "AND gate", "optc": "NOR gate", "optd": "NOT gate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many NAND circuits are contained in a 7400  NAND IC?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "8", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Exclusive-OR (XOR) logic gates can be constructed from what other logic gates?", "opta": "OR gates only", "optb": "AND gates and NOT gates", "optc": "AND gates, OR gates, and NOT gates", "optd": "OR gates and NOT gates", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many truth table entries are necessary for a four-input circuit?", "opta": "4", "optb": "8", "optc": "12", "optd": "16", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A NAND gate has:", "opta": "LOW inputs and a LOW output", "optb": "HIGH inputs and a HIGH output", "optc": "LOW inputs and a HIGH output", "optd": "None of the these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The basic logic gate whose output is the complement of the input is the:", "opta": "OR gate", "optb": "AND gate", "optc": "INVERTER gate", "optd": "comparator", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What input values will cause an AND logic gate to produce a HIGH output?", "opta": "At least one input is HIGH.", "optb": "At least one input is LOW.", "optc": "All inputs are HIGH.", "optd": "All inputs are LOW.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Permeability is the inverse equivalent of which electrical term?", "opta": "Voltage", "optb": "Current", "optc": "Resistance", "optd": "Conductance", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which electromagnetic device uses brushes and a commutator?", "opta": "A speaker", "optb": "A dc generator", "optc": "A relay", "optd": "A solenoid", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the flux density of a magnetic field whose flux is 3000 \u00b5Wb and cross-sectional area is 0.25 m2?", "opta": "12,000 T", "optb": "83,330 T", "optc": "0 T", "optd": "More information is needed in order to find flux density.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How much flux is there in a magnetic field when its flux density is 5000 T and its cross-sectional area is 300 mm2?", "opta": "16.67 mWb", "optb": "5.0 Wb", "optc": "3.0 mWb", "optd": "1.5 Wb", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the effects of moving a closed wire loop through a magnetic field?", "opta": "A voltage is induced in the wire.", "optb": "A current is induced in the wire.", "optc": "The polarity across the wire depends on the direction of motion.", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Hall effect", "opta": "is a phenomenon with no practical applications", "optb": "is used in various sensor applications", "optc": "can develop potentials of thousands of volts", "optd": "is the basis for solar cell operation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "\"Series\" and \"parallel\" as applied to dc motors refer to", "opta": "the connection of the motor and controller", "optb": "the connection of the field coil and armature windings", "optc": "the connection of the brush and commutator", "optd": "the connection of the motor batteries", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The component that produces power in an electromagnetic generator is called the", "opta": "armature", "optb": "field winding", "optc": "commutator", "optd": "brush", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the magnetomotive force in a 150-turn coil of wire with 2 A flowing through it?", "opta": "13.33 mAt", "optb": "300 At", "optc": "75 At", "optd": "152 At", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A Hall effect sensor", "opta": "exists only in theory", "optb": "is a noncontacting magnetic sensor", "optc": "can operate only a few times before failure", "optd": "produces very large voltages", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which two values are plotted on a B-H curve graph?", "opta": "Reluctance and flux density", "optb": "Permeability and reluctance", "optc": "Magnetizing force and permeability", "optd": "Flux density and magnetizing force", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which electromagnetic device has a flexible cone?", "opta": "A speaker", "optb": "A dc generator", "optc": "A relay", "optd": "A solenoid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the reluctance of a material that has a length of 0.045 m, a cross-sectional area of 0.015 m2, and a permeability of 2500 \u00b5Wb/At\u00b7m?", "opta": "833.33 \u00b5At/Wb", "optb": "0.27 At/Wb", "optc": "1200 At/Wb", "optd": "More information is needed in order to find the reluctance.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The unit of flux density is known as", "opta": "magnetomotive force", "optb": "a weber", "optc": "a maxwell", "optd": "a tesla", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do you call the characteristic of a magnetic material whereby a change in magnetization lags the application of a magnetizing force?", "opta": "Hysteresis", "optb": "Induction", "optc": "Retentivity", "optd": "Reluctance", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which electromagnetic device has a movable iron core called a plunger?", "opta": "A speaker", "optb": "A dc generator", "optc": "A relay", "optd": "A solenoid", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which electromagnetic device contains an armature?", "opta": "A speaker", "optb": "A dc generator", "optc": "A relay", "optd": "A solenoid", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The polarity of induced voltage while a field is collapsing is", "opta": "independent of the force creating the field", "optb": "opposite to the force creating the field", "optc": "identical to the force creating the field", "optd": "present only if the force is stationary", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What device is similar to an RTD but has a negative temperature coefficient?", "opta": "Strain gauge", "optb": "Thermistor", "optc": "Negative-type RTD", "optd": "Thermocouple", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The resistive change of a strain gauge", "opta": "is based on the weight placed upon it, but can be many thousands of ohms", "optb": "is usually no more than 100", "optc": "is based on the gauge factor, but is typically less than an ohm", "optd": "has a positive temperature coefficient", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The silicon-controlled rectifier can be turned off", "opta": "by a negative gate pulse", "optb": "by forced commutation", "optc": "with the off switch", "optd": "when the breakover voltage is exceeded", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output voltage of a typical thermocouple is", "opta": "less than 100 mV", "optb": "greater than 1 V", "optc": "Thermocouples vary resistance, not voltage.", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The connections to a thermocouple", "opta": "can produce an unwanted thermocouple effect, which must be compensated for", "optb": "produce an extra desirable thermocouple effect", "optc": "must be protected, since high voltages are present", "optd": "produce an extra desirable thermocouple effect and must be protected, since high voltages are present", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the zero-voltage switch used for?", "opta": "To reduce radiation of high frequencies during turn-on of a high current to a load", "optb": "To control low-voltage circuits", "optc": "To provide power to a circuit when power is lost", "optd": "For extremely low-voltage applications", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Temperature sensing can be achieved by the use of", "opta": "thermocouples", "optb": "RTDs", "optc": "thermistors", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The purpose of compensation for a thermocouple is", "opta": "to decrease temperature sensitivity", "optb": "to increase voltage output", "optc": "to cancel unwanted voltage output of a thermocouple", "optd": "used for high-temperature circuits", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The change in value of an analog signal during the conversion process produces what is called the", "opta": "quantization error", "optb": "resolution error", "optc": "Nyquist error", "optd": "sampling error", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following performance specifications applies to a sample-and-hold circuit?", "opta": "Aperture time", "optb": "Aperture droop", "optc": "Feedback", "optd": "Acquisition jitter", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "RTDs are typically connected with other fixed resistors", "opta": "in a pi configuration", "optb": "in a bridge configuration", "optc": "and variable resistors", "optd": "and capacitors in a filter-type circuit", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Holding current for an SCR is best described as", "opta": "the minimum current required for turn-off", "optb": "the current required before an SCR will turn on", "optc": "the amount of current required to maintain conduction", "optd": "the gate current required to maintain conduction", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the moving part of a linear variable differential transformer?", "opta": "Primary", "optb": "Secondary", "optc": "Diaphragm", "optd": "Core", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Base 10 refers to which number system?", "opta": "binary coded decimal", "optb": "decimal", "optc": "octal", "optd": "hexadecimal", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the decimal number 151.75 to binary.", "opta": "10000111.11", "optb": "11010011.01", "optc": "00111100.00", "optd": "10010111.11", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the binary number 1011010 to hexadecimal.", "opta": "5B", "optb": "5F", "optc": "5A", "optd": "5C", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The number of bits used to store a BCD digit is:", "opta": "8", "optb": "4", "optc": "1", "optd": "2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sample-and-hold circuits in ADCs are designed to:", "opta": "sample and hold the output of the binary counter during the conversion process", "optb": "stabilize the ADCs threshold voltage during the conversion process", "optc": "stabilize the input analog signal during the conversion process", "optd": "sample and hold the ADC staircase waveform during the conversion process", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The weight of the LSB as a binary number is:", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between binary coding and binary coded decimal?", "opta": "Binary coding is pure binary.", "optb": "BCD is pure binary.", "optc": "Binary coding has a decimal format.", "optd": "BCD has no decimal format.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the binary number 1001.0010 to decimal.", "opta": "125", "optb": "12.5", "optc": "90.125", "optd": "9.125", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 110010012 (binary) to decimal.", "opta": "201", "optb": "2001", "optc": "20", "optd": "210", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the decimal value of the hexadecimal number 777?", "opta": "191", "optb": "1911", "optc": "19", "optd": "19111", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the resultant binary of the decimal problem 49 + 1 = ?", "opta": "01010101", "optb": "00110101", "optc": "00110010", "optd": "00110001", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "3428 is the decimal value for which of the following binary coded decimal (BCD) groupings?", "opta": "11010001001000", "optb": "11010000101000", "optc": "011010010000010", "optd": "110100001101010", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the result when a decimal 5238 is converted to base 16?", "opta": "327.375", "optb": "12166", "optc": "1388", "optd": "1476", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "\"Half-splitting\" is", "opta": "a means for nuclear fuel cells to produce electricity", "optb": "a means of isolating a problem in a circuit", "optc": "a means for reducing a high ac voltage to a low dc voltage", "optd": "a means of limiting current in a circuit", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If doubling the voltage across a resistor doubles the current through the resistor then", "opta": "the resistor value decreased", "optb": "the resistor value did not change", "optc": "the resistor value increased", "optd": "it is impossible to determine the change in the resistor value", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the voltage across a fixed value of resistance is increased five times, what does the current do?", "opta": "It increases by a factor of five.", "optb": "It decreases by a factor of five.", "optc": "It stays the same.", "optd": "Not enough information", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the resistance in a circuit with constant voltage increases, the current will", "opta": "increase", "optb": "decrease", "optc": "stay the same", "optd": "Not enough information", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the power in the given circuit?", "opta": "3.6 W", "optb": "35 W", "optc": "175 W", "optd": "245 W", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the kilowatt-hour consumption of a 40 W lamp if it remains on for 1750 h?", "opta": "43.75", "optb": "70", "optc": "43,750", "optd": "70,000", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(1,750 x 40)/1000 = 70 kilowatt-hour."}, {"question": "A damaged resistor", "opta": "may appear burned", "optb": "may have an increased resistance value", "optc": "may be checked with an ohmmeter", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Power supplies differ from batteries in that", "opta": "power supply output voltages are ac and not dc", "optb": "power supply voltages are not stable", "optc": "power supplies are low-current devices", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the resistor value in the given circuit?", "opta": "200", "optb": "1 k", "optc": "2 k", "optd": "4 k", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If voltage across a resistance doubles", "opta": "the current is halved", "optb": "the resistance doubles", "optc": "the current is unchanged", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the power in the given circuit?", "opta": "32 W", "optb": "80 W", "optc": "500 W", "optd": "16 kW", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ohm's law describes the mathematical relationship between", "opta": "ohms, kilohms, and megohms", "optb": "resistor size and resistor value", "optc": "resistance, voltage, and current", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Energy is defined as the ability to", "opta": "produce heat", "optb": "produce light", "optc": "produce sound", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What electromotive force would cause 20 A of current to flow through a 500  resistor?", "opta": "0.04 V", "optb": "2.5 V", "optc": "25.0 V", "optd": "10,000 V", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The rate at which work is performed is called", "opta": "current", "optb": "energy", "optc": "power", "optd": "voltage", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A battery's capacity to deliver power is measured in", "opta": "kWh", "optb": "Ah", "optc": "Wh", "optd": "Vh", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Power supplies are regulated to prevent the output voltage from changing due to changes in the", "opta": "line voltage", "optb": "supply load", "optc": "frequency", "optd": "both line voltage and supply load", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the power in the given circuit?", "opta": "3.92 kW", "optb": "280 W", "optc": "28.6 W", "optd": "9.8 W", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If current through a resistance is halved", "opta": "the resistance is halved", "optb": "the voltage is halved", "optc": "the voltage doubles", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ohm's law is a relationship between", "opta": "voltage, current, and time", "optb": "power, current, and resistance", "optc": "resistance, time, and current", "optd": "voltage, current, and resistance", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the voltage in the given circuit was cut in half, what would the current equal?", "opta": "10 mA", "optb": "30 mA", "optc": "60 mA", "optd": "90 mA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When parallel resistors are of three different values, which has the greatest power loss?", "opta": "The smallest resistance", "optb": "The largest resistance", "optc": "They have the same power loss.", "optd": "Voltage and resistance values are needed.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the product-over-sum result of 150 and 6800?", "opta": "150", "optb": "146.7", "optc": "0.006", "optd": "6800", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The voltage across any branch of a parallel circuit:", "opta": "varies as the total current varies", "optb": "is inversely proportional to total circuit resistance", "optc": "is equally applied to all branch conductances", "optd": "is dropped in proportion to each branch resistance", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total power loss if 2 k and 1 k parallel-connected resistors have an IT of 3 mA?", "opta": "6 W", "optb": "36 W", "optc": "6 mW", "optd": "36 mW", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What happens to total resistance in a circuit with parallel resistors if one of them opens?", "opta": "It increases.", "optb": "It halves.", "optc": "It remains the same.", "optd": "It decreases.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Components that connect in parallel form:", "opta": "branches", "optb": "open circuits", "optc": "short circuits", "optd": "a voltage divider", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A parallel circuit differs from a series circuit in that a parallel circuit has", "opta": "no path for current flow", "optb": "fewer paths for current flow", "optc": "one path for current flow", "optd": "more than one path for current flow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the given circuit, Channel 1 of the stereo amplifier outputs 12 V to the speakers. How much total current is the amplifier providing to the speakers?", "opta": "0 A", "optb": "1.5 A", "optc": "3 A", "optd": "More information is needed to find the total current provided to the speakers.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If two parallel-connected resistors dissipate 6 watts and 10 watts of power, then what is the total power loss?", "opta": "3.75 watts", "optb": "4 watts", "optc": "16 watts", "optd": "60 watts", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which component is shorted?", "opta": "R1", "optb": "R2", "optc": "R3", "optd": "R4", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What would these meter readings indicate about the circuit in the given circuit?Meter Readings: I = 7.6 mA, V = 12 V", "opta": "R1 is open.", "optb": "R2 is open.", "optc": "The fuse is open.", "optd": "The circuit is operating normally.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the given circuit, Channel 1 of the stereo amplifier outputs 12 V to the speakers. How much total power is the amplifier delivering to the speakers?", "opta": "0 W", "optb": "18 W", "optc": "36 W", "optd": "More information is needed to find the total power delivered to the speakers.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a 1 k and a 2 k resistor are parallel-connected across a 12 V supply, how much current is received by the 2 k resistor?", "opta": "4 mA", "optb": "6 mA", "optc": "8 mA", "optd": "12 mA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does VS equal in the given circuit?", "opta": "0 V", "optb": "9 V", "optc": "27 V", "optd": "More information is needed to find VS.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The current through R1 will be:", "opta": "128 mA", "optb": "88 mA", "optc": "48 mA", "optd": "2.2 mA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The voltage read by the voltmeter will be:", "opta": "24 V", "optb": "12 V", "optc": "6 V", "optd": "4 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which component is of the wrong value?", "opta": "R1", "optb": "R2", "optc": "R3", "optd": "R4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does I3 equal in the given circuit?", "opta": "5 mA", "optb": "45 mA", "optc": "50 mA", "optd": "100 mA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total power of the circuit?", "opta": "2.2 W", "optb": "4.2 W", "optc": "6.2 W", "optd": "8.2 W", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the individual values of two parallel resistors whose RT is 8 ohms, when one has double the resistance of the other?", "opta": "2.7 ohms and 5.3 ohms", "optb": "8 ohms and 16 ohms", "optc": "10 ohms and 20 ohms", "optd": "12 ohms and 24 ohms", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a parallel 5 k resistor and a 25 k resistor have a 10 V supply, what is the total power loss?", "opta": "2.4 mW", "optb": "3.3 mW", "optc": "24 mW", "optd": "33 mW", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a parallel resistive circuit:", "opta": "there is more than one current path between two points", "optb": "the voltage applied divides between the branches", "optc": "the total branch power exceeds the source power", "optd": "the total circuit conductance is less than the smallest branch conductance", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total resistance?", "opta": "7 k", "optb": "1 k", "optc": "706", "optd": "353", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Kirchhoff's current law for parallel circuits states that the:", "opta": "sum of all branch voltages equals zero", "optb": "total circuit resistance is less than the smallest branch resistor", "optc": "sum of currents into a junction is equal to the difference of all the branch currents", "optd": "sum of the total currents flowing out of a junction equals the sum of the total currents flowing into that junction", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which component is open?", "opta": "R1", "optb": "R2", "optc": "R3", "optd": "R4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What would these meter readings indicate about the circuit in the given circuit?Meter Readings: I = 0 mA, V = 0 V", "opta": "R1 is open.", "optb": "R2 is open.", "optc": "The fuse is open.", "optd": "The circuit is operating normally.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If 550 mA of current leaves a node that had 250 mA entering from one branch, how much current would enter from the other?", "opta": "250 mA", "optb": "300 mA", "optc": "550 mA", "optd": "800 mA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What would these meter readings indicate about the circuit in the given circuit?Meter Readings: I = 10 mA, V = 12 V", "opta": "R1 is open.", "optb": "R2 is open.", "optc": "The fuse is open.", "optd": "The circuit is operating normally.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does RT equal in the given circuit?", "opta": "90", "optb": "180", "optc": "200", "optd": "1.8 k", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What procedure should be followed when troubleshooting with an ammeter or voltmeter?", "opta": "Short the leads and adjust.", "optb": "Check the meter\u0092s external power supply.", "optc": "Start with the highest scale and adjust down to a lower scale.", "optd": "Start with the lowest scale and adjust up to a higher scale.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A parallel circuit is also used as a divider for:", "opta": "conductance", "optb": "voltage", "optc": "power", "optd": "current", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is RT for a 12 k, a 4 k, and a 3 k resistor in parallel?", "opta": "1.5 k", "optb": "2 k", "optc": "6.3 k", "optd": "19 k", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total resistance of four 1 k parallel-connected resistors?", "opta": "200 ohms", "optb": "250 ohms", "optc": "400 ohms", "optd": "4 kilohms", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which are the better test devices used to isolate a suspected open component within a parallel circuit?", "opta": "a voltmeter or an ohmmeter", "optb": "neither an ammeter nor a voltmeter", "optc": "a wattmeter or a voltmeter", "optd": "an ammeter or an ohmmeter", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does P2 equal in the given circuit?", "opta": "45 mW", "optb": "405 mW", "optc": "450 mW", "optd": "900 mW", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does R1 equal in the given circuit?", "opta": "90", "optb": "180", "optc": "200", "optd": "1.8 k", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total resistance?", "opta": "1.045 k", "optb": "1.545 k", "optc": "2.045 k", "optd": "2.545 k", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is RT for fifteen 2 M resistors all connected in parallel?", "opta": "133 k", "optb": "300 k", "optc": "750 k", "optd": "30 M", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is considered to be the common reference for a parallel circuit?", "opta": "Voltage", "optb": "Current", "optc": "Power", "optd": "Resistance", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of PLD should be used to program basic logic functions?", "opta": "PLA", "optb": "PAL", "optc": "CPLD", "optd": "SLD", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The content of a simple programmable logic device (PLD) consists of:", "opta": "fuse-link arrays", "optb": "thousands of basic logic gates", "optc": "advanced sequential logic functions", "optd": "thousands of basic logic gates and advanced sequential logic functions", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Once a PAL has been programmed:", "opta": "it cannot be reprogrammed.", "optb": "its outputs are only active HIGHs", "optc": "its outputs are only active LOWs", "optd": "its logic capacity is lost", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The complex programmable logic device (CPLD) contains several PLD blocks and:", "opta": "field-programmable switches", "optb": "AND/OR arrays", "optc": "a global interconnection matrix", "optd": "a language compiler", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "PLAs, CPLDs, and FPGAs are all which type of device?", "opta": "SLD", "optb": "PLD", "optc": "EPROM", "optd": "SRAM", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The difference between a PLA and a PAL is:", "opta": "the PLA has a programmable OR plane and a programmable AND plane, while the PAL only has a programmable AND plane", "optb": "the PAL has a programmable OR plane and a programmable AND plane, while the PLA only has a programmable AND plane", "optc": "the PAL has more possible product terms than the PLA", "optd": "PALs and PLAs are the same thing.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Derived units are obtained from various combinations of", "opta": "electrical quantities", "optb": "fundamental units", "optc": "metric prefixes", "optd": "international standards", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following metric prefixes could replace 10\u20139?", "opta": "Nano", "optb": "Mega", "optc": "Kilo", "optd": "Micro", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Scientific notation is a method", "opta": "of expressing a very large number", "optb": "of expressing a very small number", "optc": "used to make calculations with large and small numbers", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If you drop a 5 when rounding a number, you are using the", "opta": "round-to-even rule", "optb": "significant digit rule", "optc": "round-off rule", "optd": "retained digit rule", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "7200 mV is the same as", "opta": "7.2 V", "optb": "7.2 V", "optc": "7,200,000 V", "optd": "0.0072 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A measure of the repeatability of a measurement of some quantity is", "opta": "error", "optb": "precision", "optc": "accuracy", "optd": "significant", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Another name for \"fundamental units\" is", "opta": "base units", "optb": "atoms", "optc": "the metric system", "optd": "letter symbols", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Adding 27.5 \u00d7 103 to 8.9 \u00d7 104 equals", "opta": "36.4 \u00d7 107", "optb": "116.5 \u00d7 104", "optc": "28.39 \u00d7 103", "optd": "1.165 \u00d7 105", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When using the terms \"accuracy\" and \"precision\" for measurements", "opta": "\"precision\" implies less measurement error than \"accuracy\"", "optb": "\"accuracy\" implies less measurement error than \"precision\"", "optc": "\"precision\" measures the repeatability of a measurement", "optd": "both terms mean the same thing", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The difference between scientific and engineering notation is", "opta": "powers of ten representation", "optb": "single vs. multiple digits before decimal point", "optc": "groupings of multiples of three digits", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The number 14.8 can also be expressed as", "opta": "1.48 \u00d7 10\u20131", "optb": "1.48 \u00d7 100", "optc": "1.48 \u00d7 101", "optd": "1.48 \u00d7 102", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The digits in a measured number that are known to be correct are called", "opta": "accuracy digits", "optb": "significant digits", "optc": "error digits", "optd": "precision digits", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is expressed in engineering notation?", "opta": "470 \u00d7 105", "optb": "82 \u00d7 10\u20132", "optc": "9.1 \u00d7 10\u20136", "optd": "14.7 \u00d7 108", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The unit for frequency is the", "opta": "hertz", "optb": "ampere", "optc": "watt", "optd": "second", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Add 21 mA and 8000 A and express the result in milliamperes.", "opta": "21.8 mA", "optb": "218 mA", "optc": "29 mA", "optd": "290 mA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Dividing 24 \u00d7 1011 by 3 \u00d7 104 equals", "opta": "8 \u00d7 104", "optb": "8 \u00d7 107", "optc": "8 \u00d7 1011", "optd": "8 \u00d7 1015", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pico is what relation to micro?", "opta": "one-tenth", "optb": "one-hundredth", "optc": "one-thousandth", "optd": "one-millionth", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The resistivity of copper is:", "opta": "9.9", "optb": "10.7", "optc": "16.7", "optd": "17.0", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How do fixed resistors usually fail?", "opta": "slowly over time", "optb": "by increasing their value", "optc": "by becoming an open circuit", "optd": "by increasing their value and becoming an open circuit", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With Ohm's law, if voltage increases and resistance stays the same:", "opta": "current remains the same", "optb": "power decreases", "optc": "current increases", "optd": "resistance decreases", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which formula shows a direct proportionality between power and voltage?", "opta": "V = IR", "optb": "P = VI", "optc": "P = IR", "optd": "I = V/R", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With 1 mA of current, what wattage rating should a 470 ohm resistor have?", "opta": "1/4 watt", "optb": "1/2 watt", "optc": "1 watt", "optd": "2 watts", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is a 3.9 k resistor color-coded?", "opta": "red, white, red, gold", "optb": "red, green, orange, silver", "optc": "orange, white, red, gold", "optd": "orange, green, orange, silver", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What resistor type is found in SIPs and DIPs?", "opta": "metal film", "optb": "wirewound", "optc": "metal oxide", "optd": "thick film", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ohm's law is not:", "opta": "V = IR", "optb": "I = V/R", "optc": "R = IV", "optd": "R = V/I", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the two major categories for resistors?", "opta": "low and high ohmic value", "optb": "commercial and industrial", "optc": "low and high power value", "optd": "fixed and variable", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many connections does a potentiometer have?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "A potentiometer uses three connections, as opposed to a rheostat, which only employs two. Having three connections allows the potentiometer to vary voltage. Both the potentiometer and the rheostat are classified as variable resistors."}, {"question": "What current is flowing in the circuit?", "opta": "288 kA", "optb": "2 kA", "optc": "50 mA", "optd": "500 A", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The six basic forms of energy are:", "opta": "light, sun, magnetic, chemical, electrical, and mechanical", "optb": "electrical, mechanical, light, heat, magnetic, and chemical", "optc": "electrical, mechanical, sun, heat, chemical, and light", "optd": "potential, sun, light, chemical, electrical, and mechanical", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How much energy is stored if 6.24 x 1018 electrons are stored in 4 volts?", "opta": "4 joules", "optb": "1.56 x 1018 electrons", "optc": "1.56 coulombs", "optd": "2.496 x 1019 electrons", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With Ohm's law:", "opta": "current is inversely proportional to resistance", "optb": "resistance is directly proportional to voltage", "optc": "voltage is indirectly proportional to power", "optd": "current is directly proportional to resistance", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Power is defined as:", "opta": "the rate at which energy is used", "optb": "watts", "optc": "energy", "optd": "the rate at which energy is generated", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the most commonly used conductor in electronics?", "opta": "aluminum", "optb": "copper", "optc": "gold", "optd": "silver", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With Ohm's law, no change in resistance means that current and voltage will be:", "opta": "directly proportional", "optb": "unable to produce energy", "optc": "the same", "optd": "inversely proportional", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A potentiometer has how many leads?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the ratio of 13 to 47 expressed in percent?", "opta": "2.76%", "optb": "27.7%", "optc": "3.60%", "optd": "36.1%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What happens to current and resistance if the voltage doubles?", "opta": "Current doubles and resistance doubles.", "optb": "Current doubles and resistance is halved.", "optc": "Current remains the same and resistance doubles.", "optd": "Current doubles and resistance remains the same.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One problem with mechanically variable resistors is noticeable in audio circuits as:", "opta": "scratchy noise", "optb": "lack of bass response", "optc": "variable volume", "optd": "too much treble response", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A color code of orange, orange, orange is for what ohmic value?", "opta": "22 kilohms", "optb": "3300 ohms", "optc": "44000 ohms", "optd": "33 kilohms", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A conductor's cross-sectional area in circular mils for  inch is:", "opta": "500 cmils", "optb": "100,000 cmils", "optc": "1,000,000 cmils", "optd": "500,000,000 cmils", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a variable resistor's resistance varies in a nonuniform manner as the shaft is moved, it is considered to be:", "opta": "linear", "optb": "defective", "optc": "not wirewound", "optd": "tapered", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Power is measured in units of:", "opta": "joules x charge", "optb": "joules/work", "optc": "joules x voltage", "optd": "joules/time", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many basic types of resistors exist?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a complex circuit, a supply source senses:", "opta": "open circuit components", "optb": "when voltages need to be increased", "optc": "only a single resistive connection", "optd": "when complex currents are needed", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many ohms of resistance allows a current of 720 A to flow when 3.6 kV is applied?", "opta": "200 n", "optb": "5 k", "optc": "200 k", "optd": "5 M", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is the most important step utilized when measuring resistors?", "opta": "use the highest possible scale", "optb": "keep test leads short", "optc": "zero the meter before using", "optd": "remove power from the circuit", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Components designed to oppose the flow of current are called:", "opta": "insulators", "optb": "conductors", "optc": "resistors", "optd": "heat exchangers", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many amps are used by a 100 watt, 120 volt light bulb?", "opta": "1.2 amps", "optb": "12000 amps", "optc": "830 mA", "optd": "12 amps", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The source is 24 volts and the load resistance is 100 . What is the load current?", "opta": "2.4 A", "optb": "240 mA", "optc": "24 mA", "optd": "2.4 mA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Resistors are identified as to wattage by:", "opta": "size", "optb": "color code", "optc": "types of materials", "optd": "internal construction", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of resistors have a tolerance rating of 5% or greater?", "opta": "precision", "optb": "SIP", "optc": "general-purpose", "optd": "wirewound", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Resistor tolerance is either printed on the component, or is provided by:", "opta": "keyed containers", "optb": "size", "optc": "color code", "optd": "ohmmeter reading", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many connections does a rheostat have?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the parts of a rheostat?", "opta": "wiper and resistor track", "optb": "solenoid and armature", "optc": "contact and wire wound", "optd": "center tape and wiper", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The load resistance increases. How will the load current change?", "opta": "vary", "optb": "remain constant", "optc": "increase", "optd": "decrease", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the power dissipated by a 1.2 k resistor with 12 volts across it?", "opta": "12 W", "optb": "1.2 W", "optc": ".12 W", "optd": "12 mW", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many joules of energy will a 10 W lamp dissipate in one minute?", "opta": "10 joules", "optb": "60 joules", "optc": "600 joules", "optd": "3600 joules", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of test equipment is used to measure resistors?", "opta": "ohmmeter", "optb": "ammeter", "optc": "voltmeter", "optd": "watt meter", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Resistance is:", "opta": "the opposition to current flow accompanied by the dissipation of heat", "optb": "symbolized by R, measured in ohms, and directly proportional to conductance", "optc": "directly proportional to current and voltage", "optd": "represented by the flow of fluid in the fluid circuit", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Electrical equipment is protected against excessive current by a(n):", "opta": "fusible wire link", "optb": "insulated glass container", "optc": "metal ended coil", "optd": "circuit opener", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If resistance decreases, then current will:", "opta": "decrease", "optb": "increase", "optc": "remain the same", "optd": "double", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A wire with a smaller cross-sectional area will produce:", "opta": "less heat", "optb": "more conductance", "optc": "less resistance", "optd": "more heat", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 22-gauge wire will have a diameter in mils of:", "opta": "10.03", "optb": "22.35", "optc": "45.26", "optd": "71.96", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The word work means that:", "opta": "energy has been transferred", "optb": "it is inversely related to energy", "optc": "no energy has been transferred", "optd": "work and energy are not related", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A good fuse will have:", "opta": "zero ohms resistance", "optb": "a medium resistance", "optc": "a high resistance", "optd": "an infinite resistance", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What property does an incandescent lamp possess?", "opta": "cold resistance", "optb": "hot resistance", "optc": "ballast resistance", "optd": "both cold and hot resistance", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One advantage of a carbon film resistor over a carbon composition resistor is:", "opta": "less circuit noise", "optb": "smaller size", "optc": "higher wattage", "optd": "poor tolerance", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a metallic conductor has a positive temperature coefficient of resistance, then:", "opta": "as temperature increases, resistance decreases", "optb": "as current increases, resistance decreases", "optc": "as voltage increases, current increases", "optd": "as temperature increases, resistance increases", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What value of a  1.3 k resistor as measured by a digital voltmeter would be considered within tolerance?", "opta": "1234", "optb": "1235", "optc": "1366", "optd": "1367", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a calculator display was \"0.00263,\" what would this answer be in percent?", "opta": "0.026%", "optb": "0.26%", "optc": "2.63%", "optd": "26.3%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 33 k resistor with a 20% tolerance checks out as ok with which of the following ohmmeter readings?", "opta": "26400 ohms", "optb": "24183 ohms", "optc": "6600 ohms", "optd": "39970 ohms", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For P = V2/R, a decrease in resistance should produce:", "opta": "a decrease in power", "optb": "an increase in ohms", "optc": "an increase in power", "optd": "a decrease in current", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "After a lamp is turned on, its filament resistance will change to become:", "opta": "less resistive", "optb": "cooler", "optc": "brighter", "optd": "more resistive", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Wirewound resistors are usually used in circuits that have:", "opta": "high current", "optb": "negative temperature coefficients", "optc": "low power", "optd": "high voltage", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is power dissipated in a resistor?", "opta": "by resistance", "optb": "by voltage", "optc": "by current", "optd": "by heat", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Resistance in a circuit is:", "opta": "opposition to current", "optb": "opposition to voltage", "optc": "the same as current", "optd": "the same as voltage", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The unit designator for resistance value is the:", "opta": "ampere", "optb": "ohm", "optc": "volt", "optd": "watt", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One ampere of current flowing through one ohm of resistance is equal to:", "opta": "1 horsepower", "optb": "1 Btu", "optc": "1 watt", "optd": "1 joule", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Good insulators:", "opta": "have few electrons in their outer shells", "optb": "have a large dielectric strength", "optc": "have a small breakdown voltage", "optd": "have many electrons in the nucleus", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the applied voltage for a series RLC circuit when IT = 3 mA, VL = 30 V, VC = 18 V, and R = 1000 ohms?", "opta": "3.00 V", "optb": "12.37 V", "optc": "34.98 V", "optd": "48.00 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the bandwidth of the circuit?", "opta": "31.8 Hz", "optb": "32.3 Hz", "optc": "142 Hz", "optd": "7.2 kHz", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a parallel RLC circuit, which value may always be used as a vector reference?", "opta": "current", "optb": "reactance", "optc": "resistance", "optd": "voltage", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How much current will flow in a 100 Hz series RLC circuit if VS = 20 V, RT = 66 ohms, and XT = 47 ohms?", "opta": "1.05 A", "optb": "303 mA", "optc": "247 mA", "optd": "107 mA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the Q (Quality factor) of a series circuit that resonates at 6 kHz, has equal reactance of 4 kilo-ohms each, and a resistor value of 50 ohms?", "opta": "0.001", "optb": "50", "optc": "80", "optd": "4.0", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the range between f1 and f2 of an RLC circuit that resonates at 150 kHz and has a Q of 30?", "opta": "100.0 kHz to 155.0 kHz", "optb": "147.5 kHz to 152.5 kHz", "optc": "4500 kHz to 295.5 kHz", "optd": "149,970 Hz to 150,030 Hz", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the quality factor?", "opta": "999", "optb": "223", "optc": "2.2", "optd": "0.99", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What effect will a parallel tank have upon final filter current?", "opta": "very little", "optb": "The bandpass frequencies will change.", "optc": "The frequency cutoff will change.", "optd": "The impedance will block output.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total current?", "opta": "56.6 mA", "optb": "141 mA", "optc": "191 mA", "optd": "244 mA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a parallel circuit resonates it is said to:", "opta": "flywheel", "optb": "oscillate", "optc": "both of the above", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the resonant frequency in the given circuit?", "opta": "11.6 Hz", "optb": "275.8 Hz", "optc": "1.5 kHz", "optd": "3.2 kHz", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Series RLC voltage or impedance totals must be calculated by:", "opta": "subtracting the values", "optb": "graphing the angles", "optc": "adding vectors", "optd": "multiplying the values", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total current?", "opta": "15.6 mA", "optb": "17.8 mA", "optc": "21.9 mA", "optd": "26.0 mA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When XC = XL the circuit:", "opta": "draws maximum current", "optb": "applied voltage is zero", "optc": "is at resonance", "optd": "draws minimum current", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How much current will flow in a series RLC circuit when VT = 100 V, XL = 160 , XC = 80 , and R = 60 ?", "opta": "1 A", "optb": "1 mA", "optc": "6.28 A", "optd": "10 A", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a full band of frequencies is allowed to pass through a filter circuit to the output, the resonant circuit is called a:", "opta": "low-pass filter", "optb": "high-pass filter", "optc": "band-stop filter", "optd": "bandpass filter", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "At resonance, the term bandwidth includes all frequencies that allow what percentage of maximum current to flow?", "opta": "50", "optb": "62.3", "optc": "70.7", "optd": "95.3", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the voltage across the capacitor in the given circuit?", "opta": "6.8 V", "optb": "11.9 V", "optc": "16.1 V", "optd": "22.9 V", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the impedance of the circuit in the given circuit?", "opta": "1.05 k", "optb": "1.33 k", "optc": "2.19 k", "optd": "3.39 k", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a series RLC circuit the current can be found using:", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "both of the above", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the true power consumed in a 30 V series RLC circuit if Z = 20 ohms and R = 10 ohms?", "opta": "15.0 watts", "optb": "22.5 watts", "optc": "30.0 watts", "optd": "45.0 watts", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the current phase angle for a parallel RLC circuit when IL = 15.3 A, IC = 0.43 A, and IR = 3.5 A?", "opta": "76.7 degrees", "optb": "\u20134.25 degrees", "optc": "88.8 degrees", "optd": "\u201376.7 degrees", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "At any resonant frequency, what voltage is measured across the two series reactive components?", "opta": "applied", "optb": "reactive", "optc": "zero", "optd": "inductive and capacitive", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the resonance frequency?", "opta": "31.8 Hz", "optb": "71 Hz", "optc": "7.1 kHz", "optd": "31.8 kHz", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the range between f1 and f2 of an RLC circuit that resonates at 150 kHz and has a Q of 30?", "opta": "100.0 kHz to 155.0 kHz", "optb": "147.5 kHz to 152.5 kHz", "optc": "4500 kHz to 295.5 kHz", "optd": "149,970 Hz to 150,030 Hz", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the bandwidth in the given circuit. If the winding resistance of the coil is 12 ?", "opta": "6.4 kHz", "optb": "47.2 kHz", "optc": "53.7 kHz", "optd": "60.2 kHz", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "At any resonant frequency, what net voltage is measured across the two series reactive components?", "opta": "Applied voltage", "optb": "Reactive voltage", "optc": "Zero voltage", "optd": "VL + VC voltage", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the bandwidth of a filter increases:", "opta": "Q decreases", "optb": "the roll-off rate increases", "optc": "the half-power frequency decreases", "optd": "the center frequency decreases", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Series RLC impedance or voltage totals must always be calculated by", "opta": "adding values vectorially", "optb": "graphing the angles", "optc": "multiplying the values", "optd": "subtracting the values", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the current through the capacitor in the given circuit?", "opta": "3.5 mA", "optb": "5.5 mA", "optc": "9 mA", "optd": "11.4 mA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total impedance of a 60 Hz series RLC circuit when XL = 7.5 ohms, XC = 265.3 ohms, and R = 33 ohms?", "opta": "257.8 ohms", "optb": "259.9 ohms", "optc": "290.8 ohms", "optd": "1989.75 ohms", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total current for the nonideal circuit in the given circuit. If it is at resonance?", "opta": "0 A", "optb": "284  A", "optc": "3.3 mA", "optd": "38.5 mA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the high cutoff frequency for an RLC circuit that resonates at 2000 Hz and has a bandwidth of 250 Hz?", "opta": "2125 Hz", "optb": "2250 Hz", "optc": "1750 Hz", "optd": "8.0 Hz", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Current in a series RLC circuit may always be used as:", "opta": "a leading vector", "optb": "a reference", "optc": "an angle", "optd": "a lagging vector", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the impedance of the circuit?", "opta": "12.2 k", "optb": "14.5 k", "optc": "17.8 k", "optd": "20.3 k", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the resonant frequency in the given circuit?", "opta": "6.5 kHz", "optb": "53.7 kHz", "optc": "107.4 kHz", "optd": "18.1 MHz", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the impedance of the circuit in the given circuit?", "opta": "125.7", "optb": "297.6", "optc": "370.1", "optd": "423.3", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the approximate phase angle in a series RLC circuit when VC = 117 V, VR = 14.5 V, and VL = 3.3 V?", "opta": "\u201345.0 degrees", "optb": "\u201382.7 degrees", "optc": "\u201390.0 degrees", "optd": "\u2013172.7 degrees", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which statement best describes reactance in a series RLC circuit?", "opta": "Capacitive reactance is always dominant.", "optb": "Inductive reactance is always dominant.", "optc": "Resistance is always dominant.", "optd": "The larger of the two reactances is dominant.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the band pass (F1 \u2013 F2) of an RLC filter that resonates at 150 kHz and has a coil Q of 30?", "opta": "100.0 kHz to 155.0 kHz", "optb": "147.5 kHz to 152.5 kHz", "optc": "295.5 kHz to 4500 kHz", "optd": "149,970 Hz to 150,030 Hz", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the power factor?", "opta": "0.279", "optb": "0.479", "optc": "0.679", "optd": "0.879", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the phase angle?", "opta": "61.4\u00ba", "optb": "28.5\u00ba", "optc": "-28.5\u00ba", "optd": "-61.4\u00ba", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What would be the power factor for an RLC circuit that acts inductively?", "opta": "+90 degrees leading", "optb": "one", "optc": "zero", "optd": "\u201390 degrees lagging", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Voltage lags current in an RLC circuit when it acts:", "opta": "capacitively", "optb": "resistively", "optc": "inductively", "optd": "resonantly", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the bandwidth of the circuit in the given circuit?", "opta": "11.6 Hz", "optb": "275.9 Hz", "optc": "1.5 kHz", "optd": "3.2 kHz", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the voltage across R1, C1, and L1?", "opta": "VR = 156 V, VC = 165 V, VL = 441 V", "optb": "VR = 178 V, VC = 187 V, VL = 503 V", "optc": "VR = 219 V, VC = 232 V, VL = 619 V", "optd": "VR = 260 V, VC = 276 V, VL = 735 V", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As frequency increases", "opta": "both series and parallel RL impedance decrease", "optb": "series RL impedance decreases and parallel RL impedance increases", "optc": "series RL impedance increases and parallel RL impedance decreases", "optd": "both series and parallel RL impedance increase", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Calculate the voltage dropped across R1 in the given circuit.", "opta": "14 V", "optb": "26.8 V", "optc": "28 V", "optd": "0 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the true power of a 24 Vac parallel RL circuit when R = 45  and XL = 1100 ?", "opta": "313.45 W", "optb": "12.8 W", "optc": "44.96 W", "optd": "22.3 W", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If XL= 100  and R = 100 , then impedance will be", "opta": "141.4", "optb": "14.14", "optc": "100", "optd": "200", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is true if the inductor shorts out in the circuit in the given circuit?", "opta": "Each component drops 5 V.", "optb": "The impedance equals 0 .", "optc": "The power factor equals 1.", "optd": "The phase angle equals 90\u00b0.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Calculate the voltage dropped across L2 in the given circuit.", "opta": "18 V", "optb": "6 V", "optc": "13.5 V", "optd": "0 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the magnitude of the phase angle of a 24 Vac parallel RL circuit when R = 45  and XL = 1100 ?", "opta": "0.001\u00b0", "optb": "2.3\u00b0", "optc": "87.6\u00b0", "optd": "89.9\u00b0", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is true if the frequency decreases in the circuit in the given circuit?", "opta": "The phase angle decreases.", "optb": "VR", "ans": "", "explanation": ""}, {"question": "What is the magnitude of the phase angle between the source voltage and current when a 100 mH inductor with an inductive reactance of 6 k and a 1 k resistor are in series with a source?", "opta": "0.1\u00b0", "optb": "9.0\u00b0", "optc": "61.0\u00b0", "optd": "81.0\u00b0", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is true if R1 opens in the circuit in the given circuit?", "opta": "IL2 increases.", "optb": "ZT decreases.", "optc": "VS increases.", "optd": "VL1 equals 0 V.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is true if R = 100  and XL = 100  in the circuit in the given circuit?", "opta": "Each component drops 5 V.", "optb": "The impedance equals 200 .", "optc": "The power factor equals 1.", "optd": "The phase angle equals 45\u00b0.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is true about a lag network?", "opta": "An increase in frequency causes an increase in phase lag.", "optb": "An increase in frequency causes an increase in the magnitude of the output voltage.", "optc": "A decrease in frequency causes an increase in phase lag.", "optd": "A decrease in frequency causes a decrease in the magnitude of the output voltage.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A computerized self-diagnostic for a ROM test uses:", "opta": "the check-sum method", "optb": "a ROM listing", "optc": "ROM comparisons", "optd": "a checkerboard test", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many storage locations are available when a memory device has twelve address lines?", "opta": "144", "optb": "512", "optc": "2048", "optd": "4096", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following memories uses a MOSFET and a capacitor as its memory cell?", "opta": "SRAM", "optb": "DRAM", "optc": "ROM", "optd": "DROM", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following best describes nonvolatile memory?", "opta": "memory that retains stored information when electrical power is removed", "optb": "memory that loses stored information when electrical power is removed", "optc": "magnetic memory", "optd": "nonmagnetic memory", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The access time (tacc) of a memory IC is governed by the IC's:", "opta": "internal address buffer", "optb": "internal address decoder", "optc": "volatility", "optd": "internal address decoder and volatility", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Select the best description of read-only memory (ROM).", "opta": "nonvolatile, used to store information that changes during system operation", "optb": "nonvolatile, used to store information that does not change during system operation", "optc": "volatile, used to store information that changes during system operation", "optd": "volatile, used to store information that does not change during system operation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Advantage(s) of an EEPROM over an EPROM is (are):", "opta": "the EPROM can be erased with ultraviolet light in much less time than an EEPROM", "optb": "the EEPROM can be erased and reprogrammed without removal from the circuit", "optc": "the EEPROM has the ability to erase and reprogram individual words", "optd": "the EEPROM can erase and reprogram individual words without removal from the circuit", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following RAM timing parameters determine(s) its operating speed?", "opta": "tacc", "optb": "taa and tacs", "optc": "t1 and t3", "optd": "trc and twc", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Memory that loses its contents when power is lost is:", "opta": "nonvolatile", "optb": "volatile", "optc": "random", "optd": "static", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Select the best description of the fusible-link PROM.", "opta": "user programmable, one-time programmable", "optb": "manufacturer programmable, one-time programmable", "optc": "user programmable, reprogrammable", "optd": "manufacturer programmable, reprogrammable", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A nonvolatile type of memory that can be programmed and erased in sectors, rather than one byte at a time is:", "opta": "flash memory", "optb": "EPROM", "optc": "EEPROM", "optd": "MPROM", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following best describes static memory devices?", "opta": "memory devices that are magnetic in nature and do not require constant refreshing", "optb": "semiconductor memory devices in which stored data is retained as long as power is applied", "optc": "memory devices that are magnetic in nature and require constant refreshing", "optd": "semiconductor memory devices in which stored data will not be retained with the power applied unless constantly refreshed", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the principal advantage of using address multiplexing with DRAM memory?", "opta": "reduced memory access time", "optb": "reduced requirement for constant refreshing of the memory contents", "optc": "reduced pin count and decrease in package size", "optd": "no requirement for a chip-select input line, thereby reducing the pin count", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Intrinsic semiconductor material is characterized by a valence shell of how many electrons?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "6", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ionization within a P-N junction causes a layer on each side of the barrier called the:", "opta": "junction", "optb": "depletion region", "optc": "barrier voltage", "optd": "forward voltage", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the most significant development in electronics since World War II?", "opta": "the development of color TV", "optb": "the development of the diode", "optc": "the development of the transistor", "optd": "the development of the TRIAC", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What causes the depletion region?", "opta": "doping", "optb": "diffusion", "optc": "barrier potential", "optd": "ions", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is an energy gap?", "opta": "the space between two orbital shells", "optb": "the energy equal to the energy acquired by an electron passing a 1 V electric field", "optc": "the energy band in which electrons can move freely", "optd": "an energy level at which an electron can exist", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Silicon atoms combine into an orderly pattern called a:", "opta": "covalent bond", "optb": "crystal", "optc": "semiconductor", "optd": "valence orbit", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In \"n\" type material, majority carriers would be:", "opta": "holes", "optb": "dopants", "optc": "slower", "optd": "electrons", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Elements with 1, 2, or 3 valence electrons usually make excellent:", "opta": "conductors", "optb": "semiconductors", "optc": "insulators", "optd": "neutral", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A commonly used pentavalent material is:", "opta": "arsenic", "optb": "boron", "optc": "gallium", "optd": "neon", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which material may also be considered a semiconductor element?", "opta": "carbon", "optb": "ceramic", "optc": "mica", "optd": "argon", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In \"p\" type material, minority carriers would be:", "opta": "holes", "optb": "dopants", "optc": "slower", "optd": "electrons", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The purpose of p-type doping is to create an abundance of holes. In the case of silicon, a trivalent atom (typically from Group 13 of the periodic table, such as boron or aluminium) is substituted into the crystal lattice. The result is that one electron is missing from one of the four covalent bonds normal for the silicon lattice. Thus the dopant atom can accept an electron from a neighboring atom's covalent bond to complete the fourth bond. This is why such dopants are called acceptors. The dopant atom accepts an electron, causing the loss of half of one bond from the neighboring atom and resulting in the formation of a \"hole\". Each hole is associated with a nearby negatively charged dopant ion, and the semiconductor remains electrically neutral as a whole. However, once each hole has wandered away into the lattice, one proton in the atom at the hole's location will be \"exposed\" and no longer cancelled by an electron. This atom will have 3 electrons and 1 hole surrounding a particular nucleus with 4 protons. For this reason a hole behaves as a positive charge. When a sufficiently large number of acceptor atoms are added, the holes greatly outnumber thermal excited electrons. Thus, holes are the majority carriers, while electrons become minority carriers in p-type materials."}, {"question": "What can a semiconductor sense?", "opta": "magnetism", "optb": "temperature", "optc": "pressure", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When an electron jumps from the valence shell to the conduction band, it leaves a gap. What is this gap called?", "opta": "energy gap", "optb": "hole", "optc": "electron-hole pair", "optd": "recombination", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Forward bias of a silicon P-N junction will produce a barrier voltage of approximately how many volts?", "opta": "0.2", "optb": "0.3", "optc": "0.7", "optd": "0.8", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which semiconductor material is made from coal ash?", "opta": "germanium", "optb": "silicon", "optc": "tin", "optd": "carbon", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When and who discovered that more than one transistor could be constructed on a single piece of semiconductor material:", "opta": "1949, William Schockley", "optb": "1955, Walter Bratten", "optc": "1959, Robert Noyce", "optd": "1960, John Bardeen", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When is a P-N junction formed?", "opta": "in a depletion region", "optb": "in a large reverse biased region", "optc": "the point at which two opposite doped materials come together", "optd": "whenever there is a forward voltage drop", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A P-N junction mimics a closed switch when it:", "opta": "has a low junction resistance", "optb": "is reverse biased", "optc": "cannot overcome its barrier voltage", "optd": "has a wide depletion region", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Solid state devices were first manufactured during:", "opta": "World War 2", "optb": "1904", "optc": "1907", "optd": "1960", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Electron pair bonding occurs when atoms:", "opta": "lack electrons", "optb": "share holes", "optc": "lack holes", "optd": "share electrons", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many valence electrons are in every semiconductor material?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is a type of doping material?", "opta": "extrinsic semiconductor material", "optb": "pentavalent material", "optc": "n-type semiconductor", "optd": "majority carriers", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Minority carriers are many times activated by:", "opta": "heat", "optb": "pressure", "optc": "dopants", "optd": "forward bias", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the voltage across R1 if the P-N junction is made of silicon?", "opta": "12 V", "optb": "11.7 V", "optc": "11.3 V", "optd": "0 V", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If conductance increases as temperature increases, this is known as a:", "opta": "positive coefficient", "optb": "negative current flow", "optc": "negative coefficient", "optd": "positive resistance", "ans": "C", "explanation": "A negative temperature coefficient (NTC) occurs when the thermal conductivity of a material rises with increasing temperature, typically in a defined temperature range.\nNote: The reciprocal of electrical Resistance is called Conductance."}, {"question": "Which of the following cannot actually move?", "opta": "majority carriers", "optb": "ions", "optc": "holes", "optd": "free electrons", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What electrical characteristic of intrinsic semiconductor material is controlled by the addition of impurities?", "opta": "conductivity", "optb": "resistance", "optc": "power", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A ripple counter's speed is limited by the propagation delay of:", "opta": "each flip-flop", "optb": "all flip-flops and gates", "optc": "the flip-flops only with gates", "optd": "only circuit gates", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To operate correctly, starting a ring counter requires:", "opta": "clearing all the flip-flops", "optb": "presetting one flip-flop and clearing all the others", "optc": "clearing one flip-flop and presetting all the others", "optd": "presetting all the flip-flops", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of register would shift a complete binary number in one bit at a time and shift all the stored bits out one bit at a time?", "opta": "PIPO", "optb": "SISO", "optc": "SIPO", "optd": "PISO", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Synchronous counters eliminate the delay problems encountered with asynchronous (ripple) counters because the:", "opta": "input clock pulses are applied only to the first and last stages", "optb": "input clock pulses are applied only to the last stage", "optc": "input clock pulses are not used to activate any of the counter stages", "optd": "input clock pulses are applied simultaneously to each stage", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One of the major drawbacks to the use of asynchronous counters is that:", "opta": "low-frequency applications are limited because of internal  propagation delays", "optb": "high-frequency applications are limited because of internal propagation delays", "optc": "Asynchronous counters do not have major drawbacks and are suitable for use in high- and low-frequency counting applications.", "optd": "Asynchronous counters do not have propagation delays, which limits their use in high-frequency applications.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of device may be used to interface a parallel data format with external equipment's serial format?", "opta": "key matrix", "optb": "UART", "optc": "memory chip", "optd": "serial-in, parallel-out", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When the output of a tri-state shift register is disabled, the output level is  placed in a:", "opta": "float state", "optb": "LOW state", "optc": "high impedance state", "optd": "float state and a high impedance state", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A comparison between ring and johnson counters indicates that:", "opta": "a ring counter has fewer flip-flops but requires more decoding circuitry", "optb": "a ring counter has an inverted feedback path", "optc": "a johnson counter has more flip-flops but less decoding circuitry", "optd": "a johnson counter has an inverted feedback path", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A sequence of equally spaced timing pulses may be easily generated by which type of counter circuit?", "opta": "shift register sequencer", "optb": "clock", "optc": "johnson", "optd": "binary", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is meant by parallel-loading the register?", "opta": "Shifting the data in all flip-flops simultaneously", "optb": "Loading data in two of the flip-flops", "optc": "Loading data in all four flip-flops at the same time", "optd": "Momentarily disabling the synchronous SET and RESET inputs", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is a shift register that will accept a parallel input and can shift data left or right called?", "opta": "tri-state", "optb": "end around", "optc": "bidirectional universal", "optd": "conversion", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What happens to the parallel output word in an asynchronous binary down counter whenever a clock pulse occurs?", "opta": "The output word decreases by 1.", "optb": "The output word decreases by 2.", "optc": "The output word increases by 1.", "optd": "The output word increases by 2.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mod-6 and mod-12 counters are most commonly used in:", "opta": "frequency counters", "optb": "multiplexed displays", "optc": "digital clocks", "optd": "power consumption meters", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which circuit is known as a current-to-voltage converter?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When using an OTA in a Schmitt-trigger configuration, the trigger points are controlled by", "opta": "the Iout", "optb": "the IBIAS", "optc": "the Vout", "optd": "both Iout and IBIAS", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Refer the given circuits. Which circuit is known as an OTA?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This circuit is a setup for", "opta": "an antilog amplifier", "optb": "a constant-current source", "optc": "an instrumentation amplifier", "optd": "an isolation amplifier", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which circuit is known as a voltage-to-current converter?", "opta": "a", "optb": "b", "optc": "c", "optd": "d", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The primary function of the oscillator in an isolation amplifier is to", "opta": "convert dc to high-frequency ac", "optb": "convert dc to low-frequency ac", "optc": "rectify high-frequency ac to dc", "optd": "produce dual-polarity dc voltages for the input to the demodulator", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Refer to Figure 20-2. This circuit is a setup for", "opta": "an antilog amplifier", "optb": "a constant-current source", "optc": "an instrumentation amplifier", "optd": "an isolation amplifier", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An instrumentation amplifier has a high", "opta": "output impedance", "optb": "power gain", "optc": "CMRR", "optd": "supply voltage", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This circuit is a setup for", "opta": "an antilog amplifier", "optb": "a constant-current source", "optc": "an instrumentation amplifier", "optd": "an isolation amplifier", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Circuits that shift the dc level of a signal are called", "opta": "limiters", "optb": "clampers", "optc": "peak detectors", "optd": "dc converters", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The voltage gain of an OTA can be calculated using the formula", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the classic three-op-amp instrumentation amplifier, the differential voltage gain is usually produced by the", "opta": "first stage", "optb": "second stage", "optc": "mismatched resistors", "optd": "output op-amp", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A digital logic device used as a buffer should have what input/output characteristics?", "opta": "high input impedance and high output impedance", "optb": "low input impedance and high output impedance", "optc": "low input impedance and low output impedance", "optd": "high input impedance and low output impedance", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the standard TTL noise margin?", "opta": "5.0 V", "optb": "0.2 V", "optc": "0.8 V", "optd": "0.4 V", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The range of a valid LOW input is:", "opta": "0.0 V to 0.4 V", "optb": "0.4 V to 0.8 V", "optc": "0.4 V to 1.8 V", "optd": "0.4 V to 2.4 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When an IC has two rows of parallel connecting pins, the device is referred to as:", "opta": "a QFP", "optb": "a DIP", "optc": "a phase splitter", "optd": "CMOS", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which digital IC package type makes the most efficient use of printed circuit board space?", "opta": "SMT", "optb": "TO can", "optc": "flat pack", "optd": "DIP", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The problem of interfacing IC logic families that have different supply voltages (VCCs) can be solved by using a:", "opta": "level-shifter", "optb": "tri-state shifter", "optc": "translator", "optd": "level-shifter or translator", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ten TTL loads per TTL driver is known as:", "opta": "noise immunity", "optb": "power dissipation", "optc": "fanout", "optd": "propagation delay", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following summarizes the important features of emitter-coupled logic (ECL)?", "opta": "negative voltage operation, high speed, and high power consumption", "optb": "good noise immunity, negative logic, high frequency capability, low power dissipation, and short propagation time", "optc": "slow propagation time, high frequency response, low power consumption, and high output voltage swings", "optd": "poor noise immunity, positive supply voltage operation, good low-frequency operation, and low power", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What quantities must be compatible when interfacing two different logic families?", "opta": "only the currents", "optb": "both the voltages and the currents", "optc": "only the voltages", "optd": "both the power dissipation and the impedance", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "CMOS logic is probably the best all-around circuitry because of its:", "opta": "packing density", "optb": "low power consumption", "optc": "very high noise immunity", "optd": "low power consumption and very high noise immunity", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Low power consumption achieved by CMOS circuits is due to which construction characteristic?", "opta": "complementary pairs", "optb": "connecting pads", "optc": "DIP packages", "optd": "small-scale integration", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A TTL totem pole circuit is designed so that the output transistors are:", "opta": "always on together", "optb": "providing phase splitting", "optc": "providing voltage regulation", "optd": "never on together", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The time needed for an output to change as the result of an input change is known as:", "opta": "noise immunity", "optb": "fanout", "optc": "propagation delay", "optd": "rise time", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A series of gradually decreasing sine wave oscillations is called:", "opta": "ringing", "optb": "slew", "optc": "overshooting", "optd": "undershooting", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The determination of a digital signal's frequency and       waveshape is best accomplished with which test equipment?", "opta": "an oscilloscope", "optb": "a multimeter", "optc": "a spectrum analyzer", "optd": "a frequency generator", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A logic probe is placed on the output of a gate and the display indicator is dim. A logic pulser is used on each of the input terminals, but the output indication does not change. What is wrong?", "opta": "The dim indication on the logic probe indicates that the supply voltage is probably low.", "optb": "The output of the gate appears to be open.", "optc": "The LOW indication is the result of a bad ground connection on the logic probe.", "optd": "The gate is a tri-state device.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A +5 V PCB power source that has been \"pulled down\" to a +3.4 V level may be due to:", "opta": "a circuit open", "optb": "a faulty regulator", "optc": "the half-split method", "optd": "a circuit short", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Measurement of pulse width should be taken at a 50% mean of the:", "opta": "overshoot and undershoot", "optb": "rise and fall", "optc": "damping and ringing", "optd": "leading and trailing amplitude", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which test equipment best allows a comparison between input and output signals?", "opta": "an oscilloscope", "optb": "a logic probe", "optc": "a spectrum analyzer", "optd": "a multitrace oscilloscope", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The duty cycle of a pulse is determined by which formula?", "opta": "Duty Cycle =", "optb": "Duty Cycle =", "optc": "Duty Cycle =", "optd": "Duty Cycle =", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the next step after discovering a faulty gate within an IC?", "opta": "repair the gate", "optb": "resolder the tracks", "optc": "replace the IC involved", "optd": "recheck the power source", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The use of a multimeter with digital circuits allows the measurement of:", "opta": "pulse width", "optb": "voltage or resistance", "optc": "current", "optd": "pulse trains", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The use of triggered sweep when using an oscilloscope provides more accuracy in which area?", "opta": "frequency", "optb": "amplitude", "optc": "graticule activity", "optd": "timing", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The time needed for a pulse to increase from 10% to 90% of its amplitude defines:", "opta": "pulse width", "optb": "propagation delay", "optc": "rise time", "optd": "duty cycle", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which device would best aid in shorted track detection?", "opta": "multimeter", "optb": "current tracer", "optc": "logic pulser", "optd": "oscilloscope", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A TRIAC:", "opta": "can trigger only on positive gate voltages", "optb": "can trigger only on negative gate voltages", "optc": "cannot be triggered with gate voltages", "optd": "can be triggered by either a positive or a negative gate voltage", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When checking a good SCR or TRIAC with an ohmmeter it will:", "opta": "show high resistance in both directions", "optb": "show low resistance with positive on anode and negative on cathode, and high resistance when reversed", "optc": "show high resistance with negative on anode and positive on cathode, and low resistance when reversed", "optd": "show low resistance in both directions", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does a hall effect sensor sense?", "opta": "temperature", "optb": "moisture", "optc": "magnetic fields", "optd": "pressure", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What causes the piezoelectric effect?", "opta": "heat or dissimilar metals", "optb": "pressure on a crystal", "optc": "water running on iron", "optd": "a magnetic field", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is the DIAC?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A UJT has:", "opta": "two base leads", "optb": "one emitter lead", "optc": "two emitter leads and one base lead", "optd": "one emitter lead and two base leads", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The only way to close an SCR is with:", "opta": "a trigger input applied to the gate", "optb": "forward breakover voltage", "optc": "low-current dropout", "optd": "valley voltage", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is an SCR?", "opta": "a PNPN thyristor with 3 terminals", "optb": "a PNPN thyristor with 4 terminals", "optc": "a PNP thyristor with 3 terminals", "optd": "an NPN thyristor with 3 terminals", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of application would use a photovoltaic cell?", "opta": "an automobile horn", "optb": "a TI 92 calculator", "optc": "a magnetic field detector", "optd": "a remote power source", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is the seven-segment display?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The smallest amount of current that the cathode-anode can have, and still sustain conduction of an SCR is called the:", "opta": "maximum forward current", "optb": "maximum forward gate current", "optc": "holding current", "optd": "reverse gate leakage current", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Once a DIAC is conducting, the only way to turn it off is with:", "opta": "a positive gate voltage", "optb": "a negative gate voltage", "optc": "low-current dropout", "optd": "breakover", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is the TRIAC?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The DIAC is a:", "opta": "transistor", "optb": "unidirectional device", "optc": "three-layer device", "optd": "bidirectional device", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of application would use an injection laser diode?", "opta": "a 10BASE-T Ethernet", "optb": "a liquid crystal display", "optc": "a fiber optic transmission line", "optd": "a good flashlight", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The PUT (programmable unijunction transistor) is actually a type of:", "opta": "UJT thyristor", "optb": "FET device", "optc": "TRIAC", "optd": "SCR", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A transducer's function is to:", "opta": "transmit electrical energy", "optb": "convert energy", "optc": "produce mechanical energy", "optd": "prevent current flow", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What voltage will the capacitor charge up to in the given circuit for the single input pulse shown?", "opta": "3.15 V", "optb": "4.3 V", "optc": "4.75 V", "optd": "4.9 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a periodic pulse waveform is applied to an RC differentiating circuit, which two conditions are possible?", "opta": "tw  5 or tw > 5", "optb": "tw = 5 or tw > 5", "optc": "tw  5 or tw < 5", "optd": "tw  5 or tw < 5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An RL integrator and an RC differentiator can act as what types of filters, respectively?", "opta": "low-pass, low-pass", "optb": "low-pass, high-pass", "optc": "high-pass, high-pass", "optd": "high-pass, low-pass", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a repetitive-pulse RC integrator circuit, what would the steady-state voltage equal at the end of the fifth pulse? Assume a Vin of 20 V.", "opta": "1.46 V", "optb": "14.62 V", "optc": "20 V", "optd": "0 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is a circuit that produces short-duration spikes?", "opta": "A trigger pulse generator", "optb": "An RL integrator", "optc": "A timing circuit", "optd": "A pulse waveform-to-dc converter", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the given circuit, what must the pulse width and time between pulses be to allow the capacitor to completely charge by the end of each pulse and to completely discharge between each pulse?", "opta": "940 s", "optb": "2.82 ms", "optc": "3.76 ms", "optd": "4.7 ms", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The given circuit is an", "opta": "RL integrator", "optb": "RC differentiator", "optc": "RL differentiator", "optd": "RC integrator", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true for a capacitor?", "opta": "A capacitor acts like a short to instantaneous changes in current.", "optb": "A capacitor's voltage cannot change instantaneously.", "optc": "A capacitor acts like an open to dc.", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the capacitor in an RC integrator shorts, the output", "opta": "is at ground", "optb": "would measure the same as the input", "optc": "would measure zero volts", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What has the voltage across the resistor decayed to by the end of the pulse in the given circuit?", "opta": "0 V", "optb": "0.75 V", "optc": "5.55 V", "optd": "14.25 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How long will it take the capacitor in the given circuit to discharge?", "opta": "16.4 s", "optb": "32.8 s", "optc": "65.6 s", "optd": "82 s", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the voltage across the inductor in the given circuit on the falling edge of the first input pulse?", "opta": "\u20130.2 V", "optb": "0.2 V", "optc": "\u20139.8 V", "optd": "9.8 V", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The primary function of the bias circuit is to", "opta": "hold the circuit stable at VCC", "optb": "hold the circuit stable at vin", "optc": "ensure proper gain is achieved", "optd": "hold the circuit stable at the designed Q-point", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A JFET", "opta": "is a current-controlled device", "optb": "has a low input resistance", "optc": "is a voltage-controlled device", "optd": "is always forward-biased", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A source follower has a voltage gain (Av) of", "opta": "AV = gmRd", "optb": "AV = gmRS", "ans": "", "explanation": ""}, {"question": "The capacitor that produces an ac ground is called a(n)", "opta": "coupling capacitor", "optb": "dc open", "optc": "bypass capacitor", "optd": "ac open", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The formula used to calculate the approximate ac resistance of the base-emitter diode (re) is", "opta": "", "optb": "re  25 mV \u00d7 IC", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The signal voltage gain of an amplifier, Av, is defined as:", "opta": "", "optb": "Av = IC \u00d7 RC", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a class B push-pull amplifier, the transistors are biased slightly above cutoff to avoid", "opta": "crossover distortion", "optb": "unusually high efficiency", "optc": "negative feedback", "optd": "a low input impedance", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The depletion-mode MOSFET", "opta": "can operate with only positive gate voltages", "optb": "can operate with only negative gate voltages", "optc": "cannot operate in the ohmic region", "optd": "can operate with positive as well as negative gate voltages", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Three different points are shown on a dc load line. The upper point represents the", "opta": "minimum current gain", "optb": "quiescent point", "optc": "saturation point", "optd": "cutoff point", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following conditions are needed to properly bias an npn transistor amplifier?", "opta": "Forward bias the base/emitter junction and reverse bias the base/collector junction.", "optb": "Forward bias the collector/base junction and reverse bias the emitter/base junction.", "optc": "Apply a positive voltage on the n-type material and a negative voltage on the p-type material.", "optd": "Apply a large voltage on the base.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Often a common-collector will be the last stage before the load; the main function of this stage is to", "opta": "provide voltage gain", "optb": "buffer the voltage amplifiers from the low-resistance load", "optc": "provide phase inversion", "optd": "provide a high-frequency path to improve the frequency response", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In order for feedback oscillators to have any practical value, the gain has to be", "opta": "< 1", "optb": "self-adjusting", "optc": "stabilized", "optd": "nonlinear", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To get a negative gate-source voltage in a self-biased JFET circuit, you must use a", "opta": "voltage divider", "optb": "source resistor", "optc": "ground", "optd": "negative gate supply voltage", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the color code for a 220  5% resistor?", "opta": "Red, Red, Brown, Gold", "optb": "Orange, Orange, Black, Gold", "optc": "Red, Red, Black, Gold", "optd": "Red, Red, Brown, Silver", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Resistor colour coding series:\n\nBlack   0 \nBrown   1 \nRed     2 \nOrange  3 \nYellow  4 \nGreen   5 \nBlue    6 \nViolet  7  \nGray    8   \nWhite   9 \nNone    20% \nSilver  10% \nGold    5% \n\nTherefore Red, Red, Brown, Gold \n           2    2    101    5% \n\n = 22 x 10 = 220 ohm 5% (tolerance)."}, {"question": "If 60 J of energy are available for every 15 C of charge, what is the voltage?", "opta": "4 V", "optb": "60 V", "optc": "15 V", "optd": "0.25 V", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An atom's atomic number is determined by the number of:", "opta": "neutrons minus protons", "optb": "protons", "optc": "electrons", "optd": "neutrons", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A voltage will influence current only if the circuit is:", "opta": "open", "optb": "insulated", "optc": "high resistance", "optd": "closed", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which resistive component is designed to be temperature sensitive?", "opta": "Thermistor", "optb": "Rheostat", "optc": "Potentiometer", "optd": "Photoconductive cell", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The battery symbol is:", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of switch is this?", "opta": "push button", "optb": "SPST", "optc": "DPDT", "optd": "SPDT", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Primary batteries, unlike secondary batteries, may be:", "opta": "charged once", "optb": "used once", "optc": "recharged over and over", "optd": "stored indefinitely", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Primary batteries (disposable batteries), which are designed to be used once and discarded when they are exhausted.\n\nSecondary batteries (rechargeable batteries), which are designed to be recharged and used multiple times."}, {"question": "In practical applications, battery voltage:", "opta": "is restored as soon as disconnect occurs", "optb": "is lowered as the load increases", "optc": "may be stored indefinitely", "optd": "will be reduced to zero as power is drawn", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The negative and positive charge symbols are assigned (in that order) to the:", "opta": "proton and electron", "optb": "electron and proton", "optc": "atom and nucleus", "optd": "electron and element", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A voltmeter is used:", "opta": "to measure current", "optb": "in series with the circuit", "optc": "in parallel with the circuit", "optd": "to measure coulombs", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the current in a circuit equals 0 A, it is likely that the", "opta": "voltage is too high", "optb": "resistance is too low", "optc": "circuit has a short", "optd": "circuit is open", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Current equals:", "opta": "", "optb": "coulombs \u00d7 time", "optc": "", "optd": "voltage \u00d7 time", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the unit and symbol for current?", "opta": "Ampere, A", "optb": "Coulomb, I", "optc": "Ampere, Q", "optd": "Ampere, I", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which part of an atom has no electrical charge?", "opta": "Electron", "optb": "Neutron", "optc": "Proton", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which voltage source converts chemical energy to electrical energy?", "opta": "Electrical generator", "optb": "Battery", "optc": "Solar cell", "optd": "Electronic power supply", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An example of potential energy is:", "opta": "tea-kettle steam", "optb": "a moving vehicle", "optc": "the sun", "optd": "a battery", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If 40 C of charge flow past a point in 20 s, what is the current?", "opta": "2 A", "optb": "0.5 A", "optc": "20 A", "optd": "40 A", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Batteries differ from fuel cells in that", "opta": "a battery is a closed system", "optb": "a battery uses hydrogen and oxygen to create electricity", "optc": "a battery uses a polymer electrolyte membrane", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The removal of a non-neutral subatomic particle converts the atom into a:", "opta": "charged ion", "optb": "nucleus", "optc": "heavier element", "optd": "compound", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One coulomb passing a point in one second is one:", "opta": "ampere", "optb": "volt", "optc": "ohm", "optd": "charge", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In which states may matter may be found?", "opta": "solid, liquid, or mineral", "optb": "solid, gas, or liquid", "optc": "mineral, gas, or liquid", "optd": "plastic, solid, or gas", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Material that consists of a mixture of elements is considered to be:", "opta": "an element", "optb": "an ion", "optc": "a compound", "optd": "a molecule", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many valence shell electrons are there in semiconductor atoms?", "opta": "16", "optb": "8", "optc": "4", "optd": "2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When considering conventional current versus electron current flow:", "opta": "electron current flow came first", "optb": "protons move in conventional current flow", "optc": "conventional current flow came first", "optd": "the direction of current is the same in both methods", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which unit of charge contains 6.25 \u00d7 1018 electrons?", "opta": "An ampere", "optb": "A coulomb", "optc": "A volt", "optd": "A joule", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A switch is a device that:", "opta": "short circuits complex circuits", "optb": "holds a fuse", "optc": "has double poles", "optd": "opens or completes a current path", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The term used to designate electrical pressure is:", "opta": "voltage", "optb": "current", "optc": "resistance", "optd": "conductance", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which electronics material opposes the movement of free electrons?", "opta": "Conductor", "optb": "Insulator", "optc": "Semiconductor", "optd": "Element", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Current is considered as the movement of:", "opta": "electrons", "optb": "protons", "optc": "charge", "optd": "nuclei", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A lead-acid battery is an example of a", "opta": "solar cell", "optb": "fuel cell", "optc": "primary battery", "optd": "secondary battery", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The charge of one coulomb is equal to:", "opta": "6.24 x 10\u221218 electrons", "optb": "one ampere", "optc": "one second", "optd": "6.24 x 1018 electrons", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A basic electric circuit is made up of what components?", "opta": "A load, a resistor, and a conductive path for current", "optb": "A voltage source, a load, and a conductive path for current", "optc": "A voltage source, a conductive path for current, and a battery", "optd": "A conductive path for current, a battery, and a copper wire", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An ammeter is used to measure", "opta": "voltage", "optb": "current", "optc": "resistance", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the name of the pressure that moves electrons in a closed circuit?", "opta": "amperes", "optb": "ohms", "optc": "voltage", "optd": "coulombs", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is a characteristic of a secondary cell?", "opta": "rechargeability", "optb": "not rechargeable", "optc": "a dry cell", "optd": "non-liquid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the basic building blocks that all matter is composed of?", "opta": "electrons, neutrons, and protons", "optb": "two protons for each neutron", "optc": "two protons for each electron", "optd": "electrons, neutrons, and charged ions", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a fluid system is compared to an electrical system, the fluid pump will correspond to a:", "opta": "conductor", "optb": "lamp", "optc": "battery", "optd": "insulator", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An element is a substance that is:", "opta": "varied throughout the entire piece", "optb": "used only in electronics", "optc": "electrically charged", "optd": "found only in its pure form", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Current is:", "opta": "the presence of a positive charge", "optb": "the abundance of electrons", "optc": "the movement of electrons", "optd": "the repulsion of electrons", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do you call a diagram that shows the electrical connections of a circuit's components?", "opta": "A schematic diagram", "optb": "A pictorial diagram", "optc": "A block diagram", "optd": "An electrical diagram", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A short circuit will have:", "opta": "a small current flow", "optb": "a large current flow", "optc": "no current flow", "optd": "some current flow", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The basic difference between a fuse and a circuit breaker is", "opta": "a fuse is slower", "optb": "a fuse is reusable", "optc": "a circuit breaker is reusable", "optd": "a circuit breaker is more reliable", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is the smallest?", "opta": "atom", "optb": "proton", "optc": "neutron", "optd": "electron", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A secondary cell generates dc via chemical activity; a primary cell generates dc:", "opta": "electrically", "optb": "thermally", "optc": "optically", "optd": "chemically", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is true?", "opta": "Unlike charges repel and like charges attract.", "optb": "Like charges repel and unlike charges attract.", "optc": "Unlike charges attract and like charges attract.", "optd": "Like charges repel and unlike charges repel.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If an electrical system is compared to a fluid system, the electrical current corresponds to the:", "opta": "pressure", "optb": "pump", "optc": "water wheel", "optd": "water flow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}